<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>inm98d00</tid>
<bt>50386532/6533</bt>
<ti>BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH  LEMMON, SANDRA K.</ti>
<dd>19960710</dd>
<dt>RESUME</dt>
<!-- Note:d:EDUCATION, RESEARCH AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE AND PUBLICATIONS-->
<!-- Note:dl:20010130-->
<pg>2</pg>
<dl>20021115</dl>
<ot>Biographical Sketch cont.: Sandra K. Lemmon
PUBLICATIONS (Total of 23, **Most significant publications)
Publications since 1993:
**K.K. Nelson and S.K. Lemmon, "Suppressors of Clathrin Deficiency; Overexpression of
Ubiquitin Rescues Lethal Strains of Clathrin Deficient Saccharomyces cerevisiae", Mol.
Cell. Biol. 13:521-532 (1993).
C.W. Bazinet, A.L. Katzen, M. Morgan, A.P. Mahowald and S.K. Lemmon, "The Drosophila
Clathrin Heavy Chain: Clathrin Function is Essential in a Multicellular Organism",
Genetics 134:1119-1134 (1993).
G.S. Payne and S_.K. Lemmon, CHCI, in Guidebook to the Secretory Pathway, J. Rothblatt, P.
Novick and M.J. Gething, eds., Sambrook and Tooze Pub. at Oxford Univ. Press, New
York, pp 267-269 (1994).
J.D. Stepp, A. Pellicena-Palle, S. Hamilton, T. Kirchhausen, and S.K. Lemmon, "A Late Golgi
Sorting Function for Saccharomyces cerevisiae Apm1p, but not for Apm2p, a Second
Yeast Clathrin AP Medium Chain-Related Protein", Mol. Biol. Cell. 6:41-58 (1995).
**D.M. Gelperin, J.W. Weigle, K.K. Nelson, P.H. Roseboom, K. Irie, K. Matsumoto and S.K.
Lemmon, "14-3-3 Proteins: Potential Roles in Vesicular Transport and Ras Signaling in
Saccharomyces cerevisiae", PNAS 92: 11539-11543 (1995).
**K.K. Nelson, M. Holmer, and S_.K. Lemmon, "SCD5, a Suppressor of Clathrin-Deficiency,
Encodes a Novel Protein with a Late Secretory Function in Yeast", Mol. Biol. Cell., 7:
245-260 (1996).
K. Huang, L. Gullberg, K. Nelson, C. Stefan, K. Blumer and S. K. Lemmon, "Novel Functions
for Clathrin Light Chains: Clathrin Heavy Chain Trimerization is Defective in Light
Chain-Deficient Yeast", submitted.
Other relevant publications:
C.M. Moehle, R.A. Tizard, S.K. Lemmon, J. Smart and E.W. Jones, "Protease B of the
Lysosome-like Vacuole of the Yeast Saccharomyces cerevisiae is Homologous to the
Subtilisin Family of Serine Proteases, Mol. Cell. Biol. 7:4390-4399 (1987).
**S_.K. Lemmon and E.W. Jones, "Clathrin Requirement for Normal Growth of Yeast," Science,
238:504-509 (1987).
S.K. Lemmon, V.P. Lemmon and E.W. Jones, "Characterization of Yeast Clathrin and
Anti-Clathrin Heavy Chain Monoclonal Antibodies," J. Cell. Biochem. 36:329-340
(1988).
S.K. Lemmon, C.L. Freund, K. Conley and E.W. Jones, "Genetic Instability of Clathrin Deficient
Strains of Saccharomyces cerevisiae," Genetics 124:27-38 (1990).
**S_.K. Lemmon, A. Pellicena-Palle, K. Conley and C.L. Freund, "Sequence of the Clathrin
Heavy Chain from Saccharomyces cerevisiae and Requirement of the C-terminus for
Clathrin Function," J. Cell Biol. 112:65-80 (1991).
Y. Nakayama, M. Goebl, B.O. Greco, S_.K. Lemmon, E.P. Chow and T. Kirchhausen, "The
Medium Chains of the Mammalian Clathrin-Associated Proteins have a Homolog in
Yeast", Eur. J. Biochem. 202:569-574 (1991).
In preparation:
H.R. Panek, J. D. Stepp, H.M. Engle, S.K. Lemmon and L.C. Robinson, "Suppressors of Loss of
YCK-encoded Yeast Casein Kinase 1 Define Four Subunits of a Novel Complex Related
to Clathrin Adaptors".
C.W. Bazinet, J. Polak, A.P. Mahowald and S.K. Lemmon, "Spermatogenic Defect of a Male-
Sterile Allele of the Clathrin Heavy Chain Gene".

pgNbr=1
BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH
Give the following information for the key personnel and consultants and collaborators. Begin with the principal
investigator/program director. Photocopy this page for each person.
NAME
Lemmon, Sandra K.
POSITION TITLE
Associate Professor
EDUCATION (Begin with baccalaureate or other initial professional education, such as nursing, and include
postdoctoral training.)

INSTITUTION AND LOCATION			
DEGREE	
CO	YEAR
NFERRED	
FIELD OF STUDY
University of Rochester, Rochester, NY		B.A.	1973 Biology
Washington University, St. Louis, MO		Ph.D.	1982 Cell and
			Molecular
Biolog
RESEARCH AND/OR PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE: Concluding with present position, list in chronological order previous employment, experience,
and honors. Key personnel include the principal investigator and any other individuals who participate in ihe scientific development or execution of the
project. Key personnel typically will include all individuals with doctoral or other professional degrees, but in some projects will include individuals at the
masters or baccalaureate level provided they contribute in a substantive way to the scientific development or execution of the pro1'ect. Include present
membership on any Federal Government public advisory committee. List, In chronological order, the titles, all authors, and complete references to all
publications during the past three years and to representative eadier publications pertinent to this application. D0 NOT EXCEED TWO PAGES.
1972: Clinical Investigation Training Fellowship, University of Rochester, Rochester, NY,
Department of Microbiology. Research Director: Dr. Harry Taber
1973: Phi Beta Kappa, University of Rochester, Rochester, NY
1973-1974: French Government Fellowship for Research, Centre de Genetique Moleculaire
CNRS, Gif-sur-Yvette, France. Research Director: Dr. C. Anagnostopoulos
1974-1975: Research Technician, Department of Anatomy, Emory University, Atlanta, GA.
Research Director: Dr. Bryan D. Noe
1976-1978: Research Assistant, Department of Biochemistry and Division of Medical Genetics,
Emory University, Atlanta, GA. Research Director: Dr. Dean J. Danner
1975-1976, 1978-1982: Predoctoral NIH Trainee, Washington University, St. Louis, MO.
ResearchAdvisor: Dr. Ralph A. Bradshaw
1982-1983: NIH Postdoctoral Trainee, Division of Endocrinology, Department of Medicine,
Medical University of S. Carolina, Charleston, SC. Research Director: Dr. Maria Buse
1983-1985: Individual National Research Services Award (NIH Postdoctoral Fellow),
Department of Biological Sciences, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA.
Research Director: Dr. E.W. Jones
1985-1988: Research Biologist (Research Assistant Professor), Department of Biological
Sciences, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA
1988-1996: Assistant Professor, Department of Molecular Biology and Microbiology, Case
Western Reserve University, School of Medicine, Cleveland, OH
May 2-4, 1994: Ad Hoc Member NSF Cell Biology Grant Review Panel, Cellular Organization
1995-1996: NSF Grant Review Panel, Cellular Organization
1995-present: Publications Committee, American Society for Cell Biology
July 1, 1996-: Associate Professor with tenure, Department of Molecular Biology and
Microbiology, Case Western Reserve University, School of Medicine, Cleveland, OH

pgNbr=2
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
