<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>inl36d00</tid>
<bt>50557910/7911</bt>
<ti>PERSONAL BIBLIOGRAPHIC SKETCHES  MICHEL CHRETIEN</ti>
<dd>19970102</dd>
<dt>RESUME</dt>
<!-- Note:d:EDUCATION  ACADEMIC POSITIONS HONOURS &amp; MEMBERSHIP  PUBLICATIONS-->
<!-- Note:dl:20010130-->
<pg>2</pg>
<dl>20021115</dl>
<ot>PERSONAL BIBLIOGRAPHIC SKETCHES
MICHEL CHRETIEN (Co-Investigator) - Effort on this project: 10%
EDUCATION:
Institution Degree Year Field of Study
University of Montreal, Montreal M.D. 1960 Medicine
McGill University, Montreal M.S. 1962 Experimental Medicine
H6te1-Dieu de Montreal Hospital Fellow 1960-62 Clinical Research
McGill University, Montreal Fellow 1960-62 Experimental Medicine
Peter Bent Brigham Hosp. &amp; Harvard University Resident 1962-64 Medicine
University of California, Berkeley Research Fellow 1964-67 Biochemistry
ACADEMIC POSITIONS:
Professor, Dept. of Medicine, Univ. of Montreal, 1967-
Director, Dept. of Molecular Neuroendocrinology, Clinical Research Institute of Montreal, 1967-
Physician, H8te1-Dieu de Montreal Hospital, Montreal, 1967-
Associate Member, Dept. of Experimental Medicine, McGill University, 1967-
Scientific Director &amp; CEO, Clinical Research Institute of Montreal, 1984-94
HONOURS &amp; MEMBERSHIP:
Order of Canada (OC)
Officer, Ordre du Quebec
Fellow of The Royal Society of Canada (FRSC)
Fellow of the American College of Physicians (FACP)
Fellow of the Royal College of Physicians and Surgeons of Canada (FRCP)
Izaak Walton Killam Memorial Price, 1995
McLaughlin Medal, Royal Society of Canada, 1993
D.Sc. (Honoris Causa), Universite Rene Descartes, Paris, France, 1992
D.Sc. (Honoris Causa), Universite de Liege, Belgique, 1980
PUBLICATIONS: TOTAL: 471; Last 5 years: 1992-96: Referred Papers: 66, Book Chapters: 9
Selected Relevant publications for the past 5 years:
Benjannet S, T Reudelhuber, C Mercure, N Rondeau, M Chretien, and NG Seidah (1992) Pro-protein
conversion is determined by a multiplicity of factors including convertase processing, substrate specificity and
intracellular environment. J.Biol.Chem. 267:11417-11423.
Copeland NG, DJ Gilbert, M Chnstien, NG Seidah, and NA Jenkin (1992) Regional localization of three
convertases PCI (Nec-1), PC2 (Nec-2), and Furin (Fur), on mouse chromosomes. Genomics 13:1356-1358.
Day R, MK-H Schafer, SJ Watson, M Chretien, and NG Seidah (1992) Distribution and regulation of the
prohormone convertases PCI and PC2 in the rat pituitary. Mol.Endocrinol. 6:485-497.
Seidah NG, J Hamelin, AM Gaspar, R Day, and M Chr6tien (1992) The cDNA sequence of the human
pro prohormone and pro protein convertase PCI. DNA Cell Biol. 11:283-289.
Seidah NG and M Chr6tien (1992) Pro protein and pro-hormone convertases of the subtilisin family - recent
developments and future perspectives. Trends Endocrinol.Metab. 31:133-140.
Seidah NG, H Fournier, G Boileau, S Benjannet, N Rondeau, and M Chretien (1992) The cDNA structure
of the porcine pro-hormone convertase PC2 and the comparative processing by PCI and PC2 of the
N-terminal glycopeptide segment of porcine POMC. FEBS Lett. 310:235-239.
Seidah NG, R Day, J Hamelin, A Gaspar, MW Collard, and M Chrdtien (1992) Testicular expression of PC4
in the rat: molecular diversity of a novel germ cell-specific Kex2/subtilisin-like proprotein convertase.
Mo l. Endocrinol. 6:1559-1570.
Watson SJ, WE Cullinan, MK-H SchAfer, R Day, M ChrBtien, and NG Seidah (1992) Anatomical studies of
neuropeptide precursor processing enzymes. Clin.Neuropharmacol. 15:315-316.
Benjannet S, N Rondeau, L Paquet, A Boudreault, C Lazure, M Chr6tien, and NG Seidah (1993) Comparative
biosynthesis, covalent post-translational mod fu;ations and efficiency of prosegment cleavage of the
prohormone convertases PCI and PC2: glycosylation, sulphation and identification of the intracellular site
of prosegment cleavage of PCI and PC2. Biochem.J. 294:735-743.
Day R, MK-H Schafer, WE Cullinan, SJ Watson, M C66tien, and NO Seidah (1993) Region specific
expression offurin rnRNA in the rat brain. Neurosci.Lett. 149:27-33.
Jean F, A Basak, N Rondeau, S Benjannet, GN Hendy, NG Seidah, M ChrBtien, and C Lazure (1993)
Enzymic characterization ofmurine and prohormone convertase-1 (mPCI and hPCI) expressed in manunalian
GH4C1 cells. Biochem.J. 292:891-900.
1-2
50557910

pgNbr=1
Lusson J, D Vieau, J Hamelin, R Day, M Chr6tien, and NG Seidah (1993) cDNA structure of the mouse and
rat subtilisin/kexin-like PCS.• a candidate proprotein convertase expressed in endocrine and non endocrine
cells. Proc.Natl.Acad.Sci.USA 90:6691-6695.
Marcinkiewicz M, R Day, NG Seidah, and M Chr6tien (1993) Ontogeny of the prohornwne convertases PCI
and PC2 in the mouse hypophysis and their colocalization wlth corticotropin and a-melanotropin.
Proc.Natl.Acad.Sci.USA 90:4922-4926.
Schafer MK-H, R Day, WE Cullinan, M ChrBtien, NG Seidah, and SJ Watson (1993) Gene espression of
prohonnone proprotein convertases in the rat CNS: a comparative in situ hybridization analysis. J.Neurosci.
13:1258-1279.
Seidah NG, M Day, M Marcinkiewicz, and M Chr6tien (1993) Mammalian paired basic amino acids
convertases of prohormones and proproteins. Ann.N.Y.Acad.Sci. 680:135-146.
Seidah NG and M Chrdtien (1993) 7he family of pro-hormone and pro protein convertases.
Biochem.Soc.Trans. 21:685-691.
Decroly E, M Vandenbranden, JM Ruysschaert, J Cogniaux, GS Jacob, SC Howard, G Marshall, A Kompelli,
A Basak, F Jean, C lazure, S Benjannet, M Chretien, R Day, and NG Seidah (1994) DZe convertasesfurin
and PCI can both cleave the human invnunodeficiency virus (I37V)-1 envelope glycoprotein gp160 into gp120
(HIV-I SU) and gp41 (HIV-1 TM). J.Biol.Chem. 269:12240-12247.
Ftouhi N, R Day, M Mbikay, M ChrBtien, and NG Seidah (1994) Gene organization of the mouse
pro-hormone and pro protein convertase PCI. DNA Cell Biol. 13:395-407.
Marcinkiewicz M, D Ramla, NG Seidah, and M Chr6tien (1994) Developmental expression of the prohormone
convet7ases PCI and PC2 in mouse pancreatic islets. Endocrinology 135:1651-1660.
Mbikay M, M-L Raffin-Sanson, H Tadros, F Sirois, NG Seidah, and M Chr6tien (1994) Structure of the gene
for the testis-specific proprotein convertase 4 and of its alternative messenger RNA isoforms. Genomics
20:231-237.
Seidah NG, M Chr8lien, and R Day (1994) The family of subtilisin/kexin like pro protein and pro-hormone
convertases, divergent or sharedfunctions. Biochimie 76:197-209.
Seidah NG and M Chr6tien (1994) Pro-protein convertases of subtilisin/kexin family. Methods Enzymol.
244:175-188.
Vieau D, NG Seidah, M Mbikay, M ChrEtien, and X Bertagna (1994) Expression of the prohormone
convertase PC2 correlates with the presence of corticotropin-like intermediate lobe peptide in human
adrenocorticotropin-secreting tumors. J.Clin.Endocrinol.Metab. 79:1503-1506.
Basak A, A Boudreault, A Chen, M Chr6tien, NG Seidah, and C Lazure (1995) Application of the Multiple
Antigenic Peptides (MAP) strategy to the production of prohormone convertases antibodies: synthesis,
characterization and use of 8-branched immunogenic peptides. J.Pept.Sci. 1:385-395.
Benjannet S, D Savaria, M Chr6tien, and NG Seidah (1995) 7B2 is a specific intracellular binding protein
of the prohormone convertase PC2. J.Neurochem. 64:2303-2311.
Benjannet S, J Lusson, J Hamelin, D Savaria, M ChrF:tien, and NG Seidah (1995) Structure function studies
on the biosynthesis and bioactivity of the precursor convertase PC2 and the formation of the PC2/7B2
complex. FEBS Left. 362:151-155.
Chr6tien M, M Mbikay, L Gaspar, and NG Seidah (1995) Proprotein convertases and the pathophysiology
of human diseases: prospective considerations. Proc.Assoc.Am.Physicians 107:47-66.
Dong W, M Marcinkiewicz, D Vieau, M Chr€tien, NG Seidah, and R Day (1995) Distinct mRNA expression
of the highly homologous convertases PCS and PACE4 in the rat brain and pituitary. J.Neurosci.
15:1778-1796.
Malide D, NG Seidah, M Chr6tien, and M Bendayan (1995) Electron microscopy immunocytochemical
evidence for the involvement of the convertases PCI and PC2 in the processing of proinsulin in pancreatic
S-cells. J.Histochem.Cytochem. 43:11-19.
Mbikay M, NG Seidah, M Chr6tien, and EM Simpson (1995) Chromosomal assignment of the genes for
proprotein convenases PC4, PCS and PACE4 in mouse and human. Genomics 26:123-129.
Seidah NG, S Benjannet, S Pareek, D Savaria, J Hamelin, B Goulet, J Laliberte, C Lazure, M ChrBtien, and
RA Murphy (1996) Cellular processing of the nerve growth factor precursor by the manunalian proprotein
convertases. Biochem.J. 314:951-960.
Seidah NG, S Benjannet, S Pareek, M Chrdtien, and RA Murphy (1996) Cellular processing of the
neurotrophin precursors of NT3 and BDNF by the maitvnalian pro protein convertases. FEBS Left.
379:247-250.
Seidah NG, J Hamelin, M Mamarbachi, W Dong, H Tadros, M Mbikay, M ChrBfien, and R Day (1996)
cDNA structure, tissue distribution and chromosomal localization of rat PC7.• a novel nmrtnmalian proprotein
convertase closest to yeast kexin-like proteinases. Proc.Natl.Acad.Sci.USA 93:3388-3393.
2-2
50557911

pgNbr=2
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
