<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>aan1aa00</tid>
<bt>HT0039047/9047</bt>
<ti>INDUSTRY RAPS CANCER REPORT, THE EVENING BULLETIN</ti>
<dd>19550606</dd>
<dt>NEWS CLIPPING</dt>
<au>EVENING BULLETIN;UP</au>
<bx>097</bx>
<!-- Note:dp:19960131-->
<!-- Note:rn t="m":132-->
<!-- Note:s:HOYT-->
<np>HARTNETT TV;TIRC;HAMMOND C;HORN D</np>
<!-- Note:d:TOBACCO SPOKESMAN ATTACKS FIGURES SAYING MORE RESEARCH NEEDS TO BE DONE AND MORE FACTORS TAKEN INTO ACCOUNT-->
<!-- Note:lu:MNAG-->
<pg>1</pg>
<dl>20020201</dl>
<ot>~ ~ '• ~ ~ ~ 5
, ~",~tc,~-~E,-17
"flte rate for two-pack-a-day-I THB r;VFCNING BiJ1,I£TIN
r mimes as~k gh as the rate for Fililadelphia, Penna.
Lung Cancer Called RiQ Killer ~
men who have never smoked,•' the Jtlfle 6, 1955
Of ~~~~y~a~lr11jv~~~ggy ~pg,e®~®~C rcnort %a•ent on. 'The rate for Sixty-threr per cent of the
6/ t~I ..I rw eJ men who have given up cigarettr chest surgeon•. 54 per cent of the
By PIFdi1tE C. FBALEY 'moking is 14 times as high as researthers and half of the path-
tnttvey, (areGwnia of the lung thr rate for men who have netier olo&gt;'ists checkr! '•yes' to the
iacoounted for 12 r cent of a11
lt
tl
SI
O
TM 8
e
AUantic Ctty. June 6 - 71te
g
p for men xho uere .qtoking 1eaE Gearettes may lead to lung can-
ond only to cononary artery dia- than a pack of ct.ar"itee a da3l cer.
ease as a killer. at the tam~ of q11~'• 1~"ninc, '1
'
'
'
ng
e
y.
.
men
e-
hr
no
i
rangrd from faur en
tween the ages of 50 and 70 con I The death rate from careinomn In the light of thebo findings. rN en pcr crnt. Thc remaindcr
tinues to Indicate that lung catt• of the lung increasec with the the dnrtorc tcaid, it seems prob- «cm unccrtain.
cer and cigarette smoking go ~~f of cigarette smokLtg ahlr that giving up arnolun; even The ,: o reports were presented
hand-in-hand. lesas With Pipe Smokere ait^r years of regular smoking at a syTnpnaium on t!ancer and
Dr. 8~yler Hammond, dlmti Lung cancer also appears to be m..y result in a reductlon in the medicine at the opening session
tor, and Dr. t&gt;aniel Horn, assist- associated with pipe smoking but rj-k of developing ,ng cancer. t of the A 31A convention.
ant director of staUsUwl rg'10 a!ar lesser degree than with Ho.vever• the number of cases. .~000 Are Attending
^u avatlablc for detailed analy-
search, reported toda) at the Icigarette smoking. Ther! seems r'
104th annual meeting of the to be no significant tleup between ws Is not great enough to state Some 13,000 doctors and L^,lln0
Amerlcan Medical Association ondgar smoking and lung cancer- that such a conclusion has been; guests are sehedvled to attend
^vcd beyond reasonable doubt.' the aveek-long series of meetings.
a 32-month follow-up on the The rate of lung cancer was
~
tmmkiine babita and fate of men 1 high in cigarette smokers and low More evidence is needed, they' On 1Lesday evening. Dr. Elmer
In this age group. In non-smokers regardless of said. Hess. of Erie. will be inaugurated
Tbe report is an attenslon ot whether they lived In a city or in • Sun•ey of Spor.lall•ts as Pt'esidcnt of the AMA He sna
the one at the AMA oomMntion the country. 1~fowever, smoktngl ~~ Dr- Walter 8 Mattin, of
~~ In another type of survey con-~ Norfolk. Va
last year dealing with habits were not able to stxountl ducted by the American Cancerl Another highlight of the ean-
death rates that,caused tobaeeo for ail of the hlgher death rate Soclety, a majority of chest surrv ventlon will be a symposium on
atoeks to plummet a total of 577,- from lung cantxr In Urban ereas g~m, cancer researchers and the control of polio. Among the
000.0001n a few days. as compared with rural areas. pathologist.c who were questiotr experts scheduled to partlclpate
B®ra Among 3TOmlimokera ~ the 3•t months of the ed said they believed heavy pgar- are Dr. Jonas E Salk, developer
wrvey there were 152 deaths ette smoking may lead to luno of the polio vaccine: Dr. Leonard
Today's report, concentrating from • carcinoma of the lung. can.. A. Scheele, surgeon general of the
•mairdy on the most widespread among the 108,000 men who sald f Dr. qt~les S. Cameron, medi- U. S. Public Health Serv[ce. and
type of lung rant~t'. tarcinotna, they smoked regufarly. This is 81 cal and scientific director of the Dr. Thomas Fl-ands, Jr, of the
~'= to ~~ cen~u~ong' ratio of 145 out of every 1t10.0011. A~• reported on the results of a UmvErsity of Michigan• who re-
Althottgh cat'cinotna of the This eornpares with a dealh rate qu~ty,rnnalre sent to a sample of ported on the sut'cega of the vae-
8 Is a"rare disease ammng•of 4.9 per 100,000 in non-smokcrs. the theee types of spetNalists, cine used in a n+ass test last year.
men who have never amokev:," It pg ~~ m~~
Is °an lntportant cause of d
ath
e
among men stnoking two or more "1n this group the rate for men
packs of clgerettea a day." with a history of regular cigar-
'Phe+e were 4,430 men who ette smoking was about 29 times
smoked two packs or more in the its high as the rate for men who
never smoked,° the doctors re-
ported.
Industry Raps
CancerRe~rt
Tobacco Spokesman
AftacEts Figures
New York, June ~fUP)-
lUnotltiyr H. Hartnett, chaftman
of the Tobaeco Indasqy Rekearch
Comlttae, totlay urged smokeru
not to be "rnlaled by sweeping
generalities" In a doctors' report
on the relatlotuhlp between
smoking and lung cancer.
Hartnett, ~hose organisatton
is tbnduc~irtg its own survey Into
fung rancer, charged that the tre•
port taeleared today In Atlantlc
Gty "ignores tmportant envtt+ari-
mental. geograpwca. occupatfon-
til, physical and emotional tactats
effecting disease and longevity."
American Cancer Society's long.
ta
e
tud
of 1g6
000
b
u
/
e
n
aJ, p
~moked but only half as high as statement that hravcmokin of
deaths In this u and was seo- y' g
ro
M EVENMG BU'LTIsTaQ
I Philadelp'niet, Penlna.
Jtlne 6, 1955
"19te use of big petnetttage tig-
ures ... obscvres the fact that
they are dealing with only 168
proven primary lung cancer cases
among 283 reported treses, out Of
8.105 deaths which occurred in a
32,month period -among 1B7A00
men who were 50 to 70 years old
at the start of the tnuvty over
three years ago," he said.
Hartnett also chaeged that the
quertlonnaire used by Des. E
Cuyler Hammond and Daniel
Horn contained bfae "so giwat as
to make questionable the validity
of aqy oonc]uslone .,:' 8ome of
the questions were leading. Hart-
ttett said, and use of the term
'heavy otnoking" suggested excess
which anyh ~~'y
. in
laboratory research during the
past year. has falled to, provlde
any proof that ettrooking causes
lmut cancer. Hartnett said,
EE,TROIT FREE PRESS
Detroit, Michigan
June 7, 1955
DOGT®RS FILE REPORT
Cancer Danger Seen
In Use of Whisky
Opedat to tn.Ine. Rra.
ATS.AN'PIC C1TY - Whtsky-drinkfng has been added to
tfatoMng as a posafble canee of cancer, tht+ee pbyatefana
tevealed here • ffioattay In a report to the American Medioal
~at~iag~ or cancer of the and plpe amokera, they lound,
llaryatt, or vofce box, is greatly run about the ttame risk as men
itnoreaeed, their tepart said, by wht. atmke 1e to 34 olgaaets
hea~y smoking nlone, or camn•
bined Ylth heavy dt'fng ing.
e e e
TVE r1E1rYSIa9AN9r lha 1®ea-
cat Wyader, Itsvln J. Btoae and
ltmeraop Da,y, of the Slotm-Sot-
tet•ing abatftute. based their trn-
port an tnterviewa in Bwedea,
lbdla and the Vnited States.
Men detntdng more than tt1z
otmoao af wibfasy o day oppeatt
aeve® tlmes more B1oolly to de-
veloo Ieryea eanocr than non-
tlrln~eee who do an ®ama
amount of amoking, any utdl.
They said the rlak of cancer In
the larynx tncreasea wlfh the
tlaaottnt oY eigarete amoked. Qgar
da1LY•
a7em this and other etutlleR
Dr. VPynder said, -ne pteaeat
tetes of lung and tatytt: cancer
In AmerleBn malaa probably
would be aedttced bygqpe~ o~t
in the absence of em8klag.°
The report linking oaaear i!o
amoldng oame under boaVd AS
from the tobacco fnduetry.
Ttmotby V. Biarunott. channim
or the totu+etw tnduetry reatas&gt;mi
c'omtaittee, aald that "competent
opinion research authorlUea" ovn-
aldered that the polll was "blased,
nonselentifie and filled with
ahortoominge and deteeta."

pgNbr=1
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
