<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>inn36d00</tid>
<bt>50570560/0563</bt>
<ti>CURRICULUM VITAE  FREDERICK FENGTIEN KAO</ti>
<dd>19880202</dd>
<dt>RESUME</dt>
<!-- Note:d:EDUCATION, PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE, MONOGRAPHS AND BOOKS, AND PUBLICATIONS-->
<!-- Note:dl:20010130-->
<pg>4</pg>
<dl>20021115</dl>
<ot>CURRICULUM VITAE
FREDERICK FENGTIEN KAO
Date of Birth: January 29, 1919, Peking, China
Citizenship: U.S.A.
Marital Status: Married, Edith Chung-Ying Ling; son, John Jien Kao
Education:
Jefferson Academy, Tungchou, China, 1934-37
B.S. Yenching University, Peking &amp; Chengtu, China, 1945
M.D..West China Union University, College of Medical Sciences, Chengtu,
China, 1947.
M.S. Northwestern University Graduate School, Chicago, Illinois, 1950.
Ph.D. Northwestern University Graduate School, Chicago, Illinois, 1951.
Professional Experience: National
Professor of Physiology &amp; Biophysics State University of New York
Downstate Medical Center,
Brooklyn, New York
1965-Present
Associate Professor of Physiology State University of New York
Downstate Medical Center
1960-1965
Assistant Professor of Physiology State University of New York
Downstate Medical Center
1956-1960
Instructor in Physiology
Instructor in Medical Physics
Research Fellow
State University of New York
Downstate Medical Center
1952-1956
Yale University Medical School
New Haven, Conti
1951-1952
Northwestern University Medical School, 1949-1951
Resident in Internal Medicine
Wesley Memorial Hospital, Chicago,.Illinois, 1948-1949
Resident and Teaching Assistant in Pathology
West China Union University, University Hospitals,Chengtu,China
1947-1948
50570560

pgNbr=1
`~~D kfqoL
Scientific papers - continued
pv'WtAi ys rg~\-~v ci7' Cp"
An animal model of Cheynes-Stokes breathing.
N.S.Cherniack, C. von Fuler, I. Homma and F.F. Kao.
Acta Physiol.scand. Suppl. 473, p.39, 1979
Central organization of exercise input.
F.F. Kao, S.S. Mei, A.M. Babich and I.R. Moss.
In: CENTRAL INTERACTION BET(dEEN RESPIRATORY AND CARDIOVASCULAR CONTROL SYSTEMS.
Editors: H.P. Koepchen, S.M. Hilton and A. Trzebski. Springer Verlag, Berlin
pp. 158-167, 1980
V - Pco2 response curves and respiratory patterns in dogs with vagotomy and/or sinus
nerve denervation.
Y.C.Tu, T.P.Chen, C. Hsiao, S.S.Mei and F.F.Kao.
Fed. Proc. 39:372, 1980
Effects of COZ and 02 on the electrical phenomena of medullary respiratory
neurons in rabbits.
C. Hsiao, T.P.Chen, Y.C.Tu and F.F.Kao.
Fed. Proc. 39: 952, 1980
Experimental evidence supporting the neurogenic hypothesis of exercise hyperpnea.
Frederick F. Kao
Proceedings of XXVIIIth IUPS, (Budapest) XIV: 155, 1980
Experimental differentiation of respiratory tidal volume and frequency control in dogs
during hypercapnia.
T.P.Chen, C. Hsiao, Y.C. Tu, S.S.Mei and F.F.Kao .
Proceedings of XXVIIIth IUPS (Budapest), XIV: 354, 1980
Hypercapnic and hyper-hypoxoic effects on inspiratory and -expiratory neuronal
activities in rabbits.
C. Hsiao, T.P.Chen, Y.C. Tu and F.F.Kao
Proceedings of XXVIIIth IUPS, (Budapest) XIV: 480, 1980
Endocapnia and exocapnia:their relationship to exercise hyperpnea
Frederick F. Kao and Sarah S. Mei
Adv. Physiol. Sci. Volume 10:253-262, 1981 Akademiai Kiado, Pergamon Press, London
11
50570562

pgNbr=2
Publications of Dr F. F. Kao - continued
MONOGRAPHS AND BOOKS
As Editor:
CEREBROSPINAL FLUID AND THE REGULATION OF VENTILATION
Editors: Chandler McC. Brooks, Frederick F. Kao and Brian B. Lloyd
Blackwell Scientific Publications, Oxford, 1965
RESEARCH IN PHYSIOLOGY
Editors: Frederick F. Kao, Kiyomi Koizumi, and Mario Vassalle
Aulo Gaggi Publisher, Bologna, 1971
CHINESE MEDICINE-NEW MEDICINE
Editors: Frederick F. Kao and John J. Kao
Neale Watson Academic Publications, New York, 1978
RECENT ADVANCES IN ACUPUNCTURE RESEARCH
Editors; Frederick F. Kao and John J. Kao'
Institute for Advanced Research in Asian Science and Medicine. 1979
As Author:
AN INTRODUCTION TO RESPIRATORY PHYSIOLOGY
Frederick F. Kao
Economic Research Institute Printing Office, Taipai, Taiwan, 1957
AN INTRODUCTION TO RESPIRATORY PHYSIOLOGY
Frederick F. Kao
Excerpta Medica, Amsterdam 1972
Reprinted by American Elsevier Publishing Company Inc., New York, 1974
ACUPUNCTURE THERAPEURICS
Frederick F. Kao and John J. Kao
Triple Oak Publishing Company, Ltd. 1973
RESPIRATORY RESEARCH IN THE PEOPLE'S REPUBLIC OF CHINA
Frederick F. Kao
Fogarty International Center for Advanced Study in the Health Sciences.
U.S. Department of Health, Education and Welfare, Public Health Services,
National Institute of Health. DHEW Publication No. (NIH) 75-770, 1975
1
50570561

pgNbr=3
Kao, F.F. and S. S. Mei. Endocapnia and exocapnia:their relationship
to exercise hyperpnea. Advances in Physiological Science, 10:253-262.
1981, Akademia Kiado, Pergamon Press, London.
Kalia, M.,S. S. Mei, and F. F. Kao. Central projections from
ergoreceptors ( C fibers ) in muscle involved in cardiopulmonary
responses to static exercise. Circulation Research (suppl. 1)
48:48-62 1981.
Chen, T., S.S.Mei, and F. Kao. Central mechanisms of ventilation
instability during muscular exercise. Federation Proceedings,
41:1689, 1982.
Chen, T. S. S. Mei, and F. Kao. COZ and 02 effects on medullary
respiratory neurons in cats. Federation Proceedings, 42:1253, 1983
Yongquing Jin, Frederick F. Kao, Tsupin Chen, Sarah Mewi, George A. Vas,
and Roger Cracco. Voluntary hypoventilation effects on V-Pco2 curves and
its correlation to EEG in man. Fed. Proc. 42:1252, 1983
Budzinska, K.,Curt von Euler, Frederick F. Kao, Tito Pantaleo, and Yuji
Yamamoto. Effects of graded focal cold block in the solitary and
para-ambigual regions of the medulla in cat. Acta Physiol Scand.
124:317-328, 1985
Budzinska, K.,Curt von Euler, Frederick F. Kao, Tito Pantaleo, and Yuji
Yamamoto. Effects of graded focal cold block in rostral areas of
medulla. Acta Physiol Scand. 124:329-340, 1985
Budzinska, K.,Curt von Euler, Frederick F. Kao, Tito Pantaleo, and Yuji
Yamamoto. Release of expiratory muscle activity by graded focal cold
block in the medulla. Acta Physiol Scand. 124:341-351, 1985
Frederick F. Kao, T. P. Chen, and S. S. Mei. From volitional control of
breathing to exercise hyperpnea. Nobel Conference on Neurobiology of the
Control of Breathing:Morphology, Neurophysiology, Neuropharmacology and
Development. Stockholm, September 4-6, 1985
Frederick F. Kao, Tsu Pin Chen, and Sarah S, Mei. Neural pathways in
controlling breathing during exetcise. In: Nobel Conference on
Neurobiology of the Control of Breathing. Raven Press, New York, 1986
Frederick F. Kao and Ginger McRae. Chinese medicine in America: the
rocky road to ecumenical medicine. Impact of Science on Society. number
143, The Revolution in health care: new attitudes to old approaches.
1986. UNESCO
12
50570563

pgNbr=4
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
