<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>jnj1aa00</tid>
<bt>HT0035196/5196</bt>
<ti>SMOKING LEFT TO PUBLIC BY HEALTH CHIEF STAR TUCSON, ARIZONA</ti>
<dd>19621203</dd>
<dt>NEWS CLIPPING</dt>
<au>STAR;NY TIMES NEWS SERVICE</au>
<bx>097</bx>
<!-- Note:dp:19960131-->
<!-- Note:rn t="m":132-->
<!-- Note:co:MAR;MUL-->
<!-- Note:s:HOYT-->
<np>CELEBREZZE AJ;HEW;USPHS;NIH;FDA</np>
<!-- Note:lu:MNAG-->
<pg>1</pg>
<dl>20020201</dl>
<ot>Anthony J. Celebrezze, Secretary of xealth, Educetion and Welfbtiz'e®d~a~ 5196
Washington nevemen that he didn't intend to give up smoking because of
the cancer scare. He said he didn't think government should tell the
individual to atop smoking.
`
i
TIE NE,id YORK TIM
New YorDs, New York
December 3, 1962
botA ektes"-the tobacco In•
t
d
e
gmoking. tiome waa
~~'~ ~~~~ dustry and the voluntary health cigarette packa labeled with a
jINNIJD All oegaalwtlons=and to the dov dg".trr slRo.
aona eoutd
w
d
l
b
'
~va
,
ew
a
oeo
~ gteM ce
e
raae
have taken a public stand on not tndlcato a a~tft In thlnk-
oH S~Q~llll~ I55 VL tbe Isstte.
Ing by the Adatlnlstratba, at
_ 7110 Government kas mapped teast it puts an Influential of•
a taoo•part p t to consider rictal on record against atresg
dWould Not Bid Government ~e pmbtem T~Hretpart uvln aetlon by the aovernment
Tell People to Stop o~a ~oldng aandmh~lth by dihme mleteThe e, ma ~eurgeoaadviscryaeneconral
ackatlno paneL The panel wlll Luther L Terry. met Nov. 9
8 SOBttBT 0. TO'17l also examine "possible contrl• ~ 10 to otganise Ite activl.
~ Y m ~ Np 4~ ~ uUon buting factors, Industrlat such es expsaure.alr pol- ties. Each memtw was given
e. [In• c areas to study.
WABIIII~tti1"ON, Der: 2- halaUoa of cAemlcals, for ex• ~a
Even I[ wnoldng Is found haem• amplel. radiation and alcohol." Besides looking at lung can.
IUl by a scteatlge committee The panel's report laexpec ted cer and heart dlsease, the panel
now t'eriowlRg the evldenae, the tn the spring or summer. It will will considerposslble links be•
Oovernment abould aot tell be limited to the scientists' con. tween smok nf g and peptta
bladder caacer and em•
te to 61ve up tdgen!ttes
sa cluslone on tae • nawre and e lcere
,
.
to the Bemrtary of magnttude" of the hatatd p1U'sema (lung coagesuon), a
MIth, Rduoatlon and Wellere The second part of the pro. -40kesman reported.
Anthony J. Oetebrrso, wko gram. to be undertaken only
took over the job four moatbsi after tse sMentleta have fin.
ago, said it was "peoper !o! Uro ~bed their work, witt be to
Goverament to get aa espnt [oimulate recommendattons
eommlttee to deteiasfae tt tt's for actkm." Who will nuke the
true or not" that mttoktag wes reeommeadatlons fms not yet
a dl been declded
The~ nga ~ ahould be laid fraeltlou a Ye.e1 Age
before the pubno for It to de• tyhim, the Government said
clde what actlon to tatte, be im june It would essmine the
added in an Interview. oontroversy indicatlons were
'a elnaly belleve that It Is it waa laylng_ the foundation
not the proper rote of the Fed• tor Itve ctloa.a
eral Coverntemt to tell cltlstss Three years age the gtuo to stop smoking° whatever the Genqal, then pe, tooy
scientfeta conelude, he deelsred: Ceyr, said the (iovernment'a
The BecreW~r, whose te• tlon aroe that tbe evidence
aponaIbnltlea include the Putalo = implicated smoking as "the
Health tlenlce end Its National mtewinet atininatnwl t.muw..
insUtutes of 8ealth, the Food Uvpl ~actar In the Increaa~M ia-
and the DrUff Adminletratton cldence of lung cancer."
and other h tA.6en des. sald That posltlon still atand4 and
he had a"reauatlc" attitude few sdm,tift contend that any
towarit the smWect new evidence will reverse It.
ltzantplea elven Moreover, the (lovernmest's•
'Tou can kill yourself by move thla year catne after pub•
overeating. overdrinkmg end llcatlon of aa authoritative re-
other overindulgences." he said. port by the Royal College of
"ProhlblUon did not work. And PAyNclans le Britain. It sald
we don't prevent the sale of rat that heavy smoken rau 80
poison. although It can kill times mote a sislt of
humans." lung cancer aod two to three
Mr. Oelebresae smokes about times mote of heaet dleeaee
apac kage of cigarettes a day. tban no~olara
A panel of ten sclentlsts wes After the repert, detnande
set up by the Public HealtA were made In this coun - aome
4Setvvlce Oct 87, after a delay bY ea, for aVIRn•
m choosing the members. The ment education apafEtl to In'
experts had to be acceptable to form cltlsene, paetlcularly
young people, of the danger of
STAR
Tucson, Ar!.zona
December 3, 19:2
t
,Smoking Left
To Public By
Health Chief
• 11101 N" YER Tanp R..e S• ••..
wASHINGiON, Dec. 2 -
Even ifAMp9pL is found to
be harm T6y'a scientitir
committee now reviewing the
evidence, the government
should not tell citizens to Fitie
up cigarettes, according in
the secretary of health, edura-
tion and areifare.
Anthony J. Celebrezte, who
took over the job four montha
ago, said It was "proper for
the government to get an ex-
pert committee to determine
If it's true or not" that smok-
ing is a health hazard.
'Ibe flndings should then
be laid before thepu blic for
Individuals to decide what
action to take. Celebrezze
said in an interview.
'i firmly believe that it
is not the proper role of the
federal government to tell
.citixens to stop smoking"
whatever the scientists eon-
dude, he said.
The icabmet officer, whose
reaponsibiilties Include the
Public Health Service and its
National Institutes of Health,
the Food and Drug Adminis-
tration and othergovarnment
health agencies, said he takes
a "realfstic" attitude toward
the subJeot.
'You can kWyo ursetf by
oveteating, ovmdfinkinp, and
other overindulgences, he
said. "h1»hibition did not
work. And we don't prevent
the sale of rat poison aithou8h
it can kill humans."
The secretary smokes one
package or less of cigarettes
a dav.

pgNbr=1
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
