<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>ind06d00</tid>
<bt>50493176/3177</bt>
<ti>BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH  SAMUEL R. NEWCOM</ti>
<dd>19930201</dd>
<dt>RESUME</dt>
<au>NEWCOM SR</au>
<!-- Note:d:EDUCATION, RESEARCH TRAINING, PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE, HONORS, BIBLIOGRAPHY-->
<!-- Note:dl:20010130-->
<pg>2</pg>
<dl>20021115</dl>
<ot>FF _ Principal InvastlgatortProgram Director (LasL first, middte): Newcom, Samuel R.
BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH
Give the following InformaUon for the key personnel and consultants and ccllabortors. Begin with the principal
Investigatodprogram director. Photocopy this page for each person.
NAME
Samuel R. Newcom
POSITION TITLE
Associate Professor of Medicine
EDUCATION (Begin with baccalaureate or otherlnitial prolessiona! education, such as nursing, and inGude postdoctoral training.)

INSTITUTION AND LOCATION	
DEGREE	YEAR
CONFERRED	
FIELD OF STUDY
University of California,	A.B.	1965	Chemistry
Berkeley and Santa Barbara			
University of Southern California	M.D.	1969	Medicine
Los An eles			
RESEARCH AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE: Concluding with present position, list, in chronological order, previous employment, experience, and
honors. Key personnel Include the principal investigator and any other individuals who participate In the sclentlfic development or execution of the project.
Key personnel typically wlll Inctude all individuals with doctoral or other professional degrees, but in some projects will Include individuals atthe masters or
baccalaureate level provided they contribute In a substantive way to the scientific development or execution of the project. Include present membership on
any Federal Government public advisory committee. Ust, In chronologlcal order, the tiUes, all authors, and complete references to all publications dudng the
past three years and to representallve earlier publlca8ons pertinent to this appltcagon. DO.NOT EXCEED TWO PAGES.
Research Training:
1966-68 Research Fellow, Division of Immunology, Department of Medicine
Principal Investigator: Dr. George J. Friou, University of
Southern California, Los Angeles,
Support, National Institute of Allergy and Immunology
1973-74 Research Fellow, Cell Culture and Cellular Immunology, Principal
Investigators: Drs. Marshall E. Kadin and Stephen B. Shohet
University of California, San Francisco, Support, National Cancer
Institute
1978-79 Postdoctoral Fellow, Growth Factor Characterization &amp; Purification
Principal Investigator: Dr. Denis Gospodarowicz, University of
California, San Francisco, Support, National Institutes of Health
Professional Experience.:
1969-70 Medical Intern and Senior Assistant Surgeon, USPHS, Staten Island,
New York
1970-72 Resident in Internal Medicine, University of Southern California
1972-73 Fellow in Medical Oncology, Cancer Research Institute, University
of California, San Francisco
1973-74 Fellow in Hematology/Medical Oncology, University of California,
San Francisco
1974-75 Instructor in Medicine, University of Oregon, Portland
1975-79 Assistant Clinical Professor of Medicine, Chief, Medical Oncology
Clinic, Cancer Research Institute, University of California, San
Francisco
1979-82 Assistant Professor of Medicine, Chief Medical Oncology,
University of Oregon, Portland
1982-84 Associate Professor of Medicine, Chief Medical Oncology,
University of Oregon, Portland
1984- Associate Professor of Medicine, Emory University School of
Medicine, Atlanta, Attending Physcian, Grady Memorial Hospital
Honors:
A.B. cum laude
Junior Faculty Fellow, American Cancer Society, 1980-83
Who's Who in the West, 1984,1985
Bibliography: (selected from 2 books, 35 peer-reviewed publications, 32
abstracts and 8 chapters)
1. Kadin ME, Newcom SR, Gold SB, Stites DP: Origin of Hodgkin's cells.
Lancet ii:167-168, 1974
PHS 398 (Rev. 9/91) (Form Page 6) Page _ FF
Number pages consecuevely ar ttw bottom throughout the epplicaeon. Do not use suffixes such as 3e, 3b.

pgNbr=1
Princlpal InvestlgatorlProgram Director (Last, first, middle): Newcom, Samuel R.
2. Newcom SR: Hodgkin's disease. West J Med 127:487-496, 1977
3. Newcom SR, Kadin ME: T-cell leukemia with thymic involution:
transplantation to the athymic mouse brain. Cancer 43:622-626, 1979
4. Newcom SR, Kadin ME: Prednisone in the treatment of allergen-
associated angioimmunoblastic lymphadenopathy. Lancet i:462-464, 1979
5. Linker CA, Newcom SR, Nilsson CM, Wolf JL, Shuman MA: Combined
idiopathic immune neutropenia and thrombocytopenia: a study of cell
surface autoantibodies. Ann Int Med 93:704-707, 1980
Newcom SR, O'Rourke L: Potentiation of fibroblast growth by nodular
sclerosing Hodgkin's disease cell cultures. Blood 60:228-237, 1982
Newcom SR, O'Rourke L: Oat cell carcinoma with fibrosis: Evidence for
release of a growth substance. Cancer 49:2358-2364, 1982
Goodman GE, Jones SE, Villar HV, Silverstein ME, Dabich L,
Newcom SR: Surgical restaging of Hodgkin's disease. Cancer
Treat Rep 66:751-757, 1982
Elliott WC, Newcom SR, Houghton DC, DeFehr J, Bennett WM: Cis-
diaminedichloroplatinum nephrotoxicity: tubular function after rescue
with sodium diethyldithiocarbamate in rats. Cancer Res 43:3759-3762,
1983
Donlon TA, Litt M, Newcom SR, Magenis RE: Localization of the
restriction fragment length polymorphism D14S1 (pAW-101) to chromosome
14q 32.1 leads to 32.2 by in situ hybridization. Am J Hum Genet
35:1097-1106, 1983
Newcom SR: The Hodgkin's cell in nodular sclerosis does not release
Interleukin-1. J Lab Clin Med 105:170-177, 1985
Newcom SR, Kadin ME, Ansari AA: Production of transforming growth
factor-beta activity by Ki-1 positive lymphoma cells and analysis of
its role in the regulation of Ki-1 positive lymphoma growth. Am J Path
131:569-577, 1988
Newcom SR, Kadin ME, Ansari AA, Diehl V: The L-428 nodular sclerosing
Hodgkin's cell secretes a unique TGF-beta active at physiologic pH.
J Clin Invest 82:1915-1921, 1988
Newcom SR, Kadin ME, Phillips CN: L-428 Reed-Sternberg cells and
mononuclear Hodgkin's cells arise from a single cloned mononuclear
cell. Int J Cell Cloning 6:417-431, 1988
Dhingra K, Newcom SR: Acute tumor lysis syndrome in non-Hodgkin's
lymphoma induced by dexamethasone. Am J Hematology 29:115-116, 1988
Kadin ME, Agnarsson BA, Ellingsworth LR, Newcom SR: Immunohistochemical
evidence of a role for transforming growth factor-beta in the
pathogenesis of nodular sclerosing Hodgkin's disease. Am J Path
136:1209-1214, 1990
Newcom SR, Muth LH, Parker ET: Production of monoclonal antibodies
which detect Hodgkin's high molecular weight transforming growth
factor, beta. Blood 75:2434-2437, 1990
Newcom SR, Ansari AA, Gu L: Interleukin-4 is an autocrine growth
factor secreted by the L-428 Reed-Sternberg cell. Blood 79:191-197.
1992
Newcom SR, Tagra KK, Kadin ME: Neutralizing antibodies against
transforming growth factor (TGF) # potentiate the proliferation of Ki-1
positive lymphoma ce1ls:Further evidence for negative autocrine
regulation of TGFS. A J Path 140:709-718, 1992
20. Newcom SR, Tagra KK: Urinary high molecular weight transforming growth
factor 0 in active nodular sclerosing Hodgkin's disease. Cancer Res
(in-press)
21. Newcom SR, Tagra KK, Gu L: The role of Ki-1 antigen in the
autocrine TGF,Q growth regulation of Reed-Sternberg cells, Ki-1
lymphoma cells, and activated thymocytes. Blood 80:305a, 1992
(American Society of Hematology, 1992 meeting. Anaheim, California).
PHS 398 (Rev. 9/91) - Page 8
_ Number pages consecNlvely at the bottom throughout the applloaaon. Do noluse sutlizes such as 3a. 3b.

pgNbr=2
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
