<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<tid>ind68e00</tid>
<bt>2023100295/0303</bt>
<!-- Note:br t="m":2023100283/0303-->
<dd>19830000/E</dd>
<dt>RESU, RESUME</dt>
<dt>BIBL, BIBLIOGRAPHY</dt>
<au>FINE,L</au>
<fn>2023100248/2023100470/INQUIRY COMMENTS NO. 1 CONT'D; </fn>
<!-- Note:si:N28-->
<!-- Note:s:LEGAL DEPT/CARLSTADT-->
<ti>CURRICULUM VITAE</ti>
<pg>9</pg>
<!-- Note:rn t="m":STMN/R1-116; STMN/R1-117-->
<!-- Note:lu:STMN/PRODUCED-->
<!-- Note:dl:19980605-->
<dl>20020201</dl>
<ot>R: REDACTED MATERIAL
CURRICULUM VITAE
~ame: Louis Fine
iome Address:
Office Address:
V U U, V i
Date of Bi.rth:
P1 ace of B i rth : REDACTED
rital Status:
Wife's hame:
Chi 1,dreT:
Sociali Security Number:
Education:
High School:

Dental:	Jeppe Boys' High School
Johannesburg, South Africa
Bachelor of Dental Surgery, 1 iEi
University of Witwatersrand, Jbhannesburg, South Afri;ca
Higher Diploma of Dentistry, 1966
Uhiversity of Witwatersrand, Jbhannesburg, South Africa
Prosthodontic Certificate, 1971
Univerrity of Illinois, Chicago, Illinois
Maxill,ofacial Prosthodontic Certificate, 1972	






0
	Zoller Dental Clinic. University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois	~
State Licensure: Iiiinois - No. 19A1,5405
Current Position:
Associate Professor
Zoller Dental Clinic, University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois
pgNbr=1
R: REDACTED MATERIAL
'F ~G 0'6'0--
'ositions Held:
Consultant, 1981 .- Present
Brown &amp; Williamson Tobacco Company; Louisville, Kentucky
Member, Board of Directors, 1981 - Present
Universal Prosthetics, Inc., Racine, Wisconsin
Associate Professor, Maxillofacial Prosthodontics, 1979 - Present
Assistant Professor, Maxillofacial Prosthodontics, 1972 - 1979
Instructor, Removable and Fixed Prosthodontics, 19711 - 1972
Zoll,er Dental Clinic, University of Chicago; Chicago, Illinois
Instructor, Removable Prosthodontics, 1969 - 1971
University of Illinois; Chicago, Illinois
Instructor, Restorative and Prosthodontic Dentistry, 1962 - 1968
University of Witwatersrand; Johannesburg, South Africa
Private Practice', 1961 - 1969
ComTittee Aoooiintments and Professional Oraanization Merrberships:
REDACTED
pgNbr=2
R: REDACTED MATERIAL
6 Q 6 0-- ge3Three
ommittee Aooointments and Professional Oraanization Memberships (continued):
REDACTED
_ectures Given:
Scope of Maxillofaciall Prosthetics. Uptown Dental Society, 1973; Dental Clinic,
Michael Reese HosDital, 1974; and Dental School, University of Illinois, 1974
Care of the Irradiated Dental Patient. Radiation Therapy Department, Univer-
sity of Chicago, 1973
M1axi11ofacial Prosthodontics at the Zoller Dental Clinic, University of Chicago.
'Groote Schuur-Hospital, University of Cape Town, South Africa, 1973
Maxillofaci•ali Prosthetics: Its Scope and Role in Hospital Dentistry. Univer-
sity of Witwatersrand, Johannesburg, South Africa, 1973
Dental Care of the Irradiated Head and Neck Cancer Patient. 14th Annual Meet-
ing, American Association of Hospital Dentistry, San Diego, 1974; and-Chicago
Oral Surgeons Residents' Association,.1975
A Protocol for Dental Care for the Head and Neck Cancer Patient. Radiation
Therapy and Dental Department,, Michael Reese.Hospital, 1974
Orbital and Ocular Prostheses. Ophthalmology Department, University of Chiicago,
1976
.
George Barnhart Memorial Lecture on Silicone Facial Prostheses. lst International
Syrnposium on,Maxillofacial Prostheses, Arnhem, Holland, 1976
A New Methodlof Coloring Silicone Facial Prostheses. lst International Workshop
on Facial Prostheses, Okkenbroek, Holland, 1976
~ The Silastic 399 Technic Used At Zoller Dental Clinic, University of Chicago.
University of Groningen, Holland, 1976; and University of Utrecht, Holland, 1976
Prosthodontist's Role in the Maxilllectomy Patient. Midwest Academy of Prostho-
dontics, Chicago, 1976
~ Color and Its Application in Maxi;llofacial Prosthetics. American Academy of
Maxillofacial Prosthetics, San Diego, 1976
Facial Prostheses, Uptown Dental Society, Chicago, 1976
pgNbr=3
bL'JUU4
.ectures Given (continued): -
Mandibular Staple Denture. Uptown Dental Society, Chicago, 1976
Dental Hygienist's Role in the Irradiated•Head and.Neck Cancer Patient. South
Suburban Dental Hygienist's Society, 1976
Dental Hygienist's Role in Cancer Patients. Dental Hygienists, North West Uni-
versity, 1977
Platemaker, Platemaker, Make me,a Plate. Chicago Dental Society, South Side
Branch, 1978
Maxi•1'lofacial Prosthesis for the Esthetically and Functional,ly Compromised
Patient: Mucogingival Alteration for Prosthetic Appliances. ddontographic
Society, 1979
The Maxillofacial Prosthodontist's Role in.Management of the Irradiated Head
and Neck Cancer Patient. Karl Brenmer Hospital, University of Stellenbosch,,
Cape Town, South Africa, 1979; and General Hospital, University of Witwatersrand,
Johannesburg, South Africa, 1979
The Scope of Maxillofacial Prosthodontics. University of Witwatersrand, Johan-
nesburg, South Africa, 1979; and University of Stellenbosch, Cape Town, South
Afri ca, 1979
The N,axiliofacial Prosthodontist as a Team Member in the Multidisciplinary
Team Approach in the Management of the Head and Neck Cancer Patient. Tel
Hashaemer Hospital, Te1; Aviv, Israel, 1979
"Wouldn't It be Lovely": The Importance of Cooperationt, Coordination and Coi-
laboration Between Surgeora and Maxillofacial Prosthodontist in the Rehabili-ta-
tion of the Head and Neck Cancer Patient. Institute of Maxillofacial Technol'-
ogy, Stoke-on-Trent, England, 1979	
~	Prosthetic Restoration of the Maxillectomy Patient. Oral Surgery Department,
Michael Reese Hospital, Chicago, 1980	
What Do We Know About Color in Factal Prostheses? University of Texas. San	
AhtDnio, 1980
What the Denturist Doesn't Know - Do You? Chicago Dental Society, West Side	
Branch, 1981		
YestibulopTasty. North West Indiana Dental Society, 1981	N
Prosthodontics in a Hospital Setting.	Dental Clinic, Michael Reese Hospital,	~7
1982		~
Operation Ident/Denture Identification.	Chicago Dental Society, Midwinter	~
Meeting, 1982		O
N
Unusual Prosthodontic Problems. Chicago Academy of Dental Research, 1982 ~~
Rehabilitation of the Head and Neck Cancer Patient. Chicago Dental Society,
Mid+.inter Meeting, 1983
pgNbr=4
.00005
ectures Given (coritinued):
Helpful Hints in Prosthetics. Southlake Dental Study Club, 1983.'
~
pgNbr=5
60 1,BT 8iX
Table Clinics Presented At:
Chicago Midwinter Dental Meeting, 1970, 1971, and 1978
Illinois Dental Association Annual Meeting, 1971
Midwest Academy of Prosthodontics, 1972
Ohio State Dental Association, 1974
American Dental Association, Las Vegas, 1'976
American Prosthodontic Society, Chicago, 1978
Il1inois State Dental Society, 1979
Panel Member:
Grand Rounds on treatment of cancer in the maxillary sinus. Illinois Research
Center, 1974
Multidisciplinary approach to cancer of ttie.head and neck cancer patient.
American Cancer Society and The University of Chicago, 1974
Diagnosis, dental care and rehabilitation of the intraoral'cancer."patient.
American Dental Hygienist's Association, 1975
The multidisciplinary approach to management of head and neck cancer patients.
I~ngalls Memorial Hospital, 1981
Continuing Education Courses Presented:
Prosthodontic aspects in the mandibular staple implant. University of Chicago.
1975, 1976.
Dentures--a service, nat a product. Illinois Masonic Hospital, 1978
The use of prolonged splinting in vestibuloplasties. Chicago Society of Oral
and Maxillofacial Surgeons, 1979
Preventive prosthodontics: Overdentures and immediate dentures. Scott County
Dental Society, Davenport, Iowa. 1980.
~
Overdentures. North West Indiana Dental Society, 1981 N
W
Continuing Education Courses Co-Chai,red: ~
Director for program given by Dr. Andrews, "Andrews' Bridge," 1977 W
Director for program given by Mr. Brian Conroy, "Maxillofacial Rehabilitation O
of the Face and Jaws,"'1979 ~
pgNbr=6
6ooGJig
e Sever„
:ontinuino Education Courses Co-Chaired (continued):
"MandibuTar Staple Implant and Surgical Procedure," given by Drs. Irwin A.
Small and Alfred V."Stines. Co-chaired with Dr. A. T. Indresano, 1981
"The Management and Surgical Correction of Facial and Jaw Deformities,"
given by Mr. Norman L. Rowe and Mr. Brian F. Conroy. Co-chaired with Dr.
A. T. Indresano, 1981!
Publications-
Fine, L., Robinson, J4E., Sharett, T., and Cap, B.F.
Fabrication of a prosthesis for guiding and fixing radioactive sources in the
treatment of cancer of the floor of the mouth. J.P.D,. 30:349-353, 1973
Sharett, T., Fine, L., and Chiang, T.C.
Rapid afterloading with.guide fixation of radioactive sources in cancer of the
oral cavity. A.J. of Roent., Vol. CXX, 182-187, 1974
Fine, L., Robinson, J.E., and Barnhart, G.W.
Absence or major loss of part of the external ear and its correction. J.P.D.
31:313-322, 1474
Fine, L. -
Dental care of the radiated patient. J. Nosp. D. Prac. IX:127-132, 1975
Fine, L.
The George Barnhart Memorial Lecture on. silicone facial prostheses. NADL 33 „
1976
Fine, L., Robinson, J.E., and KarT, L.
Color and its application in maxillofa,cial prosthetics. J.P.D_ 39:188-192,
1978
Fine, L.
Abstract on George Barnhart Memorial lecture on silIcone facial prostheses.
Proceedings: First International Symposium on Facial Prosthetics, p. 61, 1976
Fine, L., Mostofi, R., Wiemann, M.R., Jr., and Crinzi, R.A.
Foreign body-type reaction following crown cementation. J. Perio. 48:294-297,
1977
Fine, L_, Robinson, J.E., and Karl, L.
Room temperature vulcanizing silicone material for the fabrication of facial
prostheses. Proceedings of the Institute of Maxillofacial Technology, pp. 150-
1`56, 1976
Fine, L., Robinson, J.E., and Barnhart, G. W.
Absence or major loss of part of the ear and its correction. Compiled by 7.A.
Curtis, I.M. Ziotolow, and R.E. Gillis. Maxillofacial Prosthetics 123:313-322,
1977
Wolf, E.N., Fine, L., and Cap, B.F.
Acid etched fixed partial prosthesis. J. Acad. Gen. Dent. 28:(1) 50-53, 1980
pgNbr=7
R: REDACTED MATERIAL
L V - V V V
'ublications (continued):
Ko, S.F., Fine, L., and Robinson, J.E.
Total rhinoplasty or prosthesis? J.P.D'. 44:(1)74-76, 1980
WoTf., E.N., Fine, L.,, andlCap, B.F.
Aciid etched fixed partial prosthesis. Quintessemce of Dental TechnoloA!y 4:(7)-
17-1.8 July-Awgust, 1980,
Anglisa L., and Fine, L.
Acnalgam-Composi.te Restoration,. J.P..D. 47:(6)685, 1982
Reisberg, D., Fine, L., Fattore, L., and Edmonds,.D.
A dynami~c splint ini the management of electriical burns of the oral commisswre.
J.P.D~. 49: (1 )71-76., 19,83
'ublications Ln Prooress:
Fine. L.., and Mmstofi, R,.
The effects of sodium morrhuate on,the alveolar bone in rats.
Filne, L.
Oral' candldiasis in the irradiated head andineck cancer patient.
'
Fine,. L.., and I.ndresano, A.T.
Ab evaluation of a vestibuloplasty proceddre currently being used'.
Fi ne, L_
Vestibulopl'asty stents.
Fine, L., and Matz, G.
Prosthodontic management of ai'n+ay obstruction in patients with sleep, apnea.
i
Fine, L.
( The University of Chicago Gullet': An extra-corporeal esopha-geal devi.ce.
:esearch Grants -
k
Rehabilitatton of the Head and! Neck Cancer Patient.
Grant No. 1R78CAZfl,396,©1
Princi.pal In~(estfeator: Martin C. Robson, M.D.
Amount: K - Dr. Fine's tiune: 30'.
Approved and.!funded ftte:• 1/1/78 to 12/31/79
:esearcii Interests:
Fine„ L_
Physi cal and chemi cal pro;pe~rti es of col orants us:ed i n col'ori ng maxil.l o-Pa.ci ali
prostheses
Fine, L_, and Robsont, M:
Measurement o-f forces using, a. headgear prosthesis developed to prevent micro-
stomi a i n the burni pati ent
pgNbr=8
Research Interests:
Fine, L.
Use of MDX 4-4210 as a facial prosthetics material
Fine, L.
Low tar cigarette smoking: Oral aspects
pgNbr=9
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
