<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<tid>inc60c00</tid>
<bt>2071692648</bt>
<!-- Note:br t="m":2071692624/2661-->
<dd>19880121/P</dd>
<dt>NEWS, NEWS ARTICLE</dt>
<au>EGERTON,J</au>
<np>DAVIS,R; HOFFMAN,D; KEENEY,A; KEENEY,LD; MARLOWE,C; MAXWELL,J; WADDELL,W</np>
<ca>COURIER JOURNAL</ca>
<no>AHF, AMERICAN HEALTH FOUNDATION; BW, BROWN &amp; WILLIAMSON; CA BLOCKERS; FDA, FOOD AND DRUG ADMINISTRATION; RJR, R.J.REYNOLDS; UNIV OF KY; UNIV OF LOUISVILLE; US OFFICE OF SMOKING + HEALTH</no>
<!-- Note:co:MARG, MARGINALIA-->
<fn>2071692503/2071692701/STAR SCIENTIFIC; 2071692504/2071692700/STAR TOBACCO</fn>
<!-- Note:si:N508-->
<!-- Note:s:ARWADY,MARGE/OFFICE-->
<ti>CIGARETTE ADDITIVE REDUCES RISKS OF SMOKING, FIRM SAYS</ti>
<pg>1</pg>
<!-- Note:lu:MILE/PRODUCED-->
<!-- Note:dl:20030213-->
<dl>20030315</dl>
<ot>4a Cigarette additive reduces risks
of smoking, firm says • :. "
~
1 $y JUDITH EGERTON
!p• arm writer• ~ A new Louisville firm said yesterday that
It has produced a cigarette additive that re-
duces the health rtsks of smoking.
That announcement. however, didn't re-
ceive an enthusiastic response from tobacco
companies or health offictals. L Douglas Keeney, president and chief
executive officer of C. A. Blockers Inc In
Meidinger Tower, said yesterday that the
firm has successfully produced standard-
sized cigarettes containing an additive that
neutralizes the effect of nltrosamines, which
a"recarcinogens associated with lung can-
cer.
The product, to be called N-BLDCCIN,
could be availablt to tobacco companies
this year, Keeney said. But first, tests wlll
be done on people who smoke the cigarettes
with the implanted additive. In a six-month
test period, bronchial biopsies and cell
counts will be done on the smokers, be said,
to determine ihe product's effectiveness.
Keeney said in tests lnvolving laboratory
mice, N-BLOCTIN had proved to be "highly
' effectlve" In blocking the accumulation of
oitrosamines In the lungs.
The lab work was spearheaded by Dr.
William Waddell, a toxipology specialist and
chairman of the University of Louisville De-
partment of Pharmacology' and Toxicology,
who for years has been rrsearching toxic
effects of tobacco and searching for a com-
pound to prevent the accumulation of car-
cinogeas, according to Arthur Keeney.
Keeney Ls a former dean of the U of L
121~88i lr,~JournallG
43 jTe
L pa 24
School of Medicine, the father ot L- Douglas A spokeswoman for R. J. Reyn-
Keeney and a company shareholder. old, Tobacco Co. said more work
The additive, developed by Waddell, is needs to be done before sclentLses
composed of a high molecular weight alco- can evaluate the additive.
hot. The test etgarettes with the additive ' Keeney said the additive would
were developed at the University of Ken- not be subject to approval from the
tucky, Arthur Keeney said. federal Food and Drug Administra-
"Nitrosamines are the most abundant car. . tion because tt's a cigaretterefated
cinogens in tobacco smoke and are believed
rtgu-
to be a significant factor in smoking-assocl- product and the FDA doesn't regu-
ated cancer of the lung. We believe that N- late ctgarpnes. .
BLOCTIN will significantly reduce the ongo- \` Keeney, 36, worked In marketing
Ing risk of lung cancer among cigarette a, Brown &amp; Williamson for about
smokers," he said. thr.ee years. He and seven other
' Others aren't so sure. shireholders formed C A. Btockers
"With 4,00 chemicals having been Identi- less than two year ago after they
fied In cigarettes --• you aren't going ta' aequired the patent and research
eliminate the health risks of cigflrette smok- work for the technology that nea-
Ing," said Dr. Ran Davis, with the US. Of- trallzes nltrosamines froin Waddell
fice of Smoking and Health. But, he said, and Carolya Marlowe, a medical
you could lower the health risk by blocking school research associate married
the nttrosamloes. • to Waddell. .
Dietrich Hotfman, a toxicologist with the The company, whieh has no ties
non-proflt American Health Foundation In to any tobacco eompany, went pub-
New York, said "the concept is good," but llc ia October, Keeney said. Yester-
he would have to see the data to know Il tne , the stock closed unchanged at
development is a true breakthrough. Tobac- day, co analyst John Maxwell Jr. doesn't tbink S2~j cents a share in overihetouat-
the G'A. Blockers announcement yesterday er trading.
Is significant for the tobacco Industry. It has
never been proven that tobacco products
contain carcinogenic substances, he said.
The additive "Isn't going to get very far wtth
the tobacco industry because they feel there
isn't anything to block," he said.
16 001121

pgNbr=1
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
