<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>ink36d00</tid>
<bt>50549883/9884</bt>
<ti>BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH  SUSAN S. TAYLOR</ti>
<dd>19940000</dd>
<dt>RESUME</dt>
<au>TAYLOR SS</au>
<!-- Note:d:EDUCATION, RESEARCH AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE, HONORS AND ACTIVITIES, SELECTED PUBLICATIONS-->
<!-- Note:dl:20010130-->
<pg>2</pg>
<dl>20021115</dl>
<ot>FF Principal InvestigatorlProgram Director (Last, first, middle): TAYLOR. Susan S.
Crystal Structure of the Catalytic Subunit of cAMP-dependent Protein Kinase Complexed with MgATP and Peptide
Inhibitor. Zheng, J., Knighton, D.R., Ten Eyck, L.F., Karlsson, R., Xuong, H-h., Taylor, S.S., and
Sowadski, J.M. Biochemistry 32, 2154-2161 (1993).
A Template for the Protein Kinase Family. Taylor, Susan S., Knighton, D.R., Zheng, J., Sowadski, J.M.,
Gibbs, C.S.and Zoller, M.J. Trends Biochem. Sci. 18, 84-89 (1993).
Effects of pH on the Phosphorylation of Peptide Substrates for the Catalytic Subunit of cAMP-dependent Protein
Kinase. Adams, J.A. and Taylor, S.S. J. Biol. Chem. 268, 7747-7752 (1993).
Regulation Defective Mutants of Type I cAMP-dependent Protein Kinase: Consequences of Replacing Arg94 and
Arg95. Buechler, Y.J., Herberg, F.W., and Taylor, S.S. J. Biol. Chem. 268, 16495-16503 (1993).
Identification of Phosphorylation Sites in the Recombinant Catalytic Subunit of cAMP-dependent Protein Kinase.
Yonemoto, W., Garrod, S.M., Bell, S.M., and Taylor, S.S. J. Biol. Chem. 268, 18626-18632 (19993).
A Three-dimensional Model of the Cdc2 protein Kinase: Identification of Cyclin and Sucl Binding Regions.
Marcote, M.J.., Knighton, D.R., Basi, G., Sowadski, J.M., Brambilla, P., Draetta, G., and Taylor, S.S.
Mol. Cell. Biol. 13, 5122-5131 (1993).
Crystal Structures of the Myristylated Catalytic Subunit of cAMP-dependent Protein Kinase Reveal Open and
Closed Conformations. Zheng, J., Knighton, D.R., Xuong, N-h., Taylor, S.S., Sowadski, J.M., and
Ten Eyck, L.F. Protein Science 2, 1559-1573 (1993).
Novel Isozymes of cAMP-dependent Protein Kinase Exist in Human Cells Due to Formation of Rta-R1B
Heterodimeric Complexes. Taskdn, K., Skdlhegg, B.S., Soldberg, R., Anderson, K.B., Taylor, S.S., Lea,
T., Blomhoff, H.K., Janson, T., and Hansson, V. J. Biol. Chem. 268, 21276-21283 (1993).
Imaging of cAMP Signals and A-Kinase Translocation in Single Living Cells. Adams, S. Bacskai, B.,
Harootunian, A.T., Mahaut-Smith, M., Sammak, P.J., Taylor, S.S., and Tsien, R.Y. In Advances in Second
Messenger and Phosphoprotein Research, Vol.28, Chap. 21, B.L. Brown, and P.R.M. Dobson, Eds. (Raven
Press, Ltd., New York), p. 167-170 (1993).
Expression of the Catalytic Subunit of cAMP-dependent Protein Kinase in E. coli: Multiple Isozymes Reflect
Different Phosphorylation Sites. Herberg, F.W., Bell, S.M., and Taylor, S.S. Protein Engineering 6, 771-
777 (1993).
Conserved Helix Motif Complements the Protein Kinase Core. Veron, M., Radzio-Andzelm, E., Tsigelny, I.,
Ten Eyck, L.F., and Taylor, S.S. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 90, 10618-10622 (1993).
Movement of the Free Catalytic Subunit of cAMP-dependent Protein Kinase into and out of the Nucleus Can Be
Explained by Diffusion. Harootunian, A.T., Adams, S.R., Wen, W., Meinkoth, J.L., Taylor, S.S., and
Tsien, R.Y. Mol. Biol. Cell 4, 993-1002 (1993).
Divalent Metal Ions Influence Catalysis and Active-Site Accessibility in the cAMP-dependent Protein Kinase.
Adams, J.A. and Taylor, S.S. Protein Science 2, 2177-2186 (1993).
Physiological Inhibitors of the Catalytic Subunit of cAMP-dependent Protein Kinase: Effect of MgATP on
Protein/Protein Interaction. Herberg, F.W. and Taylor, S.S. Biochemistry 32, 14015-14022 (1993).
Thermostable Inhibitor of the cAPK Helps Export the Kinase Catalytic Subunit from the Nucleus. Fantozzi, D.A.,
Harootunian, A.T., Wen, W., Tsien, R.Y., Taylor, S.S., Feramisco, J.R., and Meinkoth, J.L. J. Biol. Chem.
269, 2676-2686 (1994).
cAMP-dependent Protein Kinase: cAMP-dependent Protein Kinase: Crystallographic Insights into Substrate
Recognition and Phosphostransfer. Madhusudan, Trafny, E.A., Xuong, N-h., Adams, J.A., Ten Eyck, L.F.,
Taylor, S.S., and Sowadski, J.M. Protein Science 3, 176-187 (1994).
Three Protein Kinase Structures Define a Common Motif. Taylor, S.S. and Radzio-Andzelm, E. Structure 2,
345-355 (1994).
Crosstalk Between Domains in the Regulatory Subunit of cAMP-Dependent Protein Kinase: Influence of Amino-
Telminus on cAMP-Binding and Holoenzyme Formation. Herberg, F.W., Dostmann, W.R.G., Zorn, M.,
Davis, S.J., and Taylor, S.S. Biochemistry 33, 7485-7494 (1994).
Holoenzyme Interaction Sites in the cAMP-dependent Protein Kinase: Histidine 87 in the Catalytic Subunit
Complements Serine 99 in the Type I Regulatory Subunit. Cox, S. and Taylor, S.S. (1994)(in press).
PHS 388 (Rev. 8i91) (Fonn Page 6) Page FF
Number pages consecutioey at tlie botoom throughout the application. Do notuse suffixes such as 3a, 3b.
50549884

pgNbr=1
FF
NAME
Susan S. Taylor
Principal Investigator/Program Director (Last, first, middle): TAYLOR. Susan S.
BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH
Give the foAowing information for the key personnel and consultants and collaborators. Begin with the principal
investigatodprogram direcror. Photocopy this page for each person.
PLsITIdNlTTLE
Professor
EDUCATION (Beginwitltdaocafaurealeorotlterinitialprofessionslea4resNon, suchasnwsing, andindudspostdactaraltrahing.)

INSTITUTION AND LOCATiON	
DEGREE	YEAR
CONFERRED	
FIELD OF STUDY
University o Wisconsin, Madison, WI	B.A.	964	Chemistry
The Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD	Ph.D.	1968	Physiological Chemistry
MRC Laboratory of Molecular Biology,	Postdoc	1969-71	Protein Chemistry
Cambridge, England			
Universi of California, San Die o, CA	Postdoc	1971-72	Protein Chemis
RESEARCH AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE: Condudng wilhpresewho nt position, list, h dvonological order, previous employment. experienae, and honors.
Key personnel indude the ndpal invesfigator and any other indviduals par6cipats m the,scientific development of exeation of tlte pro1'ect. Key personnel
typically wlll indude all indrv~idusls with doctoral or oUter professional degrees, but in some ~roteds w ll ndude mdv duals at the meaters or baccalaureate level
provided thay conhibuta In a wbstantive way to the scien6fw devebpment or execuuon of tlie project. Indudepresent membership an any Federal Govemmem
public advisory committee. List, in chrondogical order, the utles, all authors, and oomplete references to all publirations during the past three years and to
ropresentatlve esrher pudicatans parenentb this application. DO NOT EXCEED TWO PAGES.
1964-1968: Graduate Student, Dept. Physiological Chemistry, The Johns Hopkins University (Thesis
Advisor: E.C. Heath)
1969-1971: Postdoc. Fellow, MRC Laboratory of Molecular Biology, Cambridge, England (with B.S.
Hartley)
1971-1972: Postdoc. Fellow, Dept. Chemistry, University of California, San Diego (with N.O. Kaplan)
1972-1974: Assist. Prof. in Residence, Dept. Chemistry, University of California, San Diego
1974-1979: Assist. Prof. of Chemistry, University of California, San Diego
1979-1985: Assoc. Prof. of Chemistry, University of California, San Diego
1980-1981: Fogarty Fellow, MRC Laboratory of Molecular Biology, Cambridge England (with A. Klug)
1985-present: Professor of Chemistry, University of California, San Diego
Vice Chairman, 1987-1989; Acting Chairman, 1989.
Honors and Activities:
Sigma Epsilon Sigma; Phi Kappa Phi; NIH Predoctoral (1966-1968) &amp; Postdoctoral (1969-71) Fellowship; NIH
Career Development Award (1972-77); Am. Soc. Biol. Chemists (1976); NIH Biochemistry Study Section (1978-
82); American Cancer Society Study Section: Nucleic Acids and Prot. Synthesis (1983-87); Vice Chair &amp; Chair of
Gordon Conference on "Second Messengers &amp; Protein Phosphorylation (1985-86); Editorial Board, J. Biol.
Chem. (1985-90); ASBMB Nominating Committee (1986-87), Publications Committee (1986-88), Council (1989-
92), Co-Chair, ASBMB 1991 Annual Meeting; Board of Scientific Councilors, Nat. Heart, Lung &amp; Blood Inst.
(1987-92), Chair 1990-91; Nominating Committee, Protein Society (1990-93); Eli Lilly Lecturer, Mich. St. U.
(1991); Leslie Hellerman Memorial Lecturer, Johns Hopkins U. School of Medicine (1992); Burroughs-Welcome
Visiting Professor in Pharmacology, Rochester U. (1992); Faculty Distinguished Lecture, U.C. San Diego School
of Medicine (1992); Fellow of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences (1992); ASBMB Public Affairs
Advisory Committee (1992-95); Council of the Protein Society (1992-95); National Research Council/Commission
on Life Science (1992-95); Council for Research and Clinical Investigation Awards of teh Amnerican Cancer
Society (1993-96); FASEB Summer Conference on Protein Kinases (Vice-Chair, 1993; Chair, 1995), FASEB
Conference on "Protein Kinases"; Forefronts of Large Scale Computation Award (1993).
Selected Publications:
Crystal Structure of the Catalytic Subunit of cAMP- dependent Protein Kinase. Knighton, D.R., Zheng, J.
Ten Eyck, L.F., Ashford, V.A., Xuong, N-h, Taylor, S.S., and Sowadski, J. M. Science 253, 407-414
(1991).
Structural Framework for the Protein Kinase Family. Taylor, S.S., Knighton, D.R., Zheng, J., Ten Eyck, L.F.,
and Sowadski, J.M. Annu, Rev. Cell Btol. 8, 429-462 (1992).
PHS 398 (Rev. 9A1) (Form Page 6) Page FF
Number pages consearCvely at the bottom throughout the applioalion. Do notuse suffixes such as 3a, 3b.
50549883

pgNbr=2
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
