<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>inw49c00</tid>
<bt>50722487/2488</bt>
<ti>BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH  WITKIN, JOAN WARTON</ti>
<dd>19970000</dd>
<dt>RESUME</dt>
<!-- Note:d:PERSONAL, PROFESSIONAL AND EDUCATIONAL EXPERIENCE-->
<!-- Note:dl:20010130-->
<pg>2</pg>
<dl>20021115</dl>
<ot>Baldini, Giulia
1992 Witkin JW, Ferin M, Popilskis SJ, Silverman AJ Effects of gonadal steroids on the ultrastructure
of GnRH neurons in the rhesus monkey: synaptic input and glial apposition. Enedocrinology 129:
1083-1092
1992 Witkin JW Increased synaptic input to gonadotropin releasing hormone neurons in aged virgin
male S-D rats. Neurobiology of Aging 3:681-686.
1992 Witkin JW Reproductive history affects the synaptology of the ageing gonadotropin-releasing
hormone system in the male rat. J. Neuroendocrinology 4:427-432.
1990 Witkin JW Access of LHRH neurons to the vasculature in the rat. Neurosciencc 37:501-506.
1990 Chen W-P, Witkin JW and Silverman AJ Sexual dimorphism in the synaptic input to gonadotropin
releasing hormone (GnRH) neurons. Endocrinology 126:695-702.
1990 Witkin JW and Demasio K Ultrastructural differences between smooth and thorny gonadotropin-
releasing hormone neurons Neurosci. 34:777-783.
1990 Silverman AJ, Silverman RC, Witkin JW and Gibson MJ Modulation of GnRH neuronal activity
as evidenced by uptake of a tracer substance from the vascular supply. Synapse 6:154-160.
1989 Witkin, J.W. Morphology of LHRH neurons as a function of age and steroid condition in the male
rat. Neuroendocrino1.49:344-348.
1989 Witkin, J.W. Synaptology of LHRH neurons in the preoptic area of the malerat: effect of
gonadectomy. Neuroscience 29:385-390.
1988 Chen, W-P., J.W. Witkin and A-J. Silverman Gonadotropin releasing hormone (GnRH) neurons
are directly innervated by catecholamine terminals. Synapse 3:288-290.
1988 Chen, W-P., J.W. Witkin and A-J. Silverman Beta-endorphin and gonadotropin releasing
hormone synaptic input to gonadotropin releasing hormone neurosecretory cells in the male rat. J.
Comp. Neurol. 286:85-95.
1987 Witkin, J.W. Immunocytochemical demonstration of luteinizing hormone-releasing hormone in
optic nerve and nasal region in fetal primate.Neurosci. Lett. 79:73-77.
1987 Witkin, J.W. Nervus terminalis, olfactory and optic nerve representation of luteinizing hormone
releasing hormone in primates. Ann. N.Y. Acad. Sci. 519:174-183.
1987 Witkin J.W. Aging changes in synaptology of LHRH neurons in male rat preoptic area.
Neuroscience 22:1003-1013.
1987 Silverman, A-J., R. Silverman, M.N. Lehman, J.W. Witkin and R.P. Millar Localization of a
peptide sequence contained in the precursor to gonadotropin releasing hormone (GnRH). Brain
Res. 402:346-350.
1986 Witkin, J.W. Luteinizing hormone releasing hormone (LHRH) neurons in aging female rhesus
macaque. Neurobiol. Aging 7:259-263.
1985 Witkin, J.W. and A-J. Silverman Ultrastructure and synaptology of LHRH neurons in rat MPOA.
Peptides 6:263-271.
1985 Witkin, J.W. Luteinizing hormone releasing hormone (LHRH) in olfactory bulbs of primates. Am.
J. Primatology 8:309-315.
1985 Silverman, A-J. and J.W. Witkin Synaptic interaction of luteinizing hormone releasing hormone
(LHRH) neurons in the guinea pig preoptic area. J. Histochem. Cytochem. 33:66-72.
1983 Witkin, J.W. and A-J. Silverman Luteinizing hormone releasing hormone (LHRH) in rat olfactory
systems. J. Comp. Neurol. 218:426-432.
1982 Witkin, J.W., C.M. Paden and A-J. Silverman The luteinizing hormone releasing hormone
(LHRH) systems in the rat brain. Neuroendocrinology 35:429-438.
Book Chapter
1994 Silverman, A.-J., 1. Livne and J.W. Witkin. The gonadotropin-releasing hormone (GnRH)
neuronal systems: Immunocytochemistry and in situ hybridization. In, Physiology of
Reproduction, 2nd ed. E. Knobil and J.E. Neil, eds., Raven Press, NY. pp. 1683-1709.
50722488

pgNbr=1
FF PRINCIPAL INVESTIGATOR/PROGRAM DIRECTOR (Last, first, middlef. Baldini. Giulia
BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH
Give the following information for tlie key personnel and consultants and collaborators. Begin with the principal
investigatorlprogram director. Photocopy this page for each person.
NAME
Witkin, Joan Wharton
POSITION TITLE
Research Scientist
EDUCATION (Begin with baccalaureate or other initial pro%ssional education such as nursing, and include postdoctoral training.)
INSITITUTION AND LOCATION	DEGREE	YEAR
CONFERRED	FIELD OF STUDY
Mt. Holyoke College, S.Hadley, MA	BA, MA	1955,57	Zoology
Columbia Univ. NY, NY	PhD	1981	Physical Anthropology
Col. Univ., Coll. P.&amp;S., NY, NY	Postdoc	1981-'83	Neurosci/Neuroendocr
RESEARCH AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE: Concluding with present position, list, in chronological order, previous employment, experience, and
honors. Key personnel include the principal investisator and any other individuals who participate in the scientific development or execution of the project.
Key personnel typically will include all indmduals with doctoral or other professional degrees, but in some projects will include individuals at the masters or
baccalaureate level provided they contribute in a substantive way to the scientific development or execution of the project. Include present membership on
any Federal Government public advisory committee. List, in chronological order, the fitles, all authors, and complete references to all publications during thc
past three years and to representative earlier publications pertinent to this application. DO NOT EXCEED TWO PAGES.
PREVIOUS APPOINTMENTS and RESEARCH EXPERIENCE:
1991 - Research Scientist, Dept. Anat. &amp; Cell Biol. Columbia Univ. P.&amp;S.
1985-'91 Associate Research Scientist, Dept. Anat. &amp; Cell Biol. Col. U. P.&amp;S.
1982-'85 Postdoctoral fellow, Dept. Anat. &amp; Cell Biol. Col. U., P.&amp;S.
1981-'82 Staff Associate, Dept. Anat. &amp; Cell Biol. Col. U., P.&amp;S.
1980 Graduate Research Assistant, Dept. Anthro., Col, Univ.
1959-'61 Instructor, Zoology Dept., Hunter College, NY, NY
HONORS:
1955 Phi Beta Kappa
1981 Grant from Brookdale Institute on Aging and Adult Human Development
1982 National Research Service Award
PUBLICATIONS:
1997 Witkin JW, O'Sullivan H, Ferin M GnRH perikarya in medial basal hypothalamus of
pubertal femal rhesus macaque are invested with hypertrophied glia. (Submitted)
1997 Wang G, Witkin JW, Hao, G, Bankaitis VA, Scherer PE, Baldini, G Syndet is a novel
SNAP-25 related protein expressed in many tissues. J. Cell Science 110:505-513.
1997 Witkin JW Anatomical evidence for synchronized neuronal networks: GnRH system
Microscopy Research and Technique(Invlted)
1996 Witkin JW Effects of ovariectomy on GnRH neuronal morphology in rhesus monkey (Macaca
mulatta). J. Neuroendocrinology 8:601-604.
1995 Witkin JW, O'Sullivan H, Ferin M Giia] ensheathment of GnRH neurons in pubertal female
rhesus macaques. J. Neuroendocrinology 7:665-671.
1995 Sullivan KA, Witkin,JW, Ferin M, Silverman AJ Gonadotropin-releasing hormone neurons in
the rhesus macaque are not immunoreactive for the estrogen receptor. Brain Res. 685:198-
200.
1995 Witkin JW, O'Sullivan H, Silverman AJ Novel neuronal associations among GnRH neurons.
Endocrinology 136:4323-4330.
1995 Witkin JW and Romero M-T Comparison of ultrastructural characteristics of of gonadotropin-
releasing hormone (GnRH neurons in prepubertal male rats. Neuroscience 64:1145-1151.
1994 Witkin JW Electron microscopic methods for determining changes in the density of
synaptic input to neurons in the aging brain. Neuroprotocols 4:235-239.
1994 Silverman AJ and Witkin JW Biosynthesis of gonadotropin-releasing hormone during the rat
estrous cycle: a cellular analysis. Neuroendocrinology 59:545-551.
1994 Romero M-T, Silverman AJ, Wise PM and Witkin JW Ultrastructural changes in gonadotropin-
releasing hormone neurons as a function of age and ovariectomy in rats. Neuroscience 58:
217-225.
1994 Witkin JW, Xiao E, Ferin M and Silverman AJ FOS expression in the gonadotropin-releasing
hormone (GnRH) neuron does not increase during the ovarian steroid-induced GnRH surge in
the rhesus monkey. Endocrinology 135:956-96 1.
1992 Witkin JW Reproductive history affects the synaptology of the ageing gonadotropin-releasing
hormone system in the male rat. J. Neuroendocrinology 4:427-432.
PHS 398 (Rev. 9/91) (Form Page 6) Page _
Number pages consecutively at the bottom throughout the application. Do not use suffixes such as 3a, 3b.
FF
50722487

pgNbr=2
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
