<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>inq09d00</tid>
<bt>50453779/3780</bt>
<ti>BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH  ROBISON, STEVEN H.</ti>
<dd>19900611</dd>
<dt>RESUME</dt>
<!-- Note:d:EDUCATION, RESEARCH AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE AND PUBLICATIONS-->
<!-- Note:dl:20010130-->
<pg>2</pg>
<dl>20021115</dl>
<ot>Branda, Richard F.
PUBLICATIONS - Steven H. Robison
Robison SH, Bradley WG: DNA damage and repair in neuronal degenerations, J Neur Sci
64:11-20, 1984.
Robison SH &amp; Bradley WG: Impaired DNA repair replication in Alzheimer's disease cells.
In: J.T. Hutton &amp; A.D. Kenny, (eds.) Senile dementia of the Alzheimer Type, New York,
Alan R. Liss, 1985, pp 205-218.
Robison SH, Munzer JS, Tandan R &amp; Bradley WG: Alzheimer's disease cells have defective
repair of alkylating agent-induced DNA damage. Ann of Neurol 21:250-258, 1987.
Tandan R, Robison SH, Munzer JS &amp; Bradley WG: Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis cells have
abnormal repair of alkylated DNA. J Neurol Sci 79:189-203, 1987.
Bradley WG, Tandan R, Robison SH, Munzer S and Bradley R: Impaired DNA repair in
Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Alzheimer's disease. In: Gourie-Devi M.(ed.) Motor
Neuron Disease. Global Clinical Patterns and International Research. New Delhi. Oxford
and IBH Publishing Co., 1987, pp. 93-105.
Munzer JS, Jones SK, O'Neill JP Hartshorn, JN and Robison SH: Detection of DNA damage
and repair by alkaline elution using human lymphocytes, Mutat Res. 194:101-108, 1988.
Branda, RF, McCormack, JJ, Perlmutter, CA, Mathews, IA and Robison, SH: Effects of
folate deficiency on the metastatic potential of murine melanoma cells. Cancer Res.
48, 4529-4534, 1988.
Jones, SK, Nee, LE, Sweet, LM, Polinsky, RJ, Bradley, WG and Robison, SH: Decreased
DNA repair in familial Alzheimer's disease. Mutat Res 219:247-255, 1989.
Bradley, WG, Polinsky, RJ, Pendlebury, WW, Jones, SK, Nee, LE, Bartlett, JD,
Hartshorn, JN, Tandan, R, Sweer, L, Magin, CK and Robison, SH: DNA repair deficiency
for alkylation damage in cells from Alzheimer's disease patients. In: Alzheimer's
disease and Related Disorders, K. Iqbal, HM Wisniewski, B Winblad (ed) Alan R. Liss,
NY, 1989.
Bartlett, JN, Hartshorn, JN, Bradley, WG and Robison, SH: Reduced Unscheduled DNA
synthesis during alkylating agent-induced DNA damage in monocytes from patients with
presumed Alzheimer's disease. Environ Molec Mutagen (in press, 1989).
Vichi, P, Robison, SH and Tritton, TR: Temperature dependence of Adriamycin-Induced
DNA damage. Cancer Res (in press, 1989)
Hartshorn, JN and Robison, SH: DNA repair in cultured human T-lymphocytes. Mutat.
Res (in press, 1989).
Bartlett, JB, Bradley, WG and Robison, SH: Quantitation of 06-methylguanine acceptor
protein levels in cultured T-lymphocytes from Alzheimer's disease patients.
(Mutagenesis press, 1989).

pgNbr=1
---- --
PRINCIPAL INVes i wr+1ur+11---
BIa GAAPHICaL SiCETC}i
Give the following information for the key personnel and consuitants listed on page 2 eegin with the Principal
hwestigatorlPrograrn Director. Photocopy this page for eecn person.
NAME
POSITION TITLE
BIRTHOATE (Mo., Day, Yr.)
Robison, Steven H.
EDUCATION /BeQn with baccalaureate or other rnitlal orofessi	Re
onal edue	search Assi
atron. suc.R as nu	stant
rsme. ano ctude oostd	10/6/52
oetoral rrdininq.)

INS7fTUT1oN ANO LOCATION		DEGREE I	YEAR

CCNF'eRRED		
FIELD OF STUOY
Eastern College, St. Davids, PA		A.B.	197		Chemistry
Thomas Jefferson Univ., Philad.		Ph. D.	198		Path/Molec. .
Baylor Coll. of Medicine, Houston		Post-Doc	1980-19	1	Ce11 Biol.
Univ. Texas Med School, Houston		Post-Doc	1981-19	3	Cell Biol.
RESEARCH AND PROFESSfONALEXPERIENCE Concfuding with present position.list in cnronolagicalarder, previous employment, experienc-
and honors. Include present membership an any Federal Government public aovisory committee. List. in chronological order, the titles and eorr
plete references to all publications during the past three years and to representative eanier publications pertinent to this application. 00 NC
EXCEED TWO PAGES.
1974-80 Graduate Research Assistant, Department of Pathology,_Thomas Jefferson
University, Philadelphia, PA
1979 Elected to Sigma Xi membership '
1980-81 ,E?+ecipient of National Research Service Award - Postdoctoral Fellowship, Call
Biology Department, Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, TX
1981-83 Continuation of National Research Service Award - Postdoctoral Fellowship,
Pharmacology Department, University of Texas Health Science Center at
Houston, Houston, TX
1983- Research Assistant Professor, Department of Neurology, University of Vermont,
present College of Medicine, Burlington, VT
Reviewer for - Mutation Research, Cancer Research, Environmental &amp; Molecular
Mutagenesis.
PUBLICATIONS
Robison SH &amp; Costa M: The induction of DNA strand breakage by nickel compounds in
cultured Chinese hamster overy cells, Cancer Letters 15, 35-40, 1982.
Harnett PB, Robison SH, Swarzendruber DE &amp; Costa M: Comparison of protein, RNA and DNA
binding and cell cycle specific cytotoxic effects of nickel compounds in cultured
cells, Toxicology and Applied Pharmacology, 64,20-30, 1982.
Costa M, Heck JD &amp; Robison SH: Selective phagocytosis of crystalline metal sulfide
particles and DNA strand breakage as a mechanism for induction of cellular
transformation, Cancer Research, 42, 2757-2763, 1982.
Robison SH, Cantoni 0 &amp; Costa M: Strand breakage and decreased molecular weight of DNA
induced by specific metal compounds, Carcinogenesis 3:657-662, 1982. .
Robison SH, Cantoni 0, Heck JD &amp; Costa M: Soluble and insoluble nickel compounds
induce DNA repair synthesis in cultured mammalian cells, Cancer Letters 17:273-279,
1983.
Robison SH, Cantoni 0 &amp; Costa M: Analysis of metal-induced DNA lesions and DNA repair
replication in mammalian cells. Mutation Research 131:173-181, 1984:
Cantoni 0, Christie NT, Robison SH, Costa M: Characterization of DNA lesions produced
by HgC12 in cell culture systems. Chem-Biol Interact 49:209-224, 1984.
PHS 138 (Rev. 9/86) Paqe _
•"„mnur I.inc1 cnnler.uuv.nv it mn nnnnrn mrounnnut inn aoafianuun, 00 nor uin ^Wti&lt;es Iucn ae `.a.'.b.

pgNbr=2
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
