<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>ina56d00</tid>
<bt>50267812/7820</bt>
<dd>19790801</dd>
<dt>RESUME</dt>
<au>BLAIR PB</au>
<!-- Note:dl:20010130-->
<pg>9</pg>
<dl>20021115</dl>
<ot>7
77. J. R. Roubinian and P. B. Blair. Inhibition of mammary tumors by
incomplete T cell depletion. J. Nat'l Cancer Inst. 58:727-734, 1977.
78. P. B. Blair and M. A. Lane. Effect of immune manipulation on natural
immune responses to murine mammary tumor antigens. J. Nat'l. Cancer
Inst. 59:251-257, 1977.
79. P. B. Blair and M-A. L. Lane. Early detection of tumor-specific
antibodies to mammary carcinoma. Int. J. Cancer 21:476-481, 1978.
80. M. J. Yagi, P. B. Blair, and M-A. Lane, Modulation of mouse mammary
tumor virus production in the MJY-alpha cell line. J. Virology 28:
611-623, 1978.
50267820

pgNbr=1
PhylIlis B. Blair
AP
Rese:arch Interests:
Immunology, including virus-host, tumor-host, and maternal-fetal
relationships.
M
Virology, especially the antigenic and genetic characterization of
oncogenic viruses.
Genetics and developmental biology, with emphasis on the neoplastic
and the preneoplastic transformation.
Edit-orships:
Associate Editor, Cancer Research, 1972 - 1975.
Associate Editor, Journal of Immunology, 1975 - present.
Membe:rship in Professional Societies:
Phi Kappa Phi
Sigma Xi
American Association for the Advancement of Science
American Association for Cancer Research
Transplantation Society
American Association of Immunologists
50267813

pgNbr=2
Phyllis B. Blair
Persojnal Data:
Birthiplace: Buffalo, New York Birthdate: May 17, 1931
Phyllis W. Beebe
Marri.ed 1955: Husband - Sidney Mart3n Blair
Educ2=tion •
B.S., Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 1953.
Ph.D., Zoology, University of California, Berkeley, California, 1958.
Teach'-ing and Research Positions:
1972 - present Professor of Immunology, Department of Bacteriology and Immunology
University of California, Berkeley, California.
1972 - present Research Immunologist, Cancer Research Laboratory, University of
California, Berkeley, California.
1966 - 1971 Associate Professor in Residence, Department of Bacteriology and
Immunology, University of California, Berkeley, California.
1966 - 1971 Associate Research Zoologist, Department of Bacteriology and
Immunology, and Cancer Research Genetics Laboratory, University
of California, Berkeley, California.
1965 - 1966 Lecturer in Immunology, Department of Bacteriology and Immunology,
University of California, Berkeley, California.
1963 - 1966 Assistant Research Zoologist, Department of Bacteriology and
Immunology, and Cancer Research Genetics Laboratory, University
of California, Berkeley, California.
Research Biologist, Veterans Administration Hospital, Long Beach,
California.
Assistant Research Zoologist, Cancer Research Genetics Laboratory,
University of California, Berkeley, California.
Junior Research Zoologist, Cancer Research Genetics Laboratory,
University of California, Berkeley, California.
1952~ - 1955
National Science Foundation Predoctoral Fellow, University of
California, Berkeley, California.
Associate in Zoology, University of California, Berkeley, California.
Teaching Assistant in Zoology, University of California, Berkeley,
California.
50267812

pgNbr=3
6
65. Blair, P. B., M. A. Lane, and M. J. Yagi. In vitro detection of immune
responses to MTV-induced mammary tumors: activity of spleen cell prepara-
tions from both MTV-free and MTV-infected mice. J. Immunol. 112:693-705,
1974.
66. Blair, P. B., and M. A. Lane. Immunologic evidence for horizontal trans-
mission of MTV. J. Immunol. 113:1446-1449, 1974,
67. Blair, P. B., and M. A. Lane. In vitro detection of immune responses to
MTV-induced mammary tumors: qualitative differences in response detected
by time studies. J. Immunol. 114:17-23, 1975.
68. Lane, M. A., J. Roubinian, M. Slomich, P. Trafts, and P. B. Blair. Char-
acterization of cytotoxic effector cells in the mouse mammary tumor sys-
tem. J. Immunol. 114:24-29, 1975.
69. Blair, P. B., and M. A. Lane. Non-T cell killing of mammary tumor cells
by spleen cells: secretion of antibody and recruitment of cells. J.
Immunol. 115:184-189, 1975.
70. Blair, P. B., M. A. Lane, and M. J. Yagi. Blocking of spleen cell activity
against target mammary tumor cells by viral antigens. J. Immunol. 115:190-
194, 1975.
71. Newgard, K. W., R. D. Cardiff, and P. B. Blair. Human antibodies binding
to the mouse mammary tumor virus: a non-specific reaction? Cancer Res.
36:765-768, 1976.
72. Blair, P. B. Natural immunity in the oncor.navirus-infected mouse. Cancer
Res. 36:734-738, 1976.
73. Blair, P. B., M. A. Lane, and P. Mar. Antibody in the sera of tumor-bearing
mice that mediates spleen cell,cytotoxicity towards the autologous tumor.
J. Immunol. 116:606-609, 1976.
74. Blair, P. B., Lane, M. A., and P. Mar. Complexity of factors in sera of
different mice that affect MTV-induced mammary tumor cells. J. Immunol.
116:610-614, 1976.
75. Ringold, G. M., P. B. Blair, J. M. Bishop, and H. E. Varmus. Nucleotide
sequence homologies among mouse mammary tumor viruses. Virology 70:550-553,
1976.
76. Roubinian, J. R., M. A. Lane, M. Slomich, and P. B. Blair. Stimulation of
immune mechanisms against mammary tumors by incomplete T cell depletion.
J. Immunol. 117:1767-1773, 1976.
50267819

pgNbr=4
3
27, Weiss, D. W., D. H. Lavrin, M. Dezfulian, J. Vaage, and P. B. Blair.
Studies on the immunology of spontaneous mammary carcinomas of mice.
IN: Viruses Inducing Cancer-Implications for Therapy. W. J. Burdette,
ed. (University of Utah Press, Salt Lake City). pp. 138-168, 1966.
Also IN: Specific Tumour Antigens. R. J. C. Harris, ed. (Munksgaard
Messenger, Copenhagen). pp. 210-231, 1966.
28. Moretti, R. L. and P. B. Blair. The male histocompatibility antigen
in mouse mammary tissue. I. Growth of the male mammary gland in
female mice. Transplantation 4:596-604, 1966.
29. Blair, P. B., and K. B. DeOme. Tumorigenic potential of transplanted
hyperplastic alveolar nodules obtained from different strains of mice.
Abstracts of papers, Ninth International Cancer Congress, Tokyo, Japan,
Oct. 23-29. p. 247, 1966.
30. Blair, P. B. and R. L. Moretti. The mammary fat pad as a protected
transplantation site. Transplantation 5:542-544, 1967.
31. Dezfulian, M., D. H. Lavrin, A. Shen, P. B. Blair, and D. W. Weiss.
Immunology of spontaneous mammary carcinomas in mice: Studies on the
nature of the protective antigens. IN: Carcinogenesis: A Broad Critique.
(The Williams and Wilkins Company, Baltimore). pp. 365-388, 1967.
32. Blair, P. B. An approach to tumor virus identification. Perspect.
Biol. &amp; Med. 11:173-176, 1967.
33. Blair, P. B. Immunology of the mouse mammary tumor virus (MTV): Neu-
tralization of MTV by mouse antiserum. Cancer Res. 28:148-149, 1968.
34. Cardiff, R. D., P. B..Blair, and P. Nakayama. In vitro cultivation of
the mouse mammary tumor virus (MTV): Detection of MTV production by
radioisotope labeling and identification by immune precipitation. Proc.
Nat. Acad. Sci. 59:895-902, 1968.
35. Blair, P. B., C. Smol.ler, and D. W. Weiss. Immunology of the mouse
mammary tumor virus (MTV): Analysis of the antigenic components of the
virion. Proc. Amer. Assoc. Cancer Res. 9:6, 1968.
36. Cardiff, R. D., P. B. Blair, and K. B.
studies of mammary tumor virus (MTV).
9:11, 1968.
DeOme. In vitro radioisotope
Proc. Amer. Assoc. Cancer Res.
37. Weiss, D. W., D. Burton, R. Siegel and P. B. Blair. Immunogenicity of
formalin-inactivated purified mammary tumor virus preparations against
isografts of spontaneous mouse mammary carcinomas. Fed. Proc. 27:681,
1968.
38. Blair, P. B. The mammary tumor virus (MTV). Current Topics in Micro-
biologie. 45:1-69, 1968.
39. Blair, P. B., C. Smoller, R. S. Bonhag, and D. W. Weiss. Immunology of
the mouse mammary tumor virus (MTV): Electron microscopic studies of the
50267816

pgNbr=5
4
interaction between MTV and specific antibody in immunodiffusion. J.
Nat. Cancer Inst. 40:1325-1338, 1968.
40. Daniel, C. W., K. B. DeOme, J. T. Young, P. B. Blair, and L. J. Faulkin,
Jr. The in vivo life span of normal and preneoplastic mouse mammary
glands: A serial transplantation study. Proc. Nat. Acad. Sci. 61:53-60,
1968.
41. Dezfulian,.M., T. Zee, K. B. DeOme, P. B. Blair and D. W. Weiss. Role of
the mammary tumor virus in the immunogenicity of spontaneous mammary car-
cinomas of BALB/c mice and in the responsiveness of the hosts. Cancer Res.
28:1759-1772, 1968.
42. Cardiff, R. D., P. B. Blair, and K. B. DeOme. In vitro cultivation of
the mouse mammary tumor virus; Replication of MTV in tissue culture.
Virology 36:313-317, 1968.
43. Cardiff, R. D., and P. B. Blair. Correlation of infectivity with radio-
isotope studies of the mammary tumor virus (MTV) in vitro. Proc. Amer.
Assoc. Cancer Res. 10:13, 1969.
44. Blair, P. B. Detection by immunodiffusion of mouse mammary tumor virus
in milk samples and correlation with tumor development. Cancer Res.
29:745-748, 1969.
45. Burton, D. S., P. B. Blair, and D. W. Weiss. Protection against mammary
tumors in mice by immunization with purified mammary tumor virus prepara-
tions. Cancer Res. 29:971-973, 1969.
46. Lappe, M. A., and P. B. Blair. Interference with mammary tumorigenesis
by antilymphocyte serum. Proc. Amer. Assoc. Cancer Res. 11:47, 1970.
47. Manning, J. S., A. J. Hackett, R. D. Cardiff, H. C. Mel, and P. B. Blair.
Isopycnic zonal centrifugation and characterization of the mouse mammary
tumor virus (MTV) in different gradient solutions. Virology 40:912-919,
1970.
48. Cardiff, R. D., and P. B. Blair. In vitro cultivation of the mouse mammary
tumor virus: Correlation of infectivity and morphology with radioisotope
studies. Internat. J. Cancer 5:211-216, 1970.
49. Blair, P. B. Immunology of the mouse mammary tumor virus (MTV): Comparison
of the antigenicity of MTV obtained from several strains of mice. Cancer
Res. 30:625-631, 1970.
50. Blair, P. B. Search for cross-reacting antigenicity between MTV-induced
mammary tumors and embryonic antigens: Effect of immunization on develop-
ment of spontaneous mammary tumors. Cancer Res. 30:1199-1202, 1970.
51. Blair, P. B., and R. L. Moretti. Transplantation of isologous male mammary
gland tissue into the mammary fat pads of female mice. Transplantation
10:44-52, 1970.
52. McGrath, C. i[., and P. B. Blair. Immunofluorescent localization of mammary
50267817

pgNbr=6
2
13. Blair, P. B. Neutralization of the mouse mammary tumor virus by rabbit
antisera against C3Hf tissue. Cancer Res. 23:381-384, 1963.
14. Feder, B. H., A. B. Skorneck, H. W. Green, and P. B. Blair. A simple
experimental model for measuring and the effectiveness of preoperative irradi-
ation. Radiology 80:286-287, 1963.
15. Feder, B. H., and P. B. Blair. Preoperative irradiation: evaluation by
a simple experimental model. Radiology 83:111-119, 1964.
16. Feder, B. H., P. B. Blair, and P. Close. Fractionation in preoperative
irradiation. Radiology 84:447-451, 1965.
17. Blair, P. B. Serologic studies of the mouse mammary tumor virus (MTV).
Proc. Amer. Assoc. Cancer Res. 6:6, 1965.
18. Blair, P. B. Immunology of the mouse mammary tumor virus (MTV): A
qualitative in vitro assay for MTV. Nature 208:165-168, 1965.
19. Blair, P. B. and David W. Weiss. Immunology of the mouse mammary tumor
virus: Comparison of mammary tumor virus with the agent found in C3Hf/
Crgl mice; J. Nat. Cancer Inst. 36:423-429, 1966.
20. Lavrin, D. H., P. B. Blair, and D. W. Weiss. Immunology of spontaneous
mammary carcinomas in mice. III. Immunogenicity of C3H preneoplastic
hyperplastic alveolar nodules in C3Hf hosts. Cancer Res. 26:293-304, 1966.
21. Lavrin, D. H., P. B. Blair, and D. W. Weiss. Immunology of spontaneous
mammary carcinomas in mice. IV. Association of the mammary tumor virus
with the immunogenicity of C3H nodules and tumors. Cancer Res. 26:929-934,
1966.
22. Blair, P. B., and D. R. Pitelka. Immunology of the mouse mammary tumor
virus (MTV); Participation of the type B virus particle in the immuno-
diffusion precipitate line for MTV. Proc. Amer. Assoc. Cancer Res. 7:7,
1966.
23. Blair, P. B., D. W. Weiss, and D. R. Pitelka. Immunology of the mouse
mammary tumor virus. Correlation of the immunodiffusion precipitate
line with the type B virus particles. J. Nat. Cancer Inst. 37:261-277,
1966.
24. Duesberg, P. H. and P. B. Blair. Isolation of the nucleic acid of mouse
mammary tumor virus (MTV). Proc. Nat. Aced. Sci. 55:1490-1497, 1966.
25. Blair, P. R., D. H. Lavrin, M. Dezfulian, and D. W. Weiss. Immunology
of the mouse mammary tumor virus (MTV): Identification in vitro of mouse
antibodies against MTV. Cancer Res. 26:647-651, 1966.
26. Blair, P. B. Immunology of the mouse mammary tumor virus (M'TV): Develop-
ment of methods of assay. IN: Viruses Inducing Cancer-Implications for
Therapy. J. Burdette, ed. (University of Utah Press, Salt Lake City).
pp. 288-304, 1966.
50267815

pgNbr=7
Phyllis B. Blair
Publications
1. Blair, P. B. A new strain of the mouse mammary tumor virus. Science 127:
518, 1958.
2. Blair, P. B. A mutation in the mouse mammary tumor virus. Cancer Res. 20:
635-642, 1960.
3. Blair, P. B. Serologic comparison of mammary tumor viruses from 3 strains
of mice. Proc. Soc. Exper. Bio. Med. 103:188-190, 1960.
4. Blair, S. M., P. B. Blair, and T. A. Daane. Differences in the mammary
response to estrone and progesterone in castrate male mice of several
strains and hybrids. Endocrinology 61:643-651, 1957.
5. Blair, P. B., S. M. Blair, W. R. Lyons, H. A. Bern and C. H. Li. Effect
of hormones and of parity of the occurrence of hyperplastic alveolar
nodules and tumors in the mammary glands of female A/Crgl mice. Cancer
Res. 20:1640-1645, 1960.
6. DeOme, K. B., L. J. Faulkin, Jr., H. A. Bern, and P. B. Blair. Development
of mammary tumors from hyperplastic alveolar nodules transplanted into
gland-free mammary fat pads of female C3H mice. Cancer Res. 19:315-520,
1959.
7. Deome, K. B., P. B. Blair, and L. J..Faulkin, Jr. Serial transplantation
of hyperactive outgrowths derived from hyperplastic alveolar nodules trans-
planted into gland-free mammary fat pads of C3H/Crgl mice. Proc. Amer.
Assoc. Cancer Res. 3:106, 1960.
8. DeOme, K. B., P. B. Blair, and L. J. Faulkin, Jr. Some characteristics of
the preneoplastic hyperplastic alveolar nodules of C3H/Crgl mice. Acta
Unio. Inter. con Cancrum 17:973-982, 1961.
9. Blair, P. B. and K. B. DeOme. Mammary tumor development in transplanted
hyperplastic alveolar nodules of the mouse. Proc. Soc. Exper. Biol. Med.
108:289-291, 1961.
10. DeOme, K. B., S. Nandi, H. A. Bern, P. B. Blair, and D. Pitelka. The
preneoplastic hyperplastic alveolar nodule as the morphologic precursor
of mammary cancer in mice. IN: The Morphological Precursors of Cancer.
L. Severi, cd. (Perugia Univ. Press, Perugia). pp. 349-368, 1962.
11. DeOme, K. B., P. B. Blair, and L. J. Faulkin, Jr. Growth and tumor-produc-
ing potential of transplanted mouse mammary tissue. IN: Biological Aspects
of Aging. N. W. Shock, ed. (Columbia University Press). p. 189, 1962.
12. Blair, P. B., K. B. DeOme, and S. Nandi. The preneoplastic state in mouse
mammary carcinogenesis. IN: Biological Interactions in Normal and Neoplastic
Growth. M. J. Brennan and W. L. Simpson, ed. (Little, Brown and Co., Boston)
pp. 371-389, 1962.
50267814

pgNbr=8
tumor virus antigens in mammary tumor cells in culture. Cancer Res.
30:1963-1968, 1970.
53. Blair, P. B. Antigens of tumors and hyperplastic lesions induced by the
mouse mammary tumor virus (MTV). Search for antigenic similarities and
differences in hyperplastic and neoplastic mammary tissue induced by MTV
derived from different strains of mice. IN: Immunity and Tolerance in
Oncogenesis. L. Severi, ed. (Division of Cancer Research, Perugia, Italy).
pp. 83-99, 1970.
54. Blair, P. B., D. jJ. Weiss, and G. H. Smith. Studies on antigenic cross-
reactivity of oncogenic RNA viruses. Cross-reactions between mouse
mammary tumor viruses from different mouse strains. Israel J. Med. Sci.
6:611-616, 1970.
55. Blair, P. B. Immunological aspects of the relationship between host and
oncogenic virus in the mouse mammary tumor system. Israel J. Med. Sci.
7:161-186, 1971.
56. Blair, P. B., M. L. Kripke, M. A. Lappe, R. S. Bonhag, and L. Young.
Immunologic deficiency associated with mammary tumor virus (MTV) infec-
tion in mice: Hemagglutinin response and allograft survival. J. Immun.
106:364-370, 1971.
57. Blair, P. B. Search for antigenic similarities and differences in
the mammary tumor virus (M'1'V) obtained from various strains of mice.
Proc. Amer. Assoc. Cancer Res. 12:25, 1971.
58. Blair, P. B. Strain specificity in mouse mammary tumor virus virion
antigens. Cancer Res. 31:1473-1477, 1971.
59. Blair, P. B. Effect of transient immunosuppression on host response to
neonatally introduced oncogenic virus. Cancer Res. 32:356-359, 1972.
60. Blair, P. B. Immunologic aspects of tumor induction by MTV. J. Nat.
Cancer Inst. 48:1121-1124, 1972.
61. Blair, P. B. Interference with viral oncogenesis by transient immuno-
suppression. IN: Collected Abstracts of the Sessions and Workshops of
the 4th International Congress of the Transplantation Society. page 28,
1972.
62. Halpin, Z. T., J. Vaage, and P. B. Blair. Lack of antigenicity of mam-
mary tumors induced by carcinogens in a nonantigenic preneoplastic
lesion. Cancer Res. 32:2197-2200, 1972.
63. Cardiff, R. D., K. W. Newgard, and P. B. Blair. Radioimmune assay
studies on the mouse mammary tumor virus. VIII Meeting on Mammary
Cancer in Experimental Animals and Man. Airlie House, Virginia, Oct.
24-26, 1973, (National Cancer Program), page 64, 1973.
64. Blair, P. B., and M. A. Lane. Serum factors in mammary neoplasia:
enhancement and antagonism of spleen cell activity in vivo detected
by different methods of serum factor assay. J. Immunol. 112:439-443,
1974.
50267818

pgNbr=9
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
