<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>gcf30a00</tid>
<bt>60006851/6851</bt>
<dd>19930922</dd>
<dt>LETTER</dt>
<bx>259</bx>
<!-- Note:dp:19961127-->
<!-- Note:rn t="m":4-->
<!-- Note:lu:MNAG-->
<pg>1</pg>
<dl>20020201</dl>
<ot>i
e
AMGRICo"9a \
F CANCXR
.40 SOaEI i NATIONAL HOME OFFICE
September 22, 1993
JOHN LASZLO. MD °
Senior Vice President
Research ,
Raymond L. Erikson, Ph.D.
American Cancer Society Professor of
Cellular and Developmental Biology
HARVARD UNIVERSITY
Cambridge, MA
Dear Ray:
One of my colleagues at the American Cancer Society sent me
the Report of the Council for Tobacco Research-U.S.A., Inc., 1992.
You are listed there as being an American Cancer Society Professor
of Cellular and Developmental Biology and that is mentioned again.
in the introduction (see enclosed). While the Society is very
grateful for your using your American Cancer Society title in
publications and public appearances and the like, it is not
appropriate, it seems to us, to have it listed with the Council for
Tobacco Research. For our staff and volunteers this is a conflict
of interest--that at least is the perception. These are the people
that bring us products that kill a half million Americans a year,
and for the American Cancer Society to be in any way associated
with the Council for Tobacco Research lends it credibility that is
frankly embarrassing.
We certainly recognize that the members of the Scientific
Advisory Board are a distinguished group of people who are making
sincere efforts on behalf of research. Please don't take this
request personally, but I hope you understand the sensitivity that
we have to this issue of tobacco and cancer. They are not very
broad minded when it comes to dealing with some investigators that
are funded by the American Cancer Society who provide information
which they don't like--in fact, the tobacco companies have severely
pressured several scientists-fundec3 by the Society.
I wish you continued success and look forward to seeing you at
the Professors' meeting. With all best wishes.
Sincerely,
JL-j'L4b
1599CLiFTON ROAD, N.E., ATLANTA, GA 30329-4251 • 404-329-7536 • FAX 404-321-4669

pgNbr=1
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
