<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>aad2aa00</tid>
<bt>HK0485221/5221</bt>
<ti>UPI</ti>
<dd>19690205</dd>
<dt>NEWS CLIPPING</dt>
<au>UPI;STAGGERS H</au>
<bx>110</bx>
<!-- Note:dp:19960229-->
<!-- Note:rn t="m":131-->
<!-- Note:co:MUL-->
<!-- Note:s:HOCKETT-->
<!-- Note:d:THINKS SOME OF THE REGULATORY AGENCIES ARE DOING SOME OF THESE THINGS THE WRONG WAY-->
<!-- Note:lu:MNAG-->
<pg>1</pg>
<dl>20020201</dl>
<ot>2
HKM0485221
Sen. B. Everett
Jordan: "Regarded the FCC ban as 'an unwarranted, ill-advised
and improper effort to extend government control over
business and industry by administrative dictation.
I'll regard the proposal of the Federal Communications
Commission for a ban on advertising of cigarettes through
television and radio media as an unwarranted, sll-advised
and improper effort to extent government control over
business and industry by administrative dictation.
"'It is an extention of earlier efforts, successfully
resisted so far by Congress, by both the Federal Trade
Commission and the FCC to exercise control over the
tobacco industry beyond the extent of their authority
and in an area properly reserved for legislative
jurisdiction."'
(UPI 2 /5/69)
Rep. L. H. Fountain: "Said he knew of no legal authority by which FCC
could enforce its proposed ban on broadcast cigarette
advertising."
(UPI 2/5/69)
Rep. Harley Staggerst "Forecasting early hearings on the issue, offered a
critical commnt that seemed to reflect a common
attitude on the part of committee members.
"'I think some of the regulatory agencies are doing some
of thase things the wrong way.
"'They've been guilty of it before--taking a stand
of this kind on an issue which they know the Congress
would probably be considering shortly. I don't think
Congress likes this approach-and that is without
regard to the particular issue of cigarette smoking:"
(UPI 2/5/69)
Rep. Edward IoKocht "A Federal Communications proposal to ban cigarette
advertising from television and radio was 'long overdue.'
" lie will do what he can to whip up Congressional
support for the FCC proposal. }ie called on members
of the public to direct their support to the FCC -and
their Congressmen.
"'We are•going to have a fight on our hands: "
(UPI 2/5/69)
•

pgNbr=1
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
