<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>inc16d00</tid>
<bt>40005130/5131</bt>
<ti>BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH  YITONG FU, PH.D.</ti>
<dd>19950000</dd>
<dt>RESUME</dt>
<au>MATTA SG</au>
<!-- Note:d:EDUCATION, AWARDS, PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES, AND PUBLICATIONS-->
<!-- Note:dl:20010130-->
<pg>2</pg>
<dl>20021115</dl>
<ot>Matta. Shannon G.
3. Fu Y.T., Zhang J.S., Zhang S., He F.S. Effect of 3-nitropropionic acid (3-NPA) on LLpid Peroxidation in
Rat. JHygiene Research 1995;24(1):5-7
4. Fu Y.T., Zhang J.S., Jiao X.Y., Huang J.X., He F.S., Zhang S.L. Mechanism of 3-nitropropionic acid-
induced Striatal Damage. Chinese JMedicine 1994;74(8):507-508
5. Fu Y.T., Zhang J.S., Huang J.X., He F.S., Zhang S.L., Li Y.R. Establishment of Brain Microdialysis
Method in Rats. JHygiene Research 1993;22(2):75-77
6. Fu Y: T., Jiao X.Y., He F.S., Zhang S.L. An Animal Model of Striatum Damage Indu,.ed by 3-NPA in Rats.
JHygiene Research 1993;22 (3):137-140
7. Zhang, J.S., Fu, Y.T., Chen W., He F.S., Zhang S.L. Method for Determination of High Energy
Nucleotide and its Metabolites in Brain of Rats Using Reversed-phase High Performance Liquid
Chromatography. J. Chromatography 1993;11(5):289-291
8. Fu Y.T., He F.S., Zhang S.L. Histochemical Studies of Succinct Dehydrogenase in Mice Intoxicated
with 3-NPA, J Health Toxicology 1993;7(4):270-271
9. Fu Y.T., He F.S., Neurotoxicity of 3-NPA and 3-nitropropanol. Foreign Medicine, Section of Hvgiene
1992;19(1):9-13
10. Fu Y.T., He F.S., Li Y.R. Neurotoxin-induced Abnormal Metabolism of Neurotransmitters. Journal of
Health Toxicology 1991;5(1):47-49
11. Fu Y.T., He F.S. Recent Advances in Studies on Glutamate and Its Analogous (Review). Foreign Medicine,
Section of 11&gt;&gt;giene 1990;17(3):150-154
12. Fu, Y.T. and He, F.S., Copper and Zinc in Central Nervous System. Chinese Journal of Nervous and Mental
Diseases 1990;16(5)313-316
13. Fu Y.T., Zhang L., Ma X. S., Qiao C.B. Experimental Studies on interaction between Allergic and Contact
Dermatitis. Chinese Journal ofDermatology 1989;22(2):86-88
14. Fu Y.T., Chen Y.L., Zhang L., Ma X.S., Qiao C.B. Lymphocytes Transformation Test (3H-TdR method) in
Guinea Pigs. Immunology Express 1988;8(1,2):21-22
15. Fu Y.T., Zhang L., Ma X.S., Qiao C.B. Changes of Cellular Immunological Conditior in Guinea Pigs with
Contact Dermatitis, Immunology Express 1988;8(1,2):22
16. Fu Y.T., Zhang L., Ma X.S., Qiao C.B. Sequential Studies of Cellular Immunity Condition in Guinca Pigs
with Allergic Contact Dermatitis. Shanghai Journal of Immunology 1988;8(4):269-270
17. Fu Y.T., Ma X.S., Qiao C.B. Changes of Immunological Condition in Workers Expos--d to Toluene
Diisocynate. Chemical Indecsnial Safety and Health 1987;30 (4):26
18. Fu Y.T., Ma X.S., Qiao C.B. Changes of Immunological Condition in Workers Exposed to
Dinitrochlrobenzene. Industrial Safety and Health 1988;32(2):30
19. Fu Y.T., Qiao C.B. Advances in Occupational Allergic Dermatitis (Review). Railway Occupation Safety,
Health and Environmental Protection 1988;4:49-51
20. Fu Y.T., Qiao C.B. Interaction between Langhans Cells and Contact Allergy Induced by Chemicals (Review).
Foreign Medicine, Section of Hygiene 1988;15(2):69-72

pgNbr=1
Matta, Shannon G.
BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH
Give the following information for all new key personnel, consultants, and collaborators.
Copy this page for each person.
NAME
Yitong Fu, Ph.D.
POSITION TITLE
Post-doctoral Fellow
EDUCATION Be in with baccalaureate or other initlaf rotessional education, such as nurein , and rnclude ostdoctoral trainin .
			
		YEAR	
INSTITUTION AND LOCATION	DEGREE	CONFERRED	FIELD OF STUDY
Chinese Acad. of Preventive Medicine, Beijing, China	MD/PhD	1991	Neurotoxicology
Shandong Academy of Medical Sciences, Jinan, China	MA	1988	Toxicology
Shandon Medical Universit , Jinan, China	BS	1985	Medicine
RESEARCH AND/OR PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE: Concluding with present poslllon, list In chronological order previous amployment, experience, and honors.
Key personnel Inclutle the principal Investigator and any other Individuals who participate In the scienlitic development or executlon of Ihe project. Key personnel
typleally will Inolude all indlvlduals with doctoral or other professional degrees, but in some pro/eds wlll inclutle Individuals at the masters or baccalaureate level
provided they contribute in a substant'rve way to Ihe scientific development or execution of the proJed. Include present membership on any Federal Govemment public
advisory commlttee. list, in chronological order, the Itlles, all authors, and complete references to all publications during the past Ihree years and to representative
earlier publications pertinent to this application. DO NOT EXCEED TWO PAGES.
Professional Experience:
1986 - 1988 Master Degree Fellowship, Shandong Academy of Medical Sciences.
1988 - 1994 Doctoral and Postdoctoral Fellowships, Institute of Occupational Medicine, Chinese Academy
of Preventive Medicine.
1994 - 1995 Visiting Fellow, Surgical Neurology Branch, National Institutes of Health.
1995 - present Postdoctoral Fellow, Minneapolis Medical Research Foundation.
Awar
1992 Outstanding Young Scientists, Chinese Academy of Preventive Medicine.
1993 The third prize of "Progress in Sciences and Technologies ; Chinese Ministry of Public Health.
1994 Fellowship award from National Institutes of Health.
Publications
L In English
1. Fu Y.T., He F.S., Zhang S., Huang J., Zhang J., Jiao X. 3-Nitropropionic Acid Produces Indirect
Excitotoxic Damage to Rat Striatum, Neurotoxicol. and Teratol. 1995; 17(3): 333-339
2. Fu Y.T., He F.S., Zhang S., Zhang J. Lipid Peroxidation in Rats Intoxicated with 3-Nitropropionic Acid,
Toxicon 1995; 33(3): 327-331
3. Fu, Y.T., He, F.S., Zhang S., Jiao X. Consistent Striatal Damage in Rats Induced by 3-Nitropropionic Acid
and Cultures of Arthrinium Fungus, NeurotoxicolL and Teratol. 1995; 17(4): 413-418
4. Fu, Y.T., Matta S. Valentine J. and Sharp B. ACTH Response and Nicotine-induced Norepinephrine
Secretion in the Rat Paraventricular Nucleus are Mediated through Brainstem Receptors. Endocrinology 1997
(in press)
IL In Chinese
1. Fu Y.T., Jiao X.Y., He F.S., Zhang S. Neuropathological Changes in Rats Intoxicated with 3-nitropropionic
acid. J Health Toxicology 1995; 9(1):14-16
2. Fu Y.T., Jiao X.Y., Zhang S., He F. S. Neuropathological Changes in Rats Intoxicated with Sodium Azide.
JHygieneResearch 1995;24(1):l-4

pgNbr=2
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
