<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>inv26d00</tid>
<bt>50690163/0164</bt>
<ti>BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH  LI, GUO-MIN</ti>
<dd>19960000</dd>
<dt>RESUME</dt>
<au>LI G</au>
<!-- Note:d:EDUCATIONAL AND PROFESSIONAL INFORMATION-->
<!-- Note:dl:20010130-->
<pg>2</pg>
<dl>20021115</dl>
<ot>FF Principal InvestigatoriProgram Director (Last, first, middle): Li, Guo-Min
hleman, J.R., Markowitz, S.D., Donover, P.S., Lang, E.Z., Lutterbaugh, J., Li, G.-M., Longley, M.,
Modrich, P., Veigl, M.L., and Sedwick, W.D. (1996) Diverse hypermutability of multiple expressed
sequence motifs present in cancer with microsatellite instability. Oncogene 12, 1425-1432.
Li, G.-M., and Modrich, P. (1995) Restoration of mismatch repair to nuclear extracts of H6 colorectal tumor cells
by a heterodimer of human MutL homologs. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 92, 1950-1954.
Drummond, J.*, Li, G.-M.*, Longley, M.J., and Modrich, P. (1995) Isolation of an hMSH2-p160 heterodimer
that restores DNA mismatch repair to tumor cells. Science 268, 1909-19 L2.
Parsons, R., Li, G-M., Longley, M., Modrich, P., Liu, B., Berk, T., Hamilton, S.R., Kinzler, K.W., Vogelstein
B. (1995) Mismatch repair deficiency in phenotypically normal human cells. Science 268, 738-740.
Parsons, R., Li, G.-M.**, Longley, M.J., Fang, W.-h., Papadopoulos, N., Jen, J., de la Chapella, A., Kinzler,
K.W., Vogelstein, B. and Modrich, P. (1993) Hypermutability and mismatch repair deficiency in RER+
tumor cells. Cell 75, 1227-1236.
Fang, W.-h., Li, G.-M., Longley, M.J., Holmes, J., Thilly, W. and Modrich, P. (1993) Mismatch repair and
genetic stability in human cells. Cold Spring Harbor Symp. Quant. Riol. 58, 597-603.
Kat, A., Thilly, W., Fang, W.-h., Longley, M.J., Li, G.-M. and Modrich, P. (1993) An alkylation-tolerant,
mutator human cell line is deficient in strand-specific mismatch repair. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S. A. 90,
6424-6428.
Those authors contributed equally.
Made initial observation and performed large portion of the work described therein.
PHS398(Rev.5KJ5) (FormPage6) Page FF
Number pages consecutively at the bottom throughout the application. Do not use suffixes such as 3a, 3!:.
50690164

pgNbr=1
FF Principal InvestigatonProgram Director (Last, first, middle): Li, Guo-Min
BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH
Provide thefollowing information for the key personnel in the order liscec on Form Page 2.
Photocopy this page or followthis format for each person.

AME	OSITION TITLE
i, Guo-Min	ssistant Professor of Pathology
DUCATION/rRAINING (Begin with baccalaureate or other irdtiai prolessional education, such as nursing, and include postdoctoral training).
INSTITUTION AND LOCATION	DEGREE
(if applicable)	YEAR(s)	FIELD OF STUDY
Wuhan University, Wuhan, China	B.S.	1981	Biology
Wuhan University, Wuhan, China	M.S.	1984	Biology
Wayne State University, Detroit, Michigan
k
U
i
i
D
h
N
h C	Ph.D.	1991	Chemistry
u
vers
e
n
ty,
ur
am,
ort
arolina	Postdoctoral		Biochemistry
ESEARCH AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE: Concluding with present position, list, in chronological order, previous employment,
xperience, and honors. Include present membership on any Federal Government public advisory committee. List, in chronological
rder, the titles, all authors, and complete references to all publications during the past three years and to representative earlier
ublications pertinent to this application. If the list of publications in the last three years exceeds two pages, select the most pertinent
ublications. DO NOT EXCEED TWO PAGES.
EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE
Jan. 1982 - Dec. 1984 Research Assistant, Department of Biology, Wuhan University, China
m. 1985 - Aug. 1985 Lecturer, Department of Biology, Wuhan University, China
,ept. 1985 - Jan. 1991 Research Assistant, Department of Chemistry, Wayne State University
Sept. 1986 - Dec. 1989 Teaching Assistant, Department of Chemistr~~, Wayne State University
Feb. 1991 - Aug. 1995 Research Associate, Department of Biochemistry, Duke University
Sept. 1995 - Present Assistant Professor of Pathology, University of Kentucky
AWARDS AND HONORS
1979: President Award for outstanding student, Wuhan Universir., China
1978-1981: Dean's list four times, Wuhan University, China
1990: Phi Lambda Upsilon National Chemical Honor Society, Wayne State
1995: Pilot Award from American Cancer Society Institutional Research Grants, University of Kentucky
MAJOR ACTIVITIES AND SERVICES
1995: Invited speaker at Experimental Studies on Genetic Intervention for Cancer Prevention held in
Kona, Hawaii from March 23-25, 1995.
1995: Invited speaker at the Nucleic Acids Gordon Conference held in New Hampton, New Hampshire
from June 11-16, 1995.
1996: Reviewed a grant for Plant Genetic Mechanisms Program, U, S. Department of Agriculture.
1996: Invited seminar speaker at California Polytechnic State Uni ersity.
PUBLICATIONS
Li, G.-M., Longley, M.J., Drummond, J., Vogelstein, B., Sidransky, D., Markowitz, S. and Modrich, P.
(1996) Mismatch repair proficiency of tumor cells with hypermutable phenotypes. Submitted.
Li, G.-M., Wang, H., and Romano, L.J. (1996) Human MutS specifically binds to DNA containing
aminofluorene and acetylaminofluorene adducts. Journal ofBiological Chemistry, in press.
PHS 398 (Rev. 5KJ5) (Form Page 6) Page FF
Number pages consecutively at the bottom throughout the application. Do not use suffixes such as 3a, 3b
50690163

pgNbr=2
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
