<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>inn06d00</tid>
<bt>50513847/3848</bt>
<ti>BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH  CARTER BANCROFT, PH.D.</ti>
<dd>19950000</dd>
<dt>RESUME</dt>
<au>BANCROFT C</au>
<!-- Note:d:EDUCATION, RESEARCH AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE, NIH STUDY SECTION MEMBER AND RELEVANT PUBLICATIONS-->
<!-- Note:dl:20010130-->
<pg>2</pg>
<dl>20021115</dl>
<ot>Principal Investigator/Program Director (Last, lirst, middle): Bancroft, Carter
White, B.A., and F.C. Bancroft. Cytoplasmlc Dot Hybridizatlon: Simple Analysis of Relative mRNA
Levels in Multiple Small Cell or Tissue Samples. J. Biol. Chem. 257_:8569-8572 (1982).
White, B.A., and F.C. Bancroft. Epidermal Growth Factor and Thyrotropin-releasing Hormone Interact
Synergistically with Calcium to Regulate Prolactin mRNA Levels. J. Biol. Chem. 25$:4618-4622
(1983).
Gick, G.G., F.N. 7.eytin, P. Brazeau, N. Ling, F. Esch, and C. Bancroft. Growth Hormone Releasing Factor
Regulates Growth Hormone mRNA in Primary Cultures of Rat Pituitary Cells. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci.
USA$1:1553-1555 (1984).
Gick, G.G., and C. Bancroft, Regulation by Calcium of Prolactin and Growth Hormone mRNA Sequences
in Primary Cultures of Rat Pituitary Cells. J. Biol. Chem. 2Q:7614-7618 (1985).
White, B.A., G.M. Preston, T.C. Lufkin, and C. Bancroft. Detection of'ltvo Chromatin Proteins Which
Bind Specifically to the 5' Flanking Region of the Rat Prolactin Gene. Mol. Cell. Biol. 5:2967-2974
(1985).
Lufkin, T., and C. Bancroft. Identification by Cell Fusion of Gene Sequences That Interact with Positive
Trans-acting Factors. Science _23_7:283-286 (1987).
Jackson, A.E., and C. Bancroft. Proximal Upstream Flanking Sequences Direct Calcium Regulation of
the Rat Prolactin Gene. Molecular Endocrinology 2:1139-1144 (1988).
Hinkle, P.M., Jackson, A.E., Thompson, T.M.. Zavacki, A.M., Coppola, D.A., and C. Bancroft. Calcium
Channel Agonists and Antagonist: Effects of Chronic Treatment on Pituitary Prolactin Synthesis
and Intracellular Calcium. Molecular Endocrinology 2:1132-1138 (1988).
Lufkin, T., Jackson, A.E., Pan, W.T., and C. Bancroft. Proximal Rat Prolactin Promoter Sequences
Direct Optimal, Pituitary Cell-Specific Transcription. Molecular Endocrinology 5:559-566 (1989).
Bandyopadhyay, S.K., and C. Bancroft. Calcium Induction of the mRNA's for Prolactin and c-Fos is
Independent of Protein Kinase C Activity. J. Biol. Chem. 264:14216-14219 (1989).
Jackson, A.E., Bandyopadhyay, S.K., and C. Bancroft. Epidermal Growth Factor and Phorbol Ester
Regulate Prolactin Gene Expression via Distinct Pathways. Mol. Cell. Endocrinol. §,Q: R7-R11 (1990).
Pan, W.T., Liu, Q., and C. Bancroft. Identification of a Growth Hormone Gene Promoter Repressor
Element and Its Cognate Double- and Single-stranded DNA-binding Proteins. J. Biol. Chem. 265:
7022-7028 (1990).
Morris, A.E., Jiang, Y., McChesney, R.E.. Jackson, R.E., Bancroft, C., and L.A. Chasin. Use of a Selectable
Reporter for Isolation of Mammalian Regulatory Genes. Gene 94:289-294 (1990).
Yan, G.-z.,' Pan, W.T., and C. Bancroft. Thyrotropin-releasing Hormone Action on the Prolactin
Promoter is Mediated'by the POU Protein Pit-1. Mol. Endocrinol. 5_:535-541 (1991).
McChesney. R, Sealfon, S.C., Tsutsumi, M., Dong, K., Roberts, J.L., and C. Bancroft. Either Isoform of the
Dopamine D2 Receptor Can Mediate Dopaminergic Repression of the the Rat Prolactin Promoter.
Mol. Cell. Endocrin. M:R1-R7 (1991).
Yan, G.-z., and C. Bancroft. Mediation by Calcium of Thyrotropin-Releasing Hormone Action on the
Prolactin Promoter via Transcription Factor Pit-1. Mol. Endocrinol. 5:1488-1497 (1991).
Morris, A.E., Kloss, B., McChesney, R.E., Bancroft, C., and L.A. Chasin. An Alternatively Spliced Pit-1
Isoform Altered in its Ability to Trans-activate. Nucleic Acids Res. 20:1355-1361 (1992).
Coleman, D.T., and C. Bancroft. Pituitary Adenylate Cyclase-activating Polypeptide (PACAP)
Stimulates Prolactin Gene Expression in a Rat Pituitary Cell Line. Endocrinology 133:2736-2742
(1993).
TYan, J., Chen, J., and C. Bancroft. Expression of Constitutively Active G$ a-subunits in GH3 Pituitary
Cells Stimulates Prolactin Promoter Activity. J. Biol. Chem. 269:33-36 (1994).
Yan, G.-z., Chen, X.-h., and C. Bancroft. A Constitutively Active Form of CREB Can Activate Expression
of the Rat Prolactin Promoter in Non-Pituitary Cells. Mol. Cell. Endocrin. JU:R25-R30 (1994).
Fischberg, D.J., Chen. X.-H., and C. Bancroft. A Pit-1 Phosphorylation Mutant Can Mediate Either Basal
or Induced Prolactin or Growth Hormone Promoter Activity. Mol. Endocrinol„ $: 1566-1573 (1994).
Fischberg. D.J., and C. Bancroft. The D2 Receptor: Blocked Transcription in GH3 Cells and Celluar
Pathways Employed by D2A to Regulate Prolactin Promoter Activity. Mol. Cell. Endocrinol.,
;11:129-137, 1995.
Gaiddon, C., Mercken. L., Bancroft. C. and J.-P. Loeffler. Gas Mutants Associated with Human Pituitary
Secretory Tumors Stimulate Prolactin and Growth Hormone Gene Transcription. Endocrinology, in
press.
Coleman, D.T., and C.,Bancroft. Nicotine Acts Directly on Pituitary GH3 Cells to Inhibit Prolactin
Promoter Activity. J. Neuroendocrinol., in press.
Tian, J., Ma, H.-W. and C. Bancroft. Constitutively Active Gq-a Stimulates Prolactin Promoter Activity
via a Pathway Involving Raf Activity. Mol. Cell. Endocrinol., in press.
Coleman, D.T., Chen, X., Sassaroli, M., and C. Bancroft. PACAP Action on the Prolactin Promoter
Utilizes a Protein Kinase A-mediated Pathway Exclusively, and Requires an Intact Asymmetric
cAMP-Responsive Element. Submitted for publication.
PHS 398 (Rev. 9/91) Page _
Number pages consecutively at the boaom throughoul the appllcalion. Do not use suffixes such as 3a, 3b.

pgNbr=1
FF
NAME

INSTITUTION AND LOCATION	
DEGREE	YEAR
CONFERRED	
FIELD OF STUDY
Antioch College, Yellow Springs. OH	B.S.	1959	Physics
Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD	M.A.	1961	Physics
University of California, Berkeley, CA	Ph.D.	1966	Biophysics
Brandeis University, Waltham, MA	Postdoctor	1966-68	Biology
Harvard Medical School, Boston. MA	Postdoctor	1968-69	Biology
RESEARCH AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE: Concluding with present position, list, in chronological order, previous employment, expedence, and
honors. Key personnel Include the principal investigator and any other Individuals who participate in the scientific development or execution of the project.
Key personnel typically will include all individuals with doctoral or other professional degrees, but in some projects will include individuals at the masters or
baccalaureate level provided they contribute in a substantive way to the scientific development or execution of the project. Include present membership on
any Federal Government public advisory committee. Lis4 in chronological order, the titles, all authors, and complete references to all publications during the
past three years and to representative earlier publications pertinent to this application. If9he list of publications in the last three years exceeds two pages,
select Ihe most pertinent publications. DO NOT EXCEED TWO PAGES.
1968-69 Research Fellow in Pharmacology, Harvard Medical School.
1970 Instructor in Pharmacology, Harvard Medical School.
1970-75 Assistant Professor,,Department of Biological Sciences, Columbia University.
1976 Associate Professor, Department of Biological Sciences, Columbia University.
1976-77 Associate, Sloan-Kettering Institute.
1980-83 Chairman of Sloan-Kettering Institute Unit of Genetics and Molecular Biology.
Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Cornell University.
1978-85 Associate Member and Head of Cellular Gene Expression and Regulation
Laboratory, Sloan-Kettering Institute. Associate Professor of Molecular Biology
and Virology, Sloan-Kettering Division, Graduate School of Medical Sciences,
Cornell University.
1985-present Professor of Physiology and Biophysics, Mount Sinai School of Medicine of the
City University of New York
1990 Chair, Gordon Research Conference on Hormone Action
NIIi Study Section Member
1991-1995 Biochemical Endocrinology
RELEVANT PIIBLICATIONS
POSITION TITLE
Carter Bancroft, Ph.D. I Professor, Physiology/Biophysics
EDUCATION (Begin with baccalaureate or other initial prolessional education, such as nursing, and include postdoctoral training.)
Bancroft, F.C., L. Levine, and A.H. Tashjian, Jr. Control of Growth Hormone Production by a Clonal
Strain of Rat Pituitary Cells: Stimulation by Hydrocortisone. J. Cell Biol. _42: 432-441 (1969).
Tashjian, A.H., Jr., F.C. Bancroft, and L. Levine. Production of Both Prolactin and Growth Hormone
by Clonal Strains of Rat Pituitary Tumor Cells: Differential Effects of Hydrocortisone and Tissue
Extracts. J. Cell Biol. 47:61-70 (1970).
Bancroft, F.C., G. Wu, and G. Zubay. Cell-free Synthesis of Rat Growth Hormone. Proc. Natl. Acad.
Sci., USA 60:3646-3649 (1973).
Harpold, M., P. Dobner, R. Evans, and F.C. Bancroft. Construction and Identification by Positive
Hybridization-Translation of a Bacterial Plasmid Containing a Rat Growth Hormone Structural
Gene Sequence. Nucleic Acids Res. 15:2039-2053 (1978).
Soreq, H., M. Harpold, R. Evans, J.E. Darnell, and F.C. Bancroft. Rat Growth Hormone Gene:
Intervening Sequences Separate the mRNA Regions. Nucleic Acids Res. 6_:2471-2482 (1979).
Dobner, P.R., E.S. Kawasaki, L.-Y. Yu, and F.C. Bancroft. Thyroid or Glucocorticoid Hormones Induce
Pregrowth Hormone mRNA and its Probable Nuclear Precursor in Rat Pituitary Cells. Proc. Nati.
Acad. Sci. USA 78:2230-2234 (1981).
Gerhard, D.S., E.S. Kawasaki, F.C. Bancroft, and P. Szabo. Localization of a Unique Gene by Direct In
i u Hybridization. Proc. NatI. Acad. Sci. USA M.3755-3759(1981).
White, B.A., L.R Bauerle, and F.C. Bancroft. Calcium Specifically Stimulates Prolactin Synthesis and
Messenger RNA Sequences in GH3 Cells. J. Biol. Chem. 256:5942-5945 (1981).
Principal InvestigatodProgram Director (Last, lirst, middle): Bancroft, Carter
BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH
Give the fotlowing information for the key personnel and consultants and collaborators. Begin with the principal
investigator/program director. Photocopy this page for each person.
PHS 398 (Rev. 9191) (Form Page 6) Page _ FF

pgNbr=2
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
