<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>inz20a00</tid>
<bt>60037207/7209</bt>
<ti>CURRICULUM VITAE</ti>
<dd>00000000</dd>
<dt>RESUME</dt>
<au>CLAWSON GA, UNIV CA SAN FRANCISCO</au>
<bx>264</bx>
<!-- Note:dp:19961231-->
<!-- Note:rn t="m":4-->
<!-- Note:d:ST-->
<!-- Note:lu:MNAG-->
<pg>3</pg>
<dl>20020201</dl>
<ot>GARY A. CLAWSON, M.D., Ph.D.
Curriculum Vitae
it
Place and Date of Birth: Lansing, Michigan; September 30, 1950
Marital Status: Married: Shirley L. Clawson
Daughter: Katherine, born 6/25/83
Education:
1971 Michigan State University, East Lansing, MI B.S. (Mathematics)
1972 Michigan State University, East Lansing, MI M.S. (Mathematics)
1976 Michigan State University, East Lansing, MI Ph.D. (Biophysics)
1983 University of Miami, Miami, Florida M.D.
Research and/or Professional Experience:
10/76 - 3/77 Research Associate, Department of Zoology
Michigan State University, East Lansing, MI
6/77 - 5/78 Postdoctoral Fellow, Department of Pathology,
University of California, San Francisco, CA
6/78 - 5/81 Assistant Research Biophysicist; Department of Pathology
5/83 - 6/83 University of California, San Francisco, CA
7/83 - 6/85 Resident, Anatomic Pathology, Department of Pathology
University of California, San Francisco, CA
7/85-now Assistant Professor in Residence, Department of Pathology
University of California, San Francisco, CA
Honors and Awards:
1971 Graduation with "High Honors," Michigan State University
6/77 - 5/78 Giannini Foundation.Fellowship Award
6/84 Diplomate, National Board of Medical Examiners
1/85 Co-Chairman, UCLA Symposium, "Nuclear Structure and RNA Matura-
tion," Steamboat Springs, Colorado.
7/85 - 6/90 Research Career Development Award, National Cancer Institute,
NIH

pgNbr=1
GARY A. CLAWSON, M.D., Ph.D.
Curriculum Vitae 3
C/
13. Clawson, G.A., Moody, D.E., Woo, C.H., and Smuckler, E.A. Apparent dif-
ferential response of nuclear envelope cytochrome P-450 following pheno-
barbital induction arising from a preferential loss during gradient puri-
fication. Cancer Res. 41:3122-3127, 1981.
14. Moody, D.E., James, J.L., Clawson, G.A., and Smuckler, E.A. Correlations
among the changes in hepatic microsomal components after intoxication
with alkyl halides and other hepatotoxins. Molec. Pharmacol. 20:685-693,
1981.
15. Clawson, G.A. and Smuckler, E.A. A model for nucleocytoplasmic transport
of ribonucleoprotein particles. J. Theor. Biol. 95:607-613, 1982.
16. Purrello, F., Vigneri, R., Clawson, G.A., and Goldfine, I. Insulin stim-
ulation of nucleoside triphosphatase activity in isolated nuclear enve-
lopes. Science 216:1005-1007, 1982.
17. Clawson, G.A. and Smuckler, E.A. Increased amounts of double-stranded
RNA in the cytoplasm of rat liver following treatment with carcinogens.
Cancer Res. 42:3228-3231, 1982.
18. Goldfine, I., Clawson, G.A., Smuckler, E.A., and Vigneri, R.
Interactions of insulin with the nuclear envelope. Molec. Cell. Biochem.
48:3-14, 1982.
C
19. Moody, D.E., Clawson, G.A., and Smuckler, E.A. The integrity of liver
protein synthesis in male rats treated with 1,2-dibromo-3-chloropropane.
Toxicol. Lett. 12:101-108, 1982.
20. Smuckler, E.A. and Clawson, G.A. RNA transfer from nucleus to cytoplasm.
Presented at FASEB meeting, April 15-22, 1982, New Orleans, LA.
21. Clawson, G.A. and Smuckler, E.A. Increased nucleoside triphosphatase
activity of rat liver nuclear matrix following low dose carcinogen
intoxication. Biochem. Biophys; Res. Cominun. 108:1331-1339, 1982.
22. Bolton, P., Clawson, G., Basus, V., and James, T. Comparison of RNA-pro-
tein interactions in messenger V bonucleoproteins, ribosomes, MS2 virus,
and QB virus examined via P-NMR relaxation. Biochemistry
21:6073-6081, 1982.
.23. Moody, D., Clawson, G., Woo, C., and Smuckler, E. Cellular effect of
alkyl halides on cytochrome P-450. Toxicol. Appl_ Pharmacol. 66:278-289,
1982.
24. Goldfine, I.D., Purrello, F., Clawson, G.A., and Vigneri, R. Insulin
binding sites on the nuclear envelope: Potential relationship to mRNA
metabolism. J. Cell. Biochem. 20:29-39, 1982.
25. Clawson, G.A. and Smuckler, E.A. Hybridization of poly(A)-containing
ribonucleic acid transported in vitro to cDNA-cellulose transcribed from
cytoplasmic poly(A)-containing ribonucleic acid. Lab. Invest.
49:506-508, 1983.

pgNbr=2
GARY A. CLAWSON, M.D., Ph.D.
Curriculum Vitae 5
39. Liao, Y.-C., Taylor, J., Vannice, J., Clawson, G., and Smuckler, E.
Structure of the rat al-acid glycoprotein gene. Mol. Cell Biol.
5:3634-3639, 1985.
40. Clawson, G., Button, J., Woo, C., Liao, Y.-C., and Smuckler, E. In vitro
release of a-acid glycoprotein RNA sequences shows fidelity with the
acute phase ~esponse in vivo. Mol. Biol. Rots_ In press, 1986.
41. Clawson, G., Button, J., Liao, Y., and Smuckler, E. A cytoplasmic RNA
complementary to pre-albumin intron V. Biochem, Biophys. Res. Comm., In
Press, 1986.
42. Liao, Y.-C., Lebo, R., Clawson, G., and Smuckler, E. Human prion protein
cDNA: Molecular cloning, chromosomal mapping, and biological
implications. Science, in press, 1986.
43. Clawson, G., Lackey, A., Button, J., and Smuckler, E. Photolabeling of
nuclear scaffold actin is modulated by mRNA. Exp. Cell Res. Submitted,
1986.
44. Clawson, G., Button, J., Lackey, A., and Smuckler, E. Appropriate com-
partmentation of nuclear RNA sequences in vitro. Exp. Cell Res.
Submitted, 1986.

pgNbr=3
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
