<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>inw79c00</tid>
<bt>50239379/9380</bt>
<ti>CURRICULUM VITAE</ti>
<dd>19860716</dd>
<dt>RESUME</dt>
<au>MITRANIROSENBAUM S, HEBREW UNIV HADASSAH MEDICAL SCHOOL</au>
<!-- Note:dl:20010130-->
<pg>2</pg>
<dl>20021115</dl>
<ot>n+5tvrti+ • w-un n+-i5vrr nu+vm+sixn 5w mxih-* -Igon ms
THB HEBRBW UNiVRKSITY•diADASSAH MEDICAL SCHOOL 0 JERUSALEM
P• O. B. 1172 Tel. 42811t
Code 91010 Jerusalem
-z-
4x61 11 Su 1112 l1 .11
~
425..:----_..:91IDs ]11ri I[]
0,50/1ti1 91010 •T1a+7]
Investigation: Quantitation of EBV particles in the supernatants of EBV
producer cell lines by hybridization.
with: Prof. G. Klein and Dr. M. Andersson-Anvret.
1979 : Institute of Human Genetics, Aarhus University, Aarhus, Denmark.
Investigation: Viral expression'in epithelial celis previously .
microinjected with Epstein-Barr viru$.
with: Dr. J. Zeuthen.
Netherland Cancer Institute, Amsterdam, Holland.
Investigation: Cell separation from human blood and from cell lines using
the Lacs cell separation apparatus.
with: Dr. W. Bont.
Institut;Pasteur, Viral Oncology Unit, Paris, France.
Investigation: Growth in agarose of human lymphoma cells, before and after
conversion b y Epstein-Barr virus.
with: L. Montagnier, M. D.
]981-1983: National Cancer Institute,NIH, Bethesda, Maryland, U.S.A.
Laboratory of Pathology.
Investigation: Molecular biology of the Bovine Papilloma Virus, and its
use as a vector for the investigation of the expression and regulation
of foreign genes.
with:.Dr. P.M. Howley.
I811owships and Grants
1977 - International Research Technology Transfer'(ICRETT) from the International
Union against Cancer (UICC) to support my visit to Karolinska Institute,Stockholr
1979 - HMBO fellowship, to support my visits to the University of Aarhus, the
Netherland Cancer Institute and Institut Pasteur.
1981-1983- Fogarty International fellowship, to support the postddctatal training.
1983-1985- Israel Cancer Researh Fund fellowship, to support studies on the
50239380

pgNbr=1
n+5wn+ • no-Im 71+1]YT w+o~5+»x~ 'SW r1xih-15 -ison n+n
THE HEBRBW UNIVERSITY-HADASSAH MEDICAL SCHOOL • JERUSALEM
P• O. B. 1172 Td. 428111
Code 91010 Jerusalem
DEPARTMENT OF VIROLOGY
CURRICULUM VITAE
42ei/1 .5U /17z .'1 T
aze_.@ n11[I+ z•m x.l
L+17071-1+ 91010
Name: Stella Mitrani-Rosenbaum
Place and date of bitth: Barcelona, Spain, 1950.
Marital Status: Married, 'r?children
Hducation:
3967-1970 : Studies of Biology at the University of Barcelona.
1971-1973 : Master of Sciences in Microbiology at the Hebrew University, Jerusalem.
1977-1981 : Ph.D. in Virology at'the Hebrew University, Jerusalem.
Subject: Comparative studies on isolates of Epstein-Barr virus(HBV) from
various human sources: Infectious mononucleosis, cell lines established from human
lymphoma and carcinoma, and characterization of their biological g.nd immunological
properties.
Instructors:Prof. Natan Goldblum, Department of Virology, Hebrew University,
Jerusalem. Prof. George Klein, Karolinska Institute, Sockholm.
Pcademic Status:
1977-1979 : Assistant, Department of Virology, Hebrew University:
1979-1981 : Instructor, Department of Virology, Hebrew University.
1981-1983 : Visiting Fellow, Laboratory of Pathology,National Cancer Institute, NIH,
Bethesda, Maryland.
1983- : Research fellow, Department of Virology, Hebrew Uniiset.gity.
1985- : Member of the teaching staff in the Institute of Microbiology of the
Medical school.
Professional Experience:
1977: Department of Tumor Biology, Karolinska Institute, Stockholm, Sweden.
50239379

pgNbr=2
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
