<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>inp36d00</tid>
<bt>50590985/0986</bt>
<ti>CURRICULUM VITAE  ROGER LAWRENCE SIMPSON, M.D.</ti>
<dd>19900925</dd>
<dt>RESUME</dt>
<!-- Note:d:EDUCATION, HOSPITAL TRAINING, CURRENT PROFESSIONAL AND ACADEMIC APPOINTMENTS, LICENSURES, PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES, AND PUBLICATIONS-->
<!-- Note:dl:20010130-->
<pg>2</pg>
<dl>20021115</dl>
<ot>NASSAU COUNTY MEDICAL CENTFR
CURRICIA_UM VITAE
PROGRAM DIRECTORS AND PRINCIPAL TEACHING STAFF
Name and present position: Roger Lawrence Simpson, M.D. - Attending -Burn
Unit.
Address: 999 Franklin Ave. Garden City, NY 11530, 516-742-3404.
Principal hospital base: Nassau County Medical Center, 2201 Hempstead Tpke.,
East Meadow, NY 11554
Education (including dates and degrees obtained): 1968 - B.S., Syracuse Univ,
Syracuse; 1974 - M.D.- University of Brussels School of Medicine, Brussels,
Belgium
Hospital Training (including dates of Internships, residencies, fellowships,
etc. : 7/73 - 7/74 - Internshlp: - Rotating Medical/Sur.gical - St. Pierre
Univ. Hosp., Brussels, Belgium; Hadassah Hosp., Jerusalem, Israel;
Residencies: General Surgery - NCMC , East Meadow, NY, 7/74 - 6/78 - Chief
Resident 7/77 - 6/78; Plastic Surgery - NCMC - East Meadow, NY - 7/78 to 6/80
- Chief Resident 7/79 - 6/80; Fellowship - 7/90 - 1/81, Hand Surgery - The
Roosevelt Hospital, NYC, J. Wm. Littler, M.D. &amp; Richard Eaton, M.D.; Fellow,
Amer. College of Surgeons
Current professional and academic appointments: NCMC - Chief, Div. of Plastic
&amp; Reconstr. Surg; Director of Burn Ctr; Dir. Hand Surg. Serv.; Attending,
Dept. of Surg.; Winthrop Univ. Hosp.-Clinical Asst. Plastic &amp; Hand Surg;
Clinical Asst. Sect. of Microsurg; North Shore Univ. Hosp. - Asst. Attending,
Dept. of Surg; Mercy Hospital - Clinical Asst. Attend. Dept. of Surg; S.
Nassau Comm. Hosp. - Consult. Staff Dept. of Surg., Div. of Plastic Surg.; The
Comm. Hosp. At Glen Cove - Clinical Asst., Sec. of Plastic &amp; Maxillofacial
Surg; St. Francis Hosp. - Asst. Attend., Dept. of Plastic Surg; Syosset Hosp.
-Assoc. Attend., Div. of Plastic Surg
Licensure(s): 1976 - New York - #129115; 1975 - New Hampshire - #5730; Amer.
B.of Pf stic Surg - 1981; Amer. Bd. of Surg - 1980; Amer. Bd. of Surgery -
Added Qualifications in Surg. of the Hand 1989.
Professional activities/membership in surgical societies: Diplomate, Amer.
B, o P astic Surg; D.tp oma e, Amer. Bd. o Surg.; Amer. Soc. of Plastic &amp;
Reconstr. Surg.; NY Regional Soc. of Plastic &amp; Reconstr. Surg.; The Amer. Soc.
for Surgery of the Hand; Amer. Assoc. for Hand Surg.; NY Soc. for Surg of
Hand; J. William Littler Soc.(Hand Surg.); The Hand Forum; Amer. Burn Assoc.;
AMA; NY Academy of Med.; NYS Med. Soc; Nassau Co. Med. Soc; Exec. Comm. of the
Med. Staff, NCMC; Arthritis Found. LI Div.,Rheumatic Disease; Soc. of Former
Resd. &amp; Assoc. of$Plastic Surg, Downstate Med. Schl., Bklyn, NY; Reg. EMS
Council of NYC, Inc., Burn Comm.; Nassau Surg. Soc.; Nassau Acad. of Med.
Brief statement regarding role in residency program: Participate in resident
teaching &amp; e ucat.ion in P as .ic urgery.
t
50590985

pgNbr=1
Rag_i:_ Lawrence Simpson, M.D.
r' T?UBLI:CATIONS:
u)
1. r::ETABOLiSii AND HEMODYNAMICS OF EXPERIMENTAL TRANSPLANTATION OF
ZWO LUNGS "EN BLOC" USING EXTRACORPOREAL CIRCULATION (translated
from the French), P. Vanderhoeft, A. Dubois, S. Degre, M. Sarezky,
R. Simpson; ACTA CHIRURGICA BELGICA, 70:647-651, 1971.
2. ARTIFICAL LUNG VS. ALLOTRANSPLANTED LUNGS AFTER ACUTE PULMONARY
HYPERTENSION (EXPERIMENTAL), P. Vanderhoeft, P. DeFrancquen,
A. Dubois, Y. Carpentier, N. Lauvau, A. Gyhra, S. Degre,
R. Simpson, M. Sarezky, L. Brickman. Presented at European
Society for Experimental Surgery, Amsterdam, 1972. Abstract
published EUROPEAN SURGICAL RESEARCH 4:363-364, 1972.
3. BUBBLE OXYGENATOR ON BYPASS VS. ALLOTRANSPLANTED LUNGS,
P. Vanderhoeft, P. DeFrancquen, Y. Carpentier, R. Simpson,
M,• Sarez]:y, S. Degre, H. Otte, J. Kraynak, D. Jacobovitz,
ACTA CARDIOLOGICA, 28:615-624, 1973.
4. COLLAGEN AS A BIOMATERIAL in BIOMATERIALS IN RECONSTRUCTIVE
SURGERY, ed. L.R. Rubin, C.V. Mosby, April, 1982.
5.
~
SURGERY OF THE ARTHRITIC THUMB, R. Simpson, J. Kassimi.r,	O.T.R.,
NCMC PROCEEDINGS, Vol. 13, No. 2, Fall, 1986.		
CAUSTIC BURNS FROM CONTACT WITH WET CEMENT,	S. Early,	R.	SimpsofiF,
JCURN%-iL OF THE AMERICAN MEDICAL ASSOCATION,	July 26,	1985, Vol.
254, No. 4, 528-529.
7. REANIMATION OF THE LONG-STANDING FACIAL PARALYSIS, L. Rubin,
G. Lee, R. Simpson, PLASTIC AND RECONSTRUCTIVE SURGERY,
January 1986, Vol. 77, No. 1, 41-49.
.
8. LATE RECONSTRUCTION OF THE BURNED PALM IN CHILDREN, letter to
the editor, R. Simpson, PLASTIC AND RECONSTRUCTIVE SURGERY,
Voi. 82, No. 4,,0. 728.
HONORA.RIUM:
1. BLOCK ALLOTRANSPLANTATION OF BOTH LUNGS WITH PULMONARY TRUNK
AND LEFT ATRIUM IN DOGS. P. Vanderhoeft, A. Dubois, N. Lauvau,
et al. , `i'IIORAX 27 :415-419 , 1971.
2. ASSISTANCE CARDIORESPIRATOIRE PAR OXYGENATOR A MEMBRANE
E'•S:'.RACORPOREL POUR EMOLIE PULMONAIRE MASSIVE. N.	Jaspar,
P. Rocmans, et al., ACTA CARDIOLOGICA 30:35-49,	1975.
3. Lt:NDF,-ED:vARD MEM3RANE OXYGENATOR WITHOUT PUMP AS TOTAL -~,UNG
PROSTI-IESIS. P. Vanderhoeft, C. Derks, P. DeFrancquen,
J. Rozencv:ajg. JOURNAL OF.THORACIC AND CARCIOVASCULAR SURGERY
69.196-202, 1975.
50590986

pgNbr=2
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
