<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>iny95d00</tid>
<bt>50483835/3836</bt>
<ti>BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH  VICTOR A. FRIED</ti>
<dd>19920000</dd>
<dt>RESUME</dt>
<au>FRIED VA</au>
<!-- Note:d:EDUCATION AND SELECTED PUBLICATIONS-->
<!-- Note:dl:20010130-->
<pg>2</pg>
<dl>20021115</dl>
<ot>Victor A. Fried, Ph.D.
Morgan, D.O., Edman, J.C., etandring, D.N., Fried, V.A., Smith, M.C., Roth, R.A., and
Rutter, W.J. Insulin-like growth factor II receptor as a multifunctional binding
protein. Nature 329:301-307, 1987.
Roth, R.A., Stover, C., Hari, J., Morgan, D.O., Smith, M.C., Sara. V., and Pried, V.A.
interactions of the receptor fOr ineulin-like growth factor II with Manoae-6-
phoephate and antibodies to the Manose-6-phoephate receptor. Biochem. eiophye. Roa.
Commun. 149:600-606, 1987.
Murti, K.G., Smith, H.T., and Fried, V.A. Ubiquitin 19 a component of the microtubule
network. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 85c3019-3023, 1908.
Manetto, V., Perry, G., Tabaton, M., Mulvihill, P., Fried, V.A., Smith, H.T., oambetti,
P., and Autilio-GSmbetti, L. Ubiquitin is associated with abnormal cytopiacmio
filaments characteristic of neurodegenerative diseases. Proc. Nati. Acad. Sci. USA
85:4501-4505, 1988.
Perin, M.S., Fried, V.A., Slaughter, c.A., and Sudhof, T.C. The structure of
cytochrome b561, a secretory vesicle specific electron transport protein, EMBO J.
7s2697-2703, 1988.
Fried, V.A., Smith, H.T., and Hildebrandt, E. The intrinsic proteolytic activity of
ubiquitins Factors affecting activity and the structure of the active enayme.
Current Communications in Molecular Biology, The Ubiquitin Syatem. Cold Spring
Harbor Lab. 130-135, 1988.
Affholter, J.A., Fried, V.A., and Roth, R.A. Human insulin degrading enzyme shares
structural and functional homologies with t. aoli, Protease III. Science 242:1415-
1418, 1988.
Perry, G., Mulvihill, P., Fried, V.A., Smith, H.T., 6runke-Iqbal, I., and Iqba1, K.
Immunochemical properties of ubiquitin conjugates in the paired helical filaments of
Alzheimer dieeaee. J. Neurochem. 52s1523-15Z8, 1989.
Hildebrandt, E., and Pried, V.A. Phoephamino acid analysis of protein immobili::ed on
polyvinylidene difluoride membrane. Analytical Biochemistry, 177:407-412, 1999.
Sudhof, T.C., Fried, V.A., stone, D.K., Johnston, P.A., and Xie, x-8. The mammalian
endomembrane proton pump strongly resembles the ATP-eynthetase of archibactoria.
Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA B6t6067-6071, 1989.
Lee, P.L., Johnson, D.E., Cousens, L.S., Fried, V.A., and Williams, L.T, Basic
fibroblast growth factor receptore: Purification and cDNA cloning. eoianoa 245t57-
60, 1989.
Fried, V.A., and Smith, H.T. Ubiquitint a multifunctional regulatory protein
associated with the cytoekeleton. (Research Article) Ins Iqbal, K., wieniewski,
N.H., Wlnblad, B. (eds). Alzheimer disease and related disorders. New York: Alan R.
Lies, pp 733-744, 1989.
Perin, M.S., Fried, V.A., Mignery, G.A., Jahn, R., and Sudhof, T.C. Phoepholipid
binding by a synaptic vesicle protein homologous to the rogulatory region of protein
kinase C. Nature. 345t260-263, 1990.
Rancher, C., Grundke-Iqbal, I., Iqbal,"K.r Fried, V.A., Bmith, H.T., wienieweki, H.M.
Abnormal phoaphorylation of tau precedee ubiquitination in neurofibrillary pathology
of Alzheimer disease. Brain Research 539s11-18, 1991.
Lanza, F., Wolfr D., Fox, C.F., Kieffer, N., fieyere, J.M., Pried, V.A., Coughlin, S,R.,
Phillips, D.R., and Jennings, L.K. cDNA cloning and expression of platelet p24/CD9t
Evidence for a new family of multiple membrane spanning proteine. J. Riol. Chem.
266c10638-10645, 1991.
Scarborough, R.M., Roae, J.W., Hgu, M.A „ Phillipa, D.R., Fried, V.A., Campbell, A.M.,
Nannieai, L., Charo, I.?. Harbourins A OPIIb-IIla-epecific integrin antagoniet from
the venom of Sietrtre m. barbouri. J. Biol. Chem., 266:9359-9363, 1991.
Escobedo, J.A., Navankaeattueae, 8., Kavanaugh, W.H., Milfay, D., Fried, V.A.,
Williams, L.T. cDNA cloning of a novel 85kD protein that has eH2 domains, end
regulates binding of PI3 kinase to the receptor. Cell, 65s75-82, 1991.
Perin, M.S., Fried, V.A., Stone, D.K. Xie, X.-S., Sudhof, T.c. 8tructure ef the 116KDA
polypeptide of clathrin-coated veaicle/eynaptic veeicle proton pump. J.Biol. Chem.
2660877-388, 1991.
Pehreon, J.R., and Fried, V.A., MacroH2A, a core histone containing a largo nonhietone
region. Science, in prees (1992).
Cenciarelli, C., HOU, D., Hsu, Rellahan, B.L., Waiet, D.L., Smith, H.T., Fried,
V.A., and weiseman, A.M. Activation induced ubiquitination of the T-cell antigen
receptor. science, in press (1992).

pgNbr=1
FF
PRINCIPAL INVESTIGATOR/PROGRAM btRECTOR: ViCtor. A. Fried, Ph,l).
_.- ........'--- --- - ----..
BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH
Give the following Informatlan for the key pereonncl pnd consullanta listed on pagg 2. Begirt with the PrinCipal
InveetlgatodProgram Dfiector. Photocopy tinlB pege for each yerson.
-				
NAME	P091TIO	N TITLE	B	IRTHDATE (Mo.. Dny
yr)
Victor A, Fried	Pr	ofessor		,
9/23/43
			I	
		
HDUCATION (
Ae +n wlrh
DAGCd7dur@afa or ofhar7Nbal
uo(asa
n
f
d
r		-------
_,
_,- ... _,.
(
O
a
d
UCat
Ort, euclr aa nUrB	,ny, and ilR'Ntle	JfddClord+ bxini
I
	. . .	
l	. .		.. .. -~	n
- . . . .. ~-__.
	INSTITUTION AND LOC
4TION ~		I
DEGR		YEAR		
	.
_		EE	
C	
ONFERRED		FIELO OF STUDY
Uaiversity	of Chicago, Chicago, IL		BS		1965		Ph
sical Ch

University
U	
of Oregon, Eugenie, OR		
Ph,b.		
1970		y
emistry
Bluchemistry
niversity	of Oregon, Eugene, OR		Postdoc		11970-73		Gen
t
/M
l

University	
uf Connecticut, 'Parmington		
Poetdoc		
1973-75		e
.
o
,Biology
M
b

Health	
Science Ce[1[er						em
rane Biechemistr
RESEARCH AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE: Coneluoing with present puailion, Ilst. In chronological order, previous employment, e.pernence
and honors. Include preaent membershlp on any Federal Governrnent publlc advisory commiitee. Llaf. In chronological order, the lqles and coni
plete reference9 to all publloatlons during the past three years and to representative earlier publlcatione pertlnent to thls application. 00 NOT
EXCEED TWO PAGES.
1975-81 Aaeistant Profeaeor, Dept. of Microbiology, Univ.
of Medicine, Pittsburgh, PA
of Pittsburgh school
1981 Research Assistant Profeasor, Dept. of Biological Sciencea, Faculty of
Arts and SCienCes, Univ. of Pittsburgh, PA
1981-84 Assistant Member, Dept. of Biochemistry, St. Jude
Hospital, Memphie, TN
1984-90 Associate Member, Dept. of
Hospital, Memphis, TN
Biochemistry, St. Jude
1984-90 Director of Protein etructure Facility.
Hospital, Memphis, TN
Children's Research
Children's Reeearch
St. Jude Chi.ldren's Research
1990-Pre Professor, Cell Biology &amp; Anatomy, NY Medical
College, Valhalla,
NY
Selgcted Publications
McKnight, J.L., and Fried, V.A. A novel proteolytic activity apparently initiating
degradation of f3-galactoeidaee nonsense fragments in in vitro extracts of S. coli.
J. Biol. Chem. 258:7550-7555, 1983.
Fried, V.A., Ando, M.B., and Bell, A.J. Protein quantitation at the Picomol levelt
An o-phthaldialdehyde-pre TSK column derivitization assay. Anal. Biochem. 1461271-
276, 1985.
Siagelman, M. Bond, M.W., Gallatin, W.H., St. John, T., Smith, H.T., FrieQ, V.A., and
Weissman, I.L. Cell surface molacula aosociated with lymphocyte homing ia a
ubiquitinated branched chain glycoprotein. Science 231s823-829, 1986.
St. John, T., Gallatin, W.M., Siegelman, H., Smith, H.T., Fried, V.A., and WelYaman,
I.L. Expression cloning cf a lymphocyte homing receptor cDNA: Ubiquitin is the
reactive species. Science 231:845-850, 1986.
Yarden, Y., Excobedo, J.A., Kuang, W-J., Yang-Feng, T.L., Daniel, T.O., Tremble, P.M.,
Chen, &amp;.Y., Ando, M.E., HaSkine, R.A., Francke, U., Fried, V.A., Ulirich, A., and
Williams, L.T. Structure of the receptor for platelet-derived growth factor helps
define a family of closely related growth factor receptore. Nature 323r226-232,
1986.
Deehpande, x.L., Fried, V.A., Ando, M.B., and Webster, R.G. Glycosylation affecte
cleavage of an H5H2 influenza virus hemagglutinin and regulates virulence. Proc.
Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 84:36-40, 1987.
Wang, S.S., and Fried, V.A. Early atepe initiating a degradation pathway in . col1,:
Characterization of the first intermediate. J. Biol. Chem, 26216357-6374, 1997.
Fried, V.A., Smith, H.T., Hildebrandt, E., and Weiner, K. Ubiquitin has intrinsic
proteolytic activity: Its implications for cellular regulation. Proc. Natl. Acml.
sci. USA 84t3685-3689, 19e7.
Winkler, M.A., Fried, V.A., :Merat, D.L., Cheung, W.Y. Differential reactivities of
lyeines in calmodulin complexed to phoephataae. J. Bio1. chem. 262115466-15471,
1987.
PHS 398 (Rev. 10188) lReprlnted 9189) i Page _

cm

pgNbr=2
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
