<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>inr36d00</tid>
<bt>50597708/7709</bt>
<ti>BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH  IH-CHANG HSU</ti>
<dd>19900813</dd>
<dt>RESUME</dt>
<au>HSU I</au>
<!-- Note:d:EDUCATION, PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE, PUBLICATIONS-->
<!-- Note:dl:20010130-->
<pg>2</pg>
<dl>20021115</dl>
<ot>FK
PRINCIPAL INVESTIGA'ORIPROGRAM DIRECTOR: Ih-Chang Hsu, Ph, D.
BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH
Give the following infonnation !or the key personnel and consultants listed on page 2. Begin with the Principal
InvesugatonProgram Director. Photocopy this page For each person.
NAME I POSITION TITLE , BIRTHDATE (Mo., Day, Yr)
i
Ih-Chang Hsu :Associate Professor i 8/3/38
EDUCATION (Begrn with bacca/aureate or or~er rnitial proressiona) education. such as nursing. ano :ncNde ocstdoctoral rrarn,ng.)
INSTITUTION AND LOCATION I 'i DEGREE ' YEAR FIELD OF STUDY
, ' CONFERRED '
Kaohsiung Medical College	B.S.	1964	Pharmacy
National Taiwan University	M.S.	1967	Biochemistry
University of Wisconsin	Ph.D.	1972	Biochemistry
RESEARCH AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE: Concluding with present posit,onn list. in chronological orber, previous employment, expenence,
and honors. Include present membership on any Federal Government puolic advisory committee. List, in chronologioal order, the titles and com-
plete reference5 to ai) publications during the past three years and to representative earlier publications P@Rlnent to this application. DO NOT
ExcEjjOFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:
Research Assistant, Department of Biochemistry, University of Wisconsin, Madison,
Wisconsin, 1968-1972
Research Associate, Department of Pathology, University of Wisconsin, Madison,
Wisconsin, 1972-1975
Research Fellow in Cancer Program, Oak Ridge National Laboratory, Biology
Division, 1975-1977
Expert Investigator, Division of Cancer Cause and Prevention, National Cancer
Institute, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland, 1977-1981
Associate Professor, Department of Pathology, University of Maryland School of
Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland, 1981-present
Member, University of Maryland Cancer Center, University of Maryland Medical
System, Baltimore, Maryland, 1984-present
Visiting Scientist (IPA appointment), Laboratory of Human Carcinogenesis, NCI,
NIH, Bethesda, Maryland, Jan 1988-June 1989
PUBLICATIONS: (selected from 50):
Hsu, I.C., Smalley, E.B., and Strong, F.M.: Identification of T-2 toxin in
moldy corn associated with a lethal toxicosis in diary cattle. Appl.
Microbiol. 24: 683-690, 1972.
Hsu, I.C., Van Miller, J.P., Seymour, J.L., and Allen, J.R.: Urinary metabolites
of 2,5,2',5'-tetrachlorobiphenyl in the nonhuman primate. Proc. Soc. Exp.
Bio1, Med. 150: 185-188, 1975.
Hsu, I.C., Robertson, K.A., and Allen, J.R.: Tissue distribution and binding
properties of dehydroretronecine in the nonhuman primate. Chem.-Biol.
Interactions 12: 19-28, 1976
Hsu, I.C., and Yang, W.K.: DNA transfection of ecotropic murine leukemia viruses
in mouse cell cultures. Cancer Res 37: 1709-1714, 1977
Hsu, I.C., Yang, W.K., Tennant, R.W., and Brown, A.: Transfection of FV-1
permissive and restrictive mouse cells with integrated DNA of murine leukemia
viruses. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 75: 1451-1455, 1978
Hsu, I.C., Stoner, G.D., Autrup, H., Trump, B.F., Selkirk, J.K., and Harris,
C,C.: Human bronchus-mediated mutagenesis of mammalian cells by carcinogenic
polynuclear aromatic hydrocarbons. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 75: 2003-2007,
1978
Harris, C.C „ Hsu, I.C., Stoner, G.D., Trump, B.F., and Selkirk, J.K.: Human
pulmonary alveolar macrophages metabolize benzo(a)pyrene to proximate and
ultimate mutagens. Nature 272: 633-634, 1978
Hsu, I.C., Harris, C.C., Trump, B.F., Schafer, P.W., and Yamaguchi, M.:
Induction of ouabain resistant mutation and sister chromatoid exchanges in
Chinese hamster cells with chemical carcinogenesis mediated by human pulmonary
PHS 398 IRev tot881 Page 7 "N~mse• oages :ocsecun+e~, ai [,e oatom mrougnour -e acol-cai,or Do ~or ose sv.'hxee swc"* as 5a 50
FF
50597708

pgNbr=1
-
PRINCaPAL INVESTIGATOPoPROGRAM DIRECTOFt Hsu, Ih-Chang, Ph.D. -
macrophages. J. Clin. Invest. 64: 1245-1252, 1979
Harris, C.C., Yolken, R.H., Krokan, H., and Hsu, I.C.: Ultrasensitive enzymatic
radioimmunoassay assay for detection of cholera toxin and retrovirus. Proc.
Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 76: 5336-5342, 1979
Hsu, I.C., Bowden, G.T., and Harris, C.C.: A comparison of cytotoxicity, ouabain
resistant mutation, sister chromatid exchanges and nascent DNA synthesis in
Chinese hamster V-79 cells treated with dihydrodiol epoxide derivatives of
benzo[a]pyrene. Mutation Res. 63: 351-359, 1979
Bradley, M.O., Hsu, I.C., and Harris, C.C.: Sister chromatid exchanges: Varying
relationship to mutagenicity,toxicity and DNA damage.Nature 282:318-320, 1979
Hsu, I.C., Poirier, M.C., Yuspa, S.H., Yolken, R., and Harris, C.C.:
Ultrasensitive enzymatic radioimmunoassay detects femtomoles of
acetylaminofluorene-DNA adducts. Carcinogenesis 1: 455-458, 1979
Hsu, I.C., Poirier, M.C., Yuspa, S.H., Grunberger, D., Weinstein, I.B., Yolken,
R.H., and Harris, C.C.: Measurement of benzo[a]pyrene-DNA adducts by
enzymatic immunoassay and radioimmunoassay. Cancer Res. 41: 1091-1095, 1981
Haugen, A., Groopman, J.D., Hsu, I.C., Goodrich, G.R., Wogan, G.N., and Harris,
C.C.: Monoclonal antibody to aflatoxin B1 modified DNA detected by enzyme
immunoassay. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA. 78: 4124-4128, 1981.
Harris, C.C., Yolken, R.H., and Hsu, I.C.: Enzyme immunoassay: Application in
Cancer Research. Method Cancer Research Chapter VI (H. Busch and L.C. Yeoman,
eds.) Tumor Markers 20: 213-242, 1982
Hsu, I.C., Lipsky, M.M., Cole, K.E., Su, C.H., and Trump, B.F.: Isolation and
culture of hepatocytes from human liver of immediate autopsy. In Vitro 21:
154-160, 1985
Hsu, I.C., Harris, C.C., Lipsky, M.M., Synder, S., and Trump, B.F.: Cell
specificity in metabolic activation of chemical carcinogens. Mutat. Res, 177:
1-7, 1987
Cole, K.E., Hsu, I.C., and Trump, B.F.: Comparative ultrastructural effects of
aflatoxin B1 on mouse, rat and human hepatocytes in primary culture. Cancer
Res. 46: 1290-1296, 1986
Snyder, S., Hsu, I.C., and Trump, B.F.: Comparison of metabolic activation of
carcinogens in human, rat, and hamster hepatocytes. Mutat.Res.182:31-39, 1987
Cole, K.E., Jones, T.W., Lipsky, M., Trump, B.F., and Hsu, I.C.: In vitro
binding of aflatoxin B, and acetylaminofluorene to rat, mouse, and human
hepatocytes DNA-relationship of DNA binding to carcinogenicity.
Carcinogenesis 9: 711-716, 1988
Cole, K.E., Jones, T.W., Lipsky, M.M., Trump, B.F., and Hsu, I.C.: Comparative
ultrastructural effect of three carcinogens on human, rat and mouse
hepatocytes. Carcinogenesis 10: 139-143, 1989
Hsu, I.C., and Stoner, G.D.: Induction of sister chromatid exchanges in adult
human bronchial epithelial cells by carcinogens. Toxicology In Vitro 3: 21-
25, 1989
Manchester, D.K., Wilson, V.L., Hsu, I.C., Parker, N.B., Mann, D.L., Weston, A.,
..and Harris, C.C.: 32p post-labeling and immunoaffinity chromatography of human
benzo[a]pyrene diolepoxide-DNA adducts by HPLC linked synchronous fluorescence
~ spectroscopy:-'~11: 553-559, 1990
Chang, C.M., Hsia, M.T., and Hsu, I.C.: Cytotoxic and genotoxic effects of
acrylo nitrile in adult human bronchial epithelial cells. Mutat. Res. 241:
355-360, 1990.
Zhang, S., Lipsky, M.M. , Trump, B.F., and Hsu, I.C.: Determination of hepatocyte
viability in culture by neutral red assay.Cell Biol Toxicol 6(2):219-233,1990
Hsu, I.C., Metcalf, R.A., Sun, T., Welsh, J.A., Wang, N.J., and Harris, C.C.:
Mutational hotspot in the p53 gene in human hepatocellular carcinoma. Nature
350: 427-428, 1991
Lu, A-L., and Hsu, I.C.: Detection of single DNA base mutations with mismatch
repair enzymes. Submitted to Oncogenes, 1991
PHS 398 (Rev. t0/88) Paps 8 '
50597709

pgNbr=2
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
