<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>iny06d00</tid>
<bt>50535699/5699</bt>
<ti>BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH  GLENN R. CUNNINGHAM, M.D.</ti>
<dd>19950811</dd>
<dt>RESUME</dt>
<!-- Note:d:RESEARCH AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE, SOCIETIES AND HONORS, FIVE PERTINENT PUBLICATIONS-->
<!-- Note:dl:20010130-->
<pg>1</pg>
<dl>20021115</dl>
<ot>FF
Principal InvestipaMrlProgram DireGa (Last firat m/dd/a):
BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH
Ghre the 1oNO.drp hdoimelion for ft key personnel and eonsuManb and collaboratom. Bepfn with the principal
invsadparodptoprsm dkeatOr. Pholooopy ft page for slrh persen.
NAME POsMdl?lAe ~hief of Staff for R s.&amp; Dev,
Glenn R. Cunningham. M.D. VA Medical Center and Chie~ Div. Endo &amp;
Metabolism, Baylor College o~' Medicine
EDUCATION (8egin wi/h baacaJauroaAr or aASr irdtlNproA~ss'ana/ edusadon euch as 22% and Nnude pos0oeto!a/ Gae"n9•)
INSTITUTIDN AND LCCATION
DEGREE
YEAR
CONFERRED
iberal Arts
.A.
University of Oklahoma
-68 196g2g-68 Liberal
Mec~icine
Universitv of Oklahoma
Meaicine
esdent 1966
Duke University Medical Center
Duke University Medical Center 1968-70 Fellowship
RESEARCH AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE: Candudnp +wl1h present poskion. Net. In drorabpial order. previous emWoymeMt experiana, and
honors. Key personnel indude the pMcfpel inre~for and any other In6vidua4 who partlapete ie the sdendlk d~wlopnan&lt;or exeoutlon of the pojsa6
Key personnel fyPicsNy wti ineWde ali h~dMdueh wNh docloral or other profeasional dpreee, but in sane pro)eefs wiN kiehrds Indlviduale at the masters or
baxalaureate level provided they oontrtEuN in a subetentlve way to the sdemMk dwelopment «enaNon of ft pojecc Inokude present nan~beretAp on
any FederalGovemment pu6Ne advisay oannitW. LIs4 in cMonobqicd order, the tltlee, all sutlqre, and oompleoe reterer~ees to all pubHcadona during ft
past three years and to representative earibr publicaHone pertinenl to this applkxllon. If the Gst of pubkcadona in ft lest three years exceeds two pages,
'~V~g°f"n°`~rn'my, VecclDCo~rps ~rooke General Hospital;
Chief, Endocrinology Serviee. San Antonio, Texas
1973-89 Chief, Endocrinology Section, VA Medical Center, Houston, Texas
1973-79 Assist. Professor of Medicine, Baylor College of Medicine
1975-94 Assistant Professor of Cell Biology, Baylor College of Medicine
1979-91 Associate Professor of Medicine, Baylor College of Medicine
1980-86 Director, Endocrine Laboratory, The Methodist Hospital.
1981-84 Director, Core Hormone Radioimmunoassay Laboratory;
Diabetes and Endocrinology Research Center, Baylor College of Medicine
1990-92 Director, Core Hormone Radioimmunoassay Laboratory ;
Diabetes and Endocrinology Research Center, Baylor College of Med.
1986-88 Assistant Chief, Medical Service, VA Medical Center,
1988-89 Acting Chief, Medical Service, VA Medical Center
1988-89 Acting ACOS, Research Service, VA Medical Center
1989- Associate Chief of Staff. Research Service, VA Medical Center
1990-92 Acting Chief. Division of Endocrinol and Metab, Baylor College Medicine
1991- Professor of Medicine..Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, Texas
1992- Chief, Division of Endocrinol and Metab, Baylor College of Med.
1994- Professor of Cell Biology, Baylor College of Medicine
Societies and Honors: Alpha Omega Alpha, American Federation for
Clinical Research, Southern Society for Clinical Investigation, The Endocrine Society,
American Society of Andrology. American Diabetes Association; Past President -
American Society of Andrology; Editorial Board - Journal of Clinical Endocrinology and
Metabolism; Associate Editor, Journai of Andrology
Five Pertinent Publications
Ghusn H. Shao TC, Klima M. Cunningham GR: 4-MAPC, a 5a-reductase inhibitor,
reduces rat ventral prostate weight. DNA and prostatein concentrations. J Andrology;
12:315-322, 1991.
Shao TC, Kong A. Marafelia P, Cunningham GR Effects of finasteride on the rat
ventral prostate. J Andrology 14:79-86, 1993.
Shao TC, Kong A. Cunningham GR: Effects of 4-MAPC, a 5a-reductase inhibitor,
and cyproterone acetate on regrowth of the rat ventral prostate. The Prostate
24:212-220, 1994.
Shao TC, Marcelli M, Kong A, Cunningham GR: Anti-androgen effects of the
aromatase inhibitor, atamestane. J Andrology 16:100-107, 1995.
Cunningham GR Hirshkowitz M: The effect of a 5a-reductase inhibitor on sleep-
related erections, potency and libido in health male volunteers. J Clin Endocrinol
wR . ~., an..n on ion0 tqqr~
PHS 398 (Rev. 9/91) (Form Page 6) Pape _ FF
NumWr poeu eonwatlvey tl Uw Eouan tl~rw+phae the appqea5an. Do notua sul9xes weh ae 3s. 7b.
OF STUDY


pgNbr=1
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
