<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>inj16d00</tid>
<bt>50583715/3716</bt>
<ti>BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH  PETER G. TRABER, M.D.</ti>
<dd>19900500</dd>
<dt>RESUME</dt>
<!-- Note:d:EDUCATION, RESEARCH AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE, SELECTED PUBLICATIONS, AND ABSTRACTS-->
<!-- Note:dl:20010130-->
<pg>2</pg>
<dl>20021115</dl>
<ot>10. TRABER PG: Acinar localization of enzymes involved in biotransformation: Analysis of the
cytochrome P450 gene superfamily. Cell Biol Rev 19:87-116, 1989.
11. MAGANTO P, TRABER PG, WOJCIK E, RUSNELL C, GUMUCIO JJ: Long-term
maintenance of the adult pattern of liver-specific expression for P450b, P450e, albumin and
alphafetoprotein genes in intrasplenically transplanted hepatocytes. Hepatology 1990. In
Press.
12. TRABER PG, WANG W, GUMUCIO JJ: Cytochrome P450IIB gene expression and
regulation in rat small intestine: Cloning of intestinal mRNA using the polymerase chain
reaction and transcriptional regulation of induction. Molecular Pharmacology, 1990, In
Press.
Abstracts
1. GUMUCIO JJ, WOJCIK E, TRABER PG, CHIANALE J, KEREN D: Molecular
mechanism of the heterogeneous induction of cytochrome p-450 by phenobarbital with in the
liver acinus: A transcriptional event. Gastroenterology 92:1446, 1987. Oral presentation at
the AASLD plenary session in Chicago, May, 1987.
2. TRABER PG, MULHOLLAND L, CHIANALE J, GUMUCIO JJ: Phenobarbital-induction
of cytochrome P-450 b and e genes is dependent on protein synthesis. Hepatology 7:1052,
1987. Poster presentation at AASLD Meeting, October, 1987.
3. TRABER PG, CHIANALE J, FLORENCE R, KIM K, WOJCIK E, GUMUCIO JJ:
Expression of cytochrome P450b and P450e genes in rat small intestine following treatment
with phenobarbital, organochlorine pesticides and polyhalogenated biphenyls. Clin Res
36:402A, 1988. Oral Presentation at the AFCR national meeting, April, 1988.
4. MAGANTO P, TRABER PG, WOJCIK E, RUSNELL C, KEREN D, GUMUCIO JJ:
Intrasplenically transplanted hepatocytes: An expression system for genes involved in drug
metabolism. Hepatology 8:1249, 1988. Poster presentation at the AASLD meeting,
November, 1988.
5. TRABER PG, WOJCIK E, MAGANTO P, KEREN D, GUMUCIO JJ: The capacity of
hepatocytes to respond to inducers of P450b,e genes is an imprinted phenotypic
characteristic. Hepatology 8:1227, 1988. Poster presentation at the AASLD meeting,
November, 1988.
6. TRABER PG, WANG W, GUMUCIO JJ: Cytochrome P450IIB gene expression in small
intestine: Identification of mRNA using the polymerase chain reaction. Gastroenterology
1989. Oral presentation at the AGA meeting, May, 1989.
7. TRABER PG, WANG W: Differential regulation of P450 genes along the crypt-villus axis
of the rat small intestine. Accepted for oral presentation, AGA annual meetings, San Antonio,
TX, May 1990.
8. TRABER PG, MCDONNELL M, WANG W, FLORENCE R: Expression and
transcriptional regulation of P4501 genes in rat gastrointestinal mucosa. Accepted for oral
presentation, AGA annual meetings, San Antonio, TX, May 1990.

pgNbr=1
FF PRINCIPAL INVESTIGATORiPROGRAM DIRECTOR:
BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH
Give the following information for the key personnel and consultants listed on page 2. Begin with the Principal
InvestigatorlProgram Director. Photocopy this page for each person.
NAME	POSITION TITLE	BIRTHDATE (Mo., Day, Yr.)
Peter G. Traber, M.D.	Assistant Professor ~	04/06/55
EDUCATION (Begin with baccalaureate or other initial professional education, such as nursing. and includ	e postdoctoral training.J

INSTITUTION AND LOCATION	
DEGREE	
YEAR
CONFERRED	_
FIELD OF STUDY
University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI	B.S.	1977	Biochem.
			Engin.
Wayne State University, Detroit, MI	M.D.	1981	Medicine
RESEARCH AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE: Concluding with present position, list, in chronological order, previous employment, experience,
and honors. Include present membership on any Federal Government public advisory committee. List, in chronological order, the titles and com.
plete references to all publications during the past three years and to representative earlier publications pertinent to this application. DO NOT
EXCEED TWO PAGES.
1981-1982: Internship: Northwestern University, Chicago, Illinois
1982-1984: Residency: Northwestern University, Chicago, Illinois (Internal Medicine)
1984-1986: Fellowship: Northwestern University, Chicago, Illinois (Gastroenterology)
1986-1987: Research Fellow: University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan
1987-1988: Instructor: University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan
1989: Assistant Professor: University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan
Selected publications
1. TRABER PG, GANGER DR, BLEI AT: Brain edema in rabbits with galactosamine-induced
fulminant hepatitis: Regional differences and effects on intracranial pressure.
Gastroenterology 91:1347-1356, 1986.
2. TRABER PG, DAL CANTO M, GANGER DR, BLEI AT: Electron microscopic evaluation
of brain edema in rabbits with galactosamine-induced fulminant hepatic failure: Evaluation of
ultrastructure and the integrity of the blood-brain barrier. Hepatology 7:1272-1277, 1987.
3. TRABER PG, GANGER DR, GOTTSTEIN J, BLEI AT: The effect of body temperature on
brain edema and encephalopathy in the rat after hepatic devascularization. Gastroenterology
96:885-891, 1989.
4. GANZ R, SWAIN M, TRABER PG, DALCANTO M, BUTTERWORTH RF, BLEI AT:
Ammonia-induced swelling of rat cerebral cortical slices: Implications for the pathogenesis
of brain edema in acute hepatic failure. Metab Brain Dis 4:213-223, 1989.
5. CHIANALE J, MULHOLLAND L, TRABER PG, GUMUCIO JJ: Phenobarbital-induction
of cytochromes P-450 b,e genes is dependent on protein synthesis. Hepatology 8:327-331,
1988.
6. TRABER PG, CHIANALE J, FLORENCE R, KIM K, WOJCIK E, GUMUCIO JJ:
Expression of cytochrome P450b and P450e genes in small intestinal mucosa of rats
following treatment with phenobarbital, polyhalogenated biphenyls and organochlorine
pesticides. J Biol Chem 263:9449-9455, 1988.
7. WOJCIK E, DVORAK C, CHIANALE J, TRABER PG, KEREN D, GUMUCIO JJ:
Demonstration by in situ hybridization of the zonal modulation of rat liver cytochrome P450b
and P450e gene expression after phenobarbitaL J Clin Invest 82:658-666, 1988.
8. TRABER PG, CHIANALE J, GUMUCIO JJ: The Physiologic Significance and Regulation
of Hepatocellular Heterogeneity. Gastroenterology 95:1130-1143, 1988.
9. TRABER PG, WOJCIK E, MAGANTO P, KEREN D, GUMUCIO JJ: Induction of
cytochrome P450I1B genes within the rat liver acinus is not dependent on the chemical
inducer nor on the acinar organization. J Biol Chem 264:10292-10298, 1989.
PHS 398 (Rev. 10188) (Reprinted 9189) Page - FF
.. ,-.,.,,, .

pgNbr=2
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
