<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>ind09d00</tid>
<bt>50429381/9382</bt>
<ti>BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH  C. GARY GAIROLA</ti>
<dd>19871208</dd>
<dt>RESUME</dt>
<!-- Note:d:EDUCATION, RESEARCH AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE, PUBLICATIONS, ABSTRACTS AND OTHER RELATED PUBLICATIONS-->
<!-- Note:dl:20010130-->
<pg>2</pg>
<dl>20021115</dl>
<ot>Abstracts: (1987-84)
1. Doukas, M.A., Gairola, C.G., Cohen, D.A., Gass, C., Gallicch,
V.S., Messiro, M.J., and Griffith, R., 1987. Tobacco smoke
inhalation induces interleukin-1 (IL-1) elaboration by alveolar
macrophages. Exy. Hematol. 15(5):528, 1987.
2. Gairola, C. and Gupta, R.C., 1987. Cigarette smoke-induced DNA
adducts in the pulmonary tissue of rats following long-term
exposure. Proc. Am. Assoc. Canc. Res. 28:97, 1987.
3. Gairola, C., 1987. Inhibition of Fc-mediated phagocytosis in
pulmonary alveolar macrophages from mice exposed to mainstream
cigarette smoke. The Toxicologist 7:13, 1987.
4. Gairola, C. and Kaplan, A.M., 1986. Effect of cigarette smoke
exposure on the clearance and metastasis of tumor cells in
mice. The ToxicoloRist 6:135, 1986.
5. Hsu, C.C. and Gairola, C., 1985. Studies on the mechanism of
mutagenic synergism between cigarette smoke components and 2
acetyl aminofluorene in Salmonella tyvhimurium, TA98. Environ.
Mutaxen. 7:36, 1985.
6. Soloway, A.H., Lander, N., Minton, J.P., Gairola, C. and Rawal,
P., 1984. Potential metabolic mutagens from caffeine and
related compounds. VIII Internatl. Symp. Medicinal Chemistry,
1984.
7. Ficsor, G., Ginsberg, L.C., Smith, S.P., Pregenzer, J.F. and
Gairola, C., 1984. Effect of cigarette smoke exposure on
selected sperm enzymes in mice. Environ. Mutagen. 6:392, 1984.
8. Gairola, C., 1984. Comparative evaluation of the aerosol and
condensate forms of cigarette smoke in Saccharomyces
cerevisiae-D7. Environ. Mutazen. 6:400, 1984.
9. Valentovic, M.A., Gairola, C., and Lubawy, W.C., 1984. The
impact of dietary selenium (Se) and vitamin E (Vit E) on
14C-arachidonic acid metabolism in aortas and platelets of
smoked rats. The Toxicologist 4:116, 1984.
Other Related Publications
1. Lubawy, W.C., Valentovic, M.A., Atkinson, J.E. and Gairola, C.,
1983. Chronic cigarette smoke exposure adversely alters
14C-arachidonic acid metabolism in rat lungs, aorta, and
platelets. Life Sciences 33:577-584.
2. Gairola, C., 1982. Genetic effects of fresh cigarette smoke in
Saccharomyces cerevisiae. Mutation Res. 102:123-136.
3. Gairola, C. and Griffith, R.B., 1981. Recombinogenic activity
of fresh cigarette smoke in Saccharomyces cerevisiae. Cancer
Detection and Prevention 4:53-57.
4. Gairola, C. and Aleem, M.I.H. 1975. Inhibition of growth and
respiration of yeast by tobacco smoke condensate and
fractions. Experientia, 31:303-304.
5. Gairola, C. and Aleem, H.I.H., 1974. Cigarette Smoke: In
vitro effects of condensate fractions on rat liver
mitochondria. Life Sciences, 14:2199-2207.
6. Gairola, C. and Aleem, M.I.H., 1973. Cigarette Smoke: Effect
of aqueous and non-aqueous fractions on mitochondrial
function. Nature, 241:287-291.
page

pgNbr=1
Give the following intormation for the key personnel and consultants listed on page 2. Begin with the Principal
InveshgatorlProgram Directoc Photocopy this page for each person.
NAME		
C. Gary Cairola	I
~	POStT10
Sect	N TITLE
ion Head, Bi	r BiRTHDATE (Mo.. Day. Yr.l
oassays tiay 1, 1941
DUCA	TION r8	eo7n with D	accaraureate or otnPr im	rrar prntessrenai e.7u	cation. sucn as nu	include postdoctorat trarrvn .1
rsin
E						YEAR	FIELD OF STUDY
		INSTITUTION AND LOCATION	+	DEGREE	CONFERRED	
1.	Agra Univ.,	Nainital, U.P.,	India i	B.S. I	1959	t'nemistry ; Biology
2.	U.P.	Agric.	Univ., Pantnagar, UP India ;	B.S.(Hons)!	1963	Agric.; Animal Husbandry
3.	U.P.	Agric.	Univ., Pantnagar, UP India !	M.S.	1965	Plant Pathology
4.	Univ.	of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign ;	Ph.D. j	1969	Plant Pathology
RESEARCH AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE: ConcJuomp wrt"I Dresent oosition.list. in chronoiopical order, previous emplovmC-nt, e&gt;&lt;oeuencee
and honora, tncluae present memDershio on any Feoera' Governrne-d DCDbc a0v,sory cOm.'nittee. L4t, in chronolOgicai CrOer, tn6 f+iies an0 com.
ptete re'erentes to a11 puDhCa7ion5 durina the oas7 three SeaB a.^•' tC re:'PSentaUve e3r;,er publications pe'Iinent t0 this aD~ri.atipn. DO r.O ,
EY.:cED TVYO PAGES.
1969-1976 Research Associate, School of Biological Sciences,
and College of Pharmacy, Department of Pharmacognosy
and Medicinal Chemistry, University of Kentucky
1976-present Section Head, Bioassays, Tobacco and Health Research Institute,
University of Kentucky, Lexington, Kentucky 40546
1981-present Associate Professor, Graduate Center for Toxicology, University of
Kentucky (adjunct).
1979 Member of the Task Force on Carcinogenic Policy for the Academy of
Pharmaceutical Sciences, American Pharmaceutical Association, -
Washington, D.C.
Publications (1987 - 1984) --
1. Gairola, C. 1987. Pulmonary aryl hydrocarbon hydroxylase activity of mice, rats,
and guinea pigs following long term exposure to mainstream and sidestream cigarette
smoke. Toxicolory 45:177-184. '
2. Gairola, C. 1986. Free lung cell response of mice and rats to mainstream cigarette
smoke exposure Toxicol. Appl. Pharmacol. 84:567-575.
3. Gairola, C. and Tai, H.H., 1986. Cigarette smoke-induced alterations in the release
of arachidonate metabolites by pulmonary alveolar macrophages from selenium-fed and
selenium-deficient rats. Biochemical Pharmacol. 35:2423-2428.
4. Hughes, M.F., Kadry, A.R., Gairola, C.G., and Flesher, J.W., 1986. Mutagenic
activity of biliary metabolites of 6-hydroxymethylbenzo(a)pyrene. Mutation Res.
173:251-256.
5. Gairola, C. and Tai, H.H., 1985. Selective inhibition of leukotriene B4
biosynthesis in rat pulmonary alveolar macrophage by dietary selenium deficiency.
Biochem. Biophys. Res. Cotmnun. 132:397-403.
6. Graziano, M.J., Gairola, C. and Dorough, H.W., 1985. Effect of cigarette smoke
exposure on hepatic biotransformation enzymes in mice maintained on different
dietary levels of vitamin E. Drug-Nutrient Interactions 3:213-222.
7. Sopori, H.L., Gairola, C., DeLucia, A.J., Bryant, L.R. and Cherian, S. 1985. Immune
responsiveness of monkeys exposed chronically to cigarette smoke. C1in. Inmtunol.
Imtnunopathol. 36:338-344.
8. Valentovic, K.A., Gairola, C., and Lubawy, W.C., 1985. Cigarette smoke exposure
alters 14C-arachidonic acid metabolism in aortae and platelets of rats fed various
levels of selenium and vitamin E. J. Toxicol. Env. Hlth. 15:493-502.
9. Chow, C.K., Hong, C.B., Reese, M.E. and Gairola, C. 1984. Effect of dietary vitamin
E on nitrite treated rats. ToxicoloRy Lett. 23:109-117.
10. Chow, C.K. and Gairola, C., 1984. Influence of dietary vitamin E and selenium on
metabolic activation of chemicals to mutagens. J. Agric. Food Chem. 32:443-447.
PHS 398 (Rev. 9186) Pape _
..~..-•_• ___,,. ......-.......~.. _. ... ._...-..._.._......., .--~..,..._ r.. _................. ..... v. c. aw

pgNbr=2
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
