<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>ins09d00</tid>
<bt>50457000/7001</bt>
<ti>BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH  DAS, MANJUSRI</ti>
<dd>19900627</dd>
<dt>RESUME</dt>
<!-- Note:d:EDUCATION, RESEARCH AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE, AND SELECTED PUBLICATIONS-->
<!-- Note:dl:20010130-->
<pg>2</pg>
<dl>20021115</dl>
<ot>BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH
Give the following information forthe ke`y personnel and consultants listed on page 2. Begin with the Principal
Investigator/Program Director. Photocopy this page for each person.
NAMt ~ M
D
POSITION TITLE Professor
Biochemistry &amp; Biophysics
BIRTHDATE (Mo., Day. Yr.)
, anjusn
EDUCATION Be in with baccalaureate or otherlnitia!
INSTITUTION AND LOCATION	DEGREE	CONFYEAR ERRED	FIELD OF STUDY
Calcutta University India	B.S.&amp; M.S.	1966 &amp; 1968	Chem. &amp; Biochem.
Christian Med. Coll., Vellore, India	Ph.D.	1974	Enzym. of Dipeptidase
Albert Einstein Coll. Med., Bronx, NY	Postdoc.	1974-76	Ang~'otensin Conv. Enz.
Univ. of California, Los Angeles, CA	Postdoc.	1976-78	EGF-Receptor
RESEARCH AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE: Concluding with present position, list, In chronological order, previous employment, experience,
and honors. Include present membership on any Federal Government public advisory committee. List, In chronological order, the titles and com•
plete references to all publications during the past three years and to representative earlier publications pertinent to this application. DO NOT
EXCEED TWO PAGES.
1978-1984: Assistant Professor, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA
1984-1988: Associate Professor, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA
1988-present: Professor, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA
1980-1984: Recipient of Research Career Development Award from NIH
1982-1986: Member of Cell Biology &amp; Physiology Study Section, NIH
1982-present: Member of NIH site visit teams and special study sections
1988-1992: Member of NIH Reviewers Reserve 1 •
Selected Publications
*29. Bishayee, S., Feinman, J., Pitteriger, M., Michael, H., Das, M.: Cell surface insertion of
exogenous EGF receptors into receptor minus mutant cells: Demonstration of insertion in
the absence of added fusogenic agents. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA, 72:1893-1897,1982.
33. Das, M., Feinman, J., Pittenger, M., Michael, H., Bishayee, S.: Spontaneous transfer of
exogeinous EGF receptors into receptor negative mutant cells. Methods Enzymol., vol. 98
555-561,1983. "
36. Bishayee, S., Matesic, D., Das, M.: Identification of a 34,000 dalton mitogenic protein
associated with plasma membranes from human A431 epidermoid carcinoma cells. Proc.
Natl. Acad. Sci. USA, Si: 3399-3403, 1984.
37. Das, M., Knowles, B., Biswas, R., Bishayee, S.: Receptor modulating properties of an
antibody directed against the EGF-receptor. Eur. J. Biochem.,141: 429-234, 1984.
38. Das, M., Biswas, R., Basu, M., Bishayee, S.: Mitogenic activity of the EGF-receptor after
transfer from A431 carcinoma cells to receptor-negative fibroblastic cells. Cancer Res.,
44:, 3539-3545,1984.
°r39. Basu, M., Biswas, R., Das, M.: 42,000 molecular weight EGF-receptor has protein kinase
activity. Nautre (London) 311: 477-480, 1984.
*40. Biswas, R., Basu, M., Sen-Majumdar, A., Das, M.: Intrapeptide autophosphorylation of the
EGF-receptor: Regulation of kinase catalytic function by receptor dimerization.
Biochemistry 24: 3795-3802, 1985.
41. Basu, M., Frick, K., Sen-Majumdar, S., Scher, C.D., Das, M.: EGF-receptor associated
DNA-nicking activity is due to a Mr 100,000 dissociable protein. Nature (London) 316:
640-641.1985.
12/27/46
ro/essional education, such as nursin , and inctude ostdoctoral trainin .)
PHS 398 (Rev. 10188) Page _' FF
•Number naces consecutiveN at the bottom thrcuchnut tho aoolir.atinn. Do Iet nse sulFsrs suwh es sa. th

pgNbr=1
42. Das, M., Sen-Majumdar, A., Basu, M.: Interactions between different functional sites in the
EGF-rece tor. In "Biochemical actions of hormones", Ed. J. Litwack, Academic Press, N.Y.,
~: 243-264,1986.
44. Sen-Majumdar, A., Murthy, U., Das, M.: A new trophoblast-derived growth factor from
human placenta: Purification and receptor identification. Biochemistry L5: 627-633, 1986.
45. Sen-Majumdar, A., Murthy, U., Chianese, D., Das, M.: A specific antibody to a new peptide
growth factor from human placenta: Immunocytochemical studies on its location and
biosynthesis. Biochemistry 25: 634-640, 1986.
*46. Murthy, U., Basu, M., Sen-Majumdar, A., Das, M.: Perinuclear location and recycling of
EGF-receptor-kinase: Immunofluorescent visualization using antibodies directed to kinase
and extracellular domains. J. Cell. Biol. ) 03: 333-342, 1986.
47. Basu, M., Sen-Majumdar, A., Basu, A., Murthy, U., Das, M: Regulation of kinase and
intermolecular bonding in intact and truncated EGF-receptor. J. Biol. Chem. 61: 12879-
12882,1986.
48. Murthy, U., Basu, A., Rodeck, U., Herlyn, M., Ross, A.H., Das, M.: Binding of an
antagonistic monoclonal antibody to intact and fragmented EGF- receptor polypeptide.
Arch. Biochem. Biophys. 252: 549-560,1987.
49. Basu, A., Murthy, U., Rodeck, U., Herlyn, M., Mattes, L, Das, M.: Presence of tumor
associated antigens in EGF-receptors from different human carcinomas. Cancer Research
47: 2531-2536,1987.
50. Chianese, D., Roy-Choudhury, S., Murthy, U., Sen-Majumdar, A., Ernst, C., Das, M.: Cell-
and tissue-specific expression of a 34,000 molecular weight peptide growth factor in
humans. Human Pathology, ] Q:190-194,1988.
51. Roy-Choudhury, S., Sen-Majumdar, A., Murthy, U., Mishra, V.S., Kliman, J.J., Nestler, J.E.,
Strauss, J.F., Das, M.: Biosynthesis and turnover of a 34,000 molecular wieght protein
growth factor in human cytotrophoblasts. Eur. J. Biochem., IM: 777-783, 1988.
52. DePalo, L, Das, M.: EGF-induced stimulation of EGF-receptor biosynthesis in human
cytotrophoblasts and A431 carcinoma cells. Cancer Researcti, 48: 1105-1109, 1988.
*53. Roy-Choudhury, S., Mishra, V., Low, M.G., Das, M.: A phospholipid is the membrane
-anchoring domain of a 34,000 molecular weight protein growth factor in placental
trophoblasts. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA, $5: 2014-2018,1988.
55. Basu, A., Raghunath, M., Bishayee, S., Das, M.: Inhibition of tyrosine kinase activity of the
EGF-receptor by a truncated receptor form that binds to EGF: Role for interreceptor
interaction in kinase regulation. Mol. Cell. Biol. 9_: 671-677,1989.
56. Das, M., Chauhan, S., Mishra, V.S., Sanger, J.M., Sanger, J.W., Roy-Choudhury, S.:
Aberrant post-endocytotic fate of a 34,000 molecular weight growth factor from
trophoblasts. Cancer Res. 49: 2761-2765,1989.
*57. Bishayee, S., Majumdar, S., Khire, J., Das, M.: Ligand-induced dimerization of the PDGF-
receptor: monomer-dimer interconversion occurs independent of receptor
phosphorylation. J. Biol. Chem. 264: 11699-11705, 1989.
58. Kesavan, P., Das, P., Kern, J., Das, M.: Regulation of stability and synthesis of EGF-
receptor mRNAs encoding for intact and truncated receptor forms. Oncogene 5: 483-488,
1990.
59. Das, M., Rengaraju, M., Samanta, A.: Epidermal growth factor. In "Handbook on Human
Cytokines", Ed, B.B. Aggarwal &amp; J. U. Gutterman, Blackwell Scientific Publications, MA (in press).

pgNbr=2
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
