<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>inl06d00</tid>
<bt>50510506/0507</bt>
<ti>BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH  EDWIN L. BIERMAN</ti>
<dd>19930000</dd>
<dt>RESUME</dt>
<rc>BIERMAN EL</rc>
<!-- Note:d:EDUCATION, RESEARCH AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE, HONORS, SELECTED PUBLICATIONS-->
<!-- Note:dl:20010130-->
<pg>2</pg>
<dl>20021115</dl>
<ot>RUG-22-'94 08:34 ID:UW METRH ENDO NUTR TEL N0:2066=781 9004 P03
Rfnolpak Investigator/Program pireotor (Last, ftrst. mlddle):
3. Brinton EA, Kenagy R, Oram JF, Bierman EL: Regulation of high density lipoprotein binding activity
of aortic endothelial cells by treatment with acetylated low density lipoprotein. Arteriosclerosis 5:329-
335, 1985.
4. Brinton EA, Oram JF, Chen CH, Albers JJ, Bierman EL: Binding of high-density lipoprotein to
cultured fibroblasts after chemical alteration of apoprotein amino acid residues, J. Biol. Chem,
261:495-503, 1986.
5. Oppenheimer MJ, Oram 1F, Bierman EL: Downregulation of high density lipoprotein receptor activity
of cultured fibroblasts by platelet-derived growth factor. Artericsclerosis 7:325-332, 1987.
6. Brinton EA, Oram JF, Bierman EL: The effect of variations in lipid composition of high-density
lipoprotein on its interaction with receptors on human fibroblasts. Biochim. Biophys. Acta 920:68-75,
1987.
7. Slotte JP, Oram JF, Bierman EL: Binding of high density lipoproteins to cell receptors promotes
translocation of cholesterol from intracellular membranes to the cell surface. J. Biol. Chem.
262:12904-12907, 1987.
8. Slotte JP, Bierman EL: Movement of plasma-membrane sterols to the endoplasmic reticulum in
cultured cells. Biochem. J. 248:237-242, 1987.
9. Slotte JP, Bierman EL: Depletion of plasma membrane sphingomyelin rapidly alters the distribution -
of cholesterol between the plasma membrane and intracellular membranes of cultured fibroblasts.
Biochem. J. 250:653-658, 1988.
10. Chait A, Ross R, Bierman EL: Stimulation of receptor.dependent and receptor-independent pathways
of low density lipoprotein degradation in arterial smooth muscle cells by platelet-derived growth
factor. Biochim. Biophys. Acta, 1988 960:183-189, 1988.
11. Oppenheimer MJ, Oram JF, Bierman EL: Up-regulation of high density lipoprotein receptor activity
by y-Interferon associated with inhibition of cell proliferation. J. Biol, Chem. 263:19318-19323, 1988.
12. Slotte JP, Chait A, Bierman EL: Cholesterol accumulation in aortic smooth muscle cells exposed to
low density lipoproteins: contribution of free cholesterol transfer, Arteriosclerosis 8:750-758, 1988.
13. Aviram M, Bierman EL, Chait A: Modification of low density lipoprotein by lipoprotein lipase or
hepatic lipase induces enhanced uptake and cholesterol accumulation in cells. J. Biol Chem
263:15416-15422, 1988.
14. Oppenheimer MJ, Sundquist K, Bierman EL: Downregulation of high density lipoprotein receptor
activity in human fibroblasts by insulin and IGF-I. Diabetes 38:117-122, 1989.
15. Aviram M, Bierman El., Oram JF: High density lipoprotein stimulates sterol translocation between
intracellular and plasma membrane pools in human monocyte-derived macrophages. J. Lipid Res.
30:65-76, 1989.
16. Slotte JP, Hedstrom G, Bierman EL: lntracellular transport of cholesterol in type C Niemann-Pick
fibroblasts. Biochim. Biophys. Acta 1005:303-309, 1989.
17. Duell PB, Oram JF,.Bierman EL: Nonenzymatic glycosylation of 1-IDL and impaired HDL-receptor-
mediated cholesterol efflux. Diabetes 40:377-384, 1991.
18. Mendez A, Oram JF, Bierman EL: Protein kinase C as a mediator of high density lipoprotein
receptor-dependent.efflux of intercellular cholesterol. J. Biol. Chem. 266:10104-10111, 1991.
19. Oikawa S, Mendez AJ, Bierman EL, Cheung M: Effect of high density lipoprotein particles
containing apo A-I with or without apo A-11 on intracellular cholesterol eff7ux. Biochim. Biophys. Acta
1165:327-334, 1993.
20. Francis GA, Mendez AJ, Bierman EL, Heinecke JW: Oxidative tyrosylation of high density
lipoprotein by peroxidase enhances cholesterol removal from cultured fibroblasts and macrophage
foam cells. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 90:6631-6635, 1993.
21. Hokland BM, Slotte JP, Bierman EL, Oram 1F: Cyclic-AMP sti.nulates efflux of intracellular sterol
from cholesterol-loaded cells. J. Biol. Chem. 268:25343-25349, 1993.
V. - a- g~

pgNbr=1
AUG-22-'9A 00:33 ID:UW METRB ENDO MUTP. TEL N0:2066853781 _ tt0N P02
FF
Principal mvestlpal«rrropram Director (tast. Brst. middlep
BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH
Give the following Information for the key pareoonel arrci consultanta anp eollaborators. tlepln with the pdncipal
trrvastlpatorlpfogram director. Photooopy this pape ror each person,
NAMt
Edwiu L. Bierman
POSmON TITLC
Professor of Medicine
EDUGATIUN (tlepfn witA baCCa(au/98te of nthrxInldal profacslona! educa6on, LueAcs nuralng, endincfude pusrduururaf tra7rdnp.)
INSTITUTION AND LOCATION
Brooklyn College, New York
Cornell Ilniv. Medical College, New York
DCOREE
A.B.
M.D.
YEAR
CONFERRED
1951
1955
FIELU UI• S1UDY
Honors in Cbemistry
Mediciuc
RESEARCH AND PROrESS1ONAL EXPERIENCE: tArlUuom9 w'Ith presenl po6iUorl. list. in chronoloolnal nrder, previous omploymont, e,cpedonoo, and
nanora. Key personnel Include the princtpal Invealioator and any other Indivlduak who parttolpnto in the scientific deve4ment or n.ewtkm of the project,
Kay pentonnel lypicaby wlll include all Individuals nlth doctoral wopror proleselonal deptees, butln some projects will Include Individuals at the maalerc or
baccalaureate level p,uvided they conmbUte In a subatantive waytothe adentifle devalnprnent oreyaeution of theprojeet.Inelude present momberahlp on
any Federal Government public adv~cnry oommihee. Uat inahronoloploal ordor, Ihe tMea, all authom, and comptute references to an pudlcatlons dunnp the
past thrae years and to rcpreaentafive eadler puLlicatlone perpnent to 1n1a appGcatqn. tt Itte list of publlpaUons In the last three yenre nrrreds two pagec,
eelet,i tue most pemnem pubacapons, D.Q NOT EXCEED TWO PAIiFS
1956-57 Assistant, Rockefeller Institute for Medical Rcsearch, New York
Assistant Physician, Rockefeller Institute Hospital, New Tork '
1957-59 Assistant Chief and Chief, Metabolic Research Division, U.S. Az'my Medical Research and
Nutrition Lab, Fitzsimons Hospital, Denver, CO
1959-60 Assictant. Resident (2nd year) in Medicine, New York Hospital
1960-62 Assistant Prnfecsnr, Rocke.feJler Institute
Assoctate Physician, Rockefeller Institute Hospital, New York
1962-63 Assislant Professor of Medicine, University of Washington School of Medicine, Seattle, WA
1962-75 Chief, Metabolism Section, VA Hospital, Seattle, WA
1963-68 Associate Prqfessor of Mcdicine, University of Washington School of Medicine, Seattle, WA
1966-75 Head, Division of Metabolisn] and Gerontology, University of Washington School of Medicine
1966-75 Assistant Chiof, Medical Service, VA Hospital, Seattle, WA
1968- Professor of Medicine, University of Washington School of Medicine
1971-73 Director, Northwest Lipid Research Clinic, Seattle, WA
1972-73 Visiting Professor, Hebrew University, Hadassah Medical Sclrool, Jerusalein, Israel
1975- Head, Division of Metabolism, Endocrinology and Nutrition, UW
1985- t..o-I)ire.ctor, Clinical Nutrition Research Unit, Univ. of Washington
HOIl4rS;
Research Career Development Award, NIH; Guggenheim Fellowship; American Society for Clinical
Investigatiun; Assoc. of American Physicians; Western Assoc. of Physicians (President, 1980-81);
Conamitlee uit Food &amp; Nutrition, ADA (196R-71, Chair 1969); Editorial Board, J. Clin. Invcst.,
11tabo ism- Mech. AginE xnd Devel., and Cit9..Be5-: Ftlitnr, Ajteriosclerosis; Assoc. Editor, Diabetes;
Nutrition Committee, AHA (1971-80, Chair 1976-79): Council, Snciety for Experimental Biology in
Medicine; National Advisory Council, NIA (1975-77); National Advlsory Council, NIAT7llK (1980-84);
AI-IA Council on Arteriosclcrosis, Exec, Committee (1979-90, Chair 1983-85); Award of Merit, AHA
(1984); Herman Award, ASCN (1984); Fellow, AAAS; Goldbergct Award. AMA (1988); Gold Hearr
Award, AHA (1990); National Diabetes Advisory Board (1988-92); Institute of Medicine (1988- ); Fnod
&amp; Nutrition Board IOM/NAS (1989- ). Scientific Advisory Council, AIIA (1989-93, chair 1990-93).
Selected Puhlicationc (out of a total of 295):
1. Chait A, Eisenberg S, Steinmet7. A, Albers JJ, Bierman EL: Low density lipoprotcins modified by lipid
transfer protein have altered biological activity. Biochim. Biophys. Acta 795:314-325, 1984.
2. IIiramalsu K, Bierman EL, Chalt A: Metabnlism of low-de.nsity liptiprotein from patients with diabetic
hypcrtriglyceridcauia by cultured human skin fibroblasts. Diabete.s 34:8-14, 1985.
PHS 398 (Rev. p,rp1) (Funn Page 6) Page - FF NumMr peaee consecuti.eiy at ma oonom mroupnow Ine appiiaaaon. Do rrorusa auMlzessuch as 3a.9b- ~

pgNbr=2
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
