<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>fae8aa00</tid>
<bt>CTRSP/FILES004518/4518</bt>
<ti>MEETING ON THE FUTURE USE OF SWEDISH AND AMERICAN TWIN REGISTERS FOR RESEARCH ON SMOKING AND HEALTH.  DECEMBER 1 - 4, 1969</ti>
<dd>19690729</dd>
<dt>LETTER</dt>
<au>FRIBERG L, KAROLINSKA INST</au>
<rc>HOCKETT R, CTR</rc>
<pc>HOLTZMAN A</pc>
<bx>85</bx>
<!-- Note:dp:19960116-->
<!-- Note:rn t="m":34; 39; 40; 41; 42; 43; 44; 45; 46; 47; 48; 89-->
<np>VI HILTON HOTEL ST THOMAS;HILLER TRAVEL SERVICE;AMERICANA HOTEL SAN JUAN PR;VA;TRC;CORNFIELD J;ENSLEIN;FEINLEIB M, NHI</np>
<!-- Note:d:CHANGE OF MEETING LOCATION-->
<!-- Note:lu:MNAG-->
<pg>1</pg>
<dl>20020201</dl>
<ot>4
THE KAROLINSKA INSTITUTE
Department of Environmental Hygiene
S-104 01 Stockholm 60, Sweden
TELEPHONE 08-23 54 80 EXT 165 or 08-33 01 13
Stockholm, July 29, 1969
LARS FRIBERG M. D.
PROFESSOR AND CHAIRMAN
Dr. Robert Hockett
Associate Scientific Director
The Counci for Tobacco Research-USA
110 East 59th Street
NEW YORK, N.Y. 10022
Re: Meeting on the Future Use of Swedish and
American Twin Registers for Research on
Smoking and Health. December 1 - 4, 1969
----------------------------------------------
Dear Dr. Hockett:
In my letter of July 15 I stated that the place
for the meeting would be the Virgin Isle Hilton
on St. Thomas. However, I have now been informed
by the Hiller Travel Service that this hotel
will not be able to receive our group, due to
other previously accepted arrangements. The
travel agency instead suggest the Americana Hotel
of San Juan on Puerto Rico. As far as I can see
this place is in all respects comparable to
the Virgin Isle Hilton and I hope that this
change of sites in no way will be inconvenient
to you.
Yours sincerely;
-~
. ~,
Lars Friberg, M.D.
P.S.
I have got a letter from Dr. J. Cornfield, where
he suggests that we invite Dr. Manning Feinleib
of the National Heart Institute. He is engaged in
a detailed examination in Framingham of several
hundreds of the VA pairs. I think this is a good
idea and have sent him a letter of invitation.
We believe it is possible to include Dr. Feinleib
in the group because of the fact that Mr. Enslein
is not among the invited participants but is taking
part as an observer from the Tobacco Research Council.
cc: Mr. Alexander Holtzman

pgNbr=1
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
