<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>ino09d00</tid>
<bt>50449946/9947</bt>
<ti>BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH  JEAN-NUMA LAPEYRE</ti>
<dd>19891214</dd>
<dt>RESUME</dt>
<au>LAPEYRE J</au>
<!-- Note:d:EDUCATION, RESEARCH AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE, PERTINENT PUBLICATIONS,-->
<!-- Note:dl:20010130-->
<pg>2</pg>
<dl>20021115</dl>
<ot>Prlacipal Iavestigator. J.-N. Lapeyre, Ph.D.
4. Lapeyre J-N and Becker FF: Analysis of highly repeated DNA sequences of rat with Eco RI
endonuclease. Biochim Biophys Acta fQZ:23-24. 1980.
5. Lapeyre J-N. Maizel AL and Becker FF: DNA methylation of liver and HTC cells during
eorticosteroid Inductlon. Blochem Biophys Res Comm 9&amp;630-637, 1980.
6. Lapeyre J-N, Beattie WG, Dugaiczyk A, Vlzard D and Becker FF: EcoR 1-generated components
of the rat genome. I. Sequence of two (92 and 93 bp) related DNA fragments. Gene jQ:330-346.
1980.
7. Lapeyre J-N, Waiker MS and Becker FF: DNA methylation and methylasc levels 1n normal and
malignant mouse hepatlc tissues. Carcinogenesl3 1:873-878, 1981.
8. Chan JYH. Ruchixawat M, Lapeyre J-N and Becker FF: The protective role of thiol reducing
agents in the in vitro inhibitton of rat liver DNA methylase by dimt-acttng carcinogens.
Carclnogenesis 4:1097-1100, 1983.
9. Kuo MT. Iyer B, Lapeyre J-N and Becker FF: Methylatioa of alpha fetoprotein gene in productive
and non-productive rat hepatocellular carcinomas. Cancer Res 14:1642-1647, 1984.
10. Ruchirawat M, Becker FF and Lapeyre J-N: Interaction of DNA methyhransferase with
aminofluorene and N-acetyl aminofluorene modified poly(dC-dG). Nucl Acids Res 12:3357-3371,
1984.
11. Ruchtrawat M, Becker FF and l.apeysp J-N: Mechanism of fnteracuon of DNA methyltransferase
with DNA modified by anti-benzo[alpyrenedioi epoxide. Biochemistry =:5426-5432, 1984.
12. Ruchtrawat R.. Becker FF and Lapeyre J-N: Indistinguishable physical and catalytic properties of
DNA methyltransferase from normal rat liver and a transplantable rat hepatoeellular carclnoma.
Carclnogenesis fa:877-882, 1985.
13. Becker FF, Holton P, Ruchirawat M and Lapeyre J-N: Perturbation of maintenance and de novo
DNA methylatton in vitro by UVB induced pyrlmidtne photodlmers. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA
a-6055-6059, 1985.
14. Ruchirawat M, Nosharl J and Lapeyre J-N: Kinetic mechanisms and interaction of rat liver DNA
methyltransferase with defined DNA substrates. Mol Cell Biochem Zfi:45-54. 1987.
15. Yoo H, Nosharl J and Lapeyre J-N: Subunit and functtonal size of human placental DNA
methyltransferase lnvolved in de novo and maintenance methylation. J Biol Chem
M.8066-8070, 1987.
16. Banaa T, Holton P, Ruchirawat M, Becker FF and Lapeyre J-N: UV-indueed photoproducts of
5-methylcytosine 1n a DNA sequence context. Nucl Acids Res j¢:3327-3340, 1988.
17. Rachal M, Yoo H, Becker FF and Lapeyre JN. In W6°o DNA cytosine methylation of cis-regulatory
elements modulates c-Ha-ras promoter Oe ufvo. Nucl Acids Res 1Z:5135-5147, 1989.

pgNbr=1
PRINCIPAL INVESTIGATORIPROGRAM DIRECTOR:
BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH
Give the following information for the key personnel and consultants listed on page 2. Begin with the Principal
InvestigatorlProgram Director. Photocopy this page for each person.
NAME
POSITION TITLE
BIRTHDATE (Mo., Day, Yr.)

Jean-Ntmma Lapevre I Associate Professor 1 10/17/45
EDUCATION (8e in with bacca/aureate or other initial rofessional education, sueh as nursin , and inc7ude postdoctoral trainin .)
	
INSTITUTION AND LOCATION	DEGREE	YEAR
CONFERRED	FIELD OF STUDY
Univ. of California at Los Angeles	B.S.	1967	Physics/Biology
Univ. of California at Ir+dne	M.S.	19fi9	Molecular Biology
University of Southern Callf=la	Ph.D.	1975	Molecular and Cell
			Biology
RESEARCH AND PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE: Concluding with present position, list, in chronological order, previous employment, experience,
and honors. Include present membership on any Federal Government public advisory committee. List, in chronological order, the titles and com•
plete references to all publications during the past three years and to representative earlier publications pertinent to this application. DO NOT
EXCEED TWO PAGES.
RESEARCH AND PROFESSIONAL E%PERIENCE
1977-1978 ProJect Investigator, Department of Pathology. The University of Texas
M. D. Anderson Cancer Center, Houston, Texas.
1979-1980 Assistant Biochemist and Instructor In BiochemLstry (Pathology)
The University of Texas M. D. Anderson Cancer Center, Houston, Texas.
1980-1985 Assistant Biochemist and Assistant Professor eSBiochemistry (Pathology)
The University oTTexas M. D. Anderson Cancer Center, Houston, Texas.
1985-Present Associate Biochemist and Associate Professor of Biochemistry (Pathology)
The University of Texas M. D. Anderson Cancer Center, Houston, Texas.
SONORS
1975-1976 Fogarty International Fellow. Molecular Biology
Institute, University of Geneva, Swttzerland.
June-Sept NCI/INSERM Visiting Mcchange Scientist, CNRS
1982 Institute for Molecular Biophysics. Orleans, France.
1985-Present Director, Recombinant DNA Facility,
M. D. Anderson Cancer Center. Houston, TK
1985-Ptesent Member, NIH Clinical Science IV Study Section (ferm eacp]res 1989).
PERTII4EAIT PUBLICATIONS
l. Lapeyre J-N and Bekhor I: Effect of 5-bromo-2' deoxyurldine and dlmethyl sulfoxlde
properties and structure of chromatln. J Mol Bio1 @,Q:137-162. 1974.
on
2. Lapeyce J-N and Bekhor I: Chromosomal protein interaetions in chromatin and with DNA.
J Mol Biol 1Q4:24-58, 1976.
3. Lapeyre J-N and Becker FF: 5-Methylcytosine content of nuclear DNA during chemical
hepatocarcinogenesLs and in carcinomas which result. Biochem Biophys Res Comm QZ:698-
705, 1979.
PHS 398 (Rev. 9158) Page _
-Numba pages consecutively at the bottom throughout the application. Do not use suftins suoh as St Sb.

pgNbr=2
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
