<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<LTDLWOCR>
<!-- forcebtag -->
<tid>inv98d00</tid>
<bt>50410607/0615</bt>
<ti>R.S. SOHAL</ti>
<dd>19840800</dd>
<dt>RESUME</dt>
<!-- Note:d:EDUCATION, PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE, RECENT PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES, BOOKS-->
<!-- Note:dl:20010130-->
<pg>9</pg>
<dl>20021115</dl>
<ot>fi.5. Satixz.
Current Position
and Address: Professor; Department of Biology, Southern Methodist
University, Dallas, Texas 75275; Telephone Number
214/692-2732; Home 214/824-8594
Personal: Born, July 1, 1936; naturalized citizen of USA;
married to Barbara Hart Harris; no children
1
Education: B.S. (Honors); Zoology; Panjab University (India), 1961
Ph.D., Zoology, Tulane University, New Orleans, Louisiana,
1965
Professional
Experience:
1965-69 Instructor to Assistant Professor, Section of Cardiovascular
Research, Tulane Medical School
1969-present Assistant Professor of Biology, promoted to Associate
Professor in 1971 and full Professor in 1979, Southern
Methodist University, Dallas, Texas
1975 and 1979 Senior Visiting Scholar, Department of Zoology, The
(Jan.-Aug.) University of Cambridge, England
1984 (Jan.-Aug.) Visiting Scientist; Institute of Physiological Chemistry,
The University of Dusseldorf, W. Germany
Recent Professional
Activities:
Member of -he Managing Board, American Aging Association, 1982 - 1984
Co-Chairman of the Symposium on "Free Radicals in Molecular Biology and
Aging"; Annual Meeting of the American Aging Association, Washington,
D.C., 1983
Chairman, Program Committee, American Aging Association, 1984
Chairman of the Symposium on "Molecular Biology of Aging"; Annual
Meeting of the American Aging Association, New York, 1984
Books:
Sohal, R.S. (Editor) Age Pigments, Elsevier/North Holland, Amsterdam, 1981
Armstrong, D., Sohal, R.S., Cutler, R.G. and Slater, T.F. (Editors) Free
Radicals in Molecular Biology and Aging. Raven Press, New York, 1984
Sohal, R.S., Birnbaum, L. and Cutler, R.G. (Editors) Molecular Biology of
Aging: Gene Stability and Gene Expression, Raven Press, New York, 1985
Collatz, K.G. and Sohal, R.S. (Editors) Comparative Biology of Aging
in Insects, Springer-Verlag, Heidelberg, 1986

pgNbr=1
2
MAJOR PUBLICATIONS
Sohal, R.S. and Copeland, E. (1966) Ultrastructural variations in
the anal papillae of Aedes aegypti (L.) at different environmen-
tal salinities. J. Insect Physiol. 12, 429-439.
Sohal, R.S., Sun, S.C., Burch, G.E. and Colcolough, H.L. (1967)
Ultrastructural localization of Coxsackie B4 virus in mouse
myocardium. Nature (London) 215, 312-313.
Sun, S.C., Sohal, R.S., Burch, G.E., Chu, K.C. and Colcolough, H.L.
(1967) Coxsackie B4 pancarditis in cynomolgus monkeys resembling
rheumatic heart lesions. Brit. J. Exp. Path. 48, 655-661.
Sun, S.C., Colcolough, H.L., Burch, G.E., DePasquale, N.P. and Sohal,
R.S. (1967) Immunofluorescent study of B4 Coxsackie valvulitis
in mice. Proc. Soc. E. Biol. Med. 125, 157 162.
Burch, G.E., Sun, S.C., Colcolough, H.L., DePasquale, N.P. and
Sohal, R.S. (1967) Acute myocardial lesions following experi-
mentally induced intracranial hemorrhage in mice: A histological
and histochemical study. Arch. Path. 84, 517-521.
Burch, G.E., Sun, S.C., Colcolough, H.L., Sohal, R.S. and DePasquale,
N.P. (1967) Coxsackie B viral myocarditis and valvulitis iden-
tified by immunofluorescent techniques. Amer. Heart J. 74,
13-23.
Burch, G.E., Sun, S.C., Colcolough, H., Sohal, R.S. and DePasquale,
N.P. (1967) Coxsackie virus valvulitis and myocarditis
observed at routine autopsy. Experientia 23, 1041-1043.
Burch, G.E., Chu, K.C., and Sohal, R.S. (1968) Glomerulonephritis
induced in mice by ECHO 9 virus. New Eng. J. Med. 279, 1420--
1424.
Sohal, R.S., Sun, S.C., Burch, G.E. and Colcolough, H.L. (1968)
Ultrastructural changes in intercalated discs in exercised rat
hearts. Lab. Invest. 18, 49-53.
Sohal, R.S., Sun, S.C., Burch, G.E. and Colcolough, H.L. (1968) Heat
stroke. An electron microscopic study of endothelial cell damage
and disseminated intravascular coagulation. Arch. Int. Med.
122, 43-47.
Burch, G.E., Sun, S.C., Chu, K.C., Sohal, R.S. and Colcolough, H.L.
(1968) Interstitial and Coxsackie B4 myocarditis in infants and
children, J. Amer. Med. Ass. 203, 1-8.

pgNbr=2
4
Burch, G.E., Sohal, R.S., Sun, S.C. and Colcolough, H.L. (1969)
Effects of experimental intracranial hemmorrhage on the
myocardium of mice. Amer. H.J. 77, 427-429.
Chu, K.C., Sohal, R.S., Sun, S.C., Burch, G.E. and Colcolough, H.L.
(1969) Lipid cardiomyopathy of the hypertrophied heart of
glucose obese mice. J. Path. 97, 99-103.
Burch, G.E., Chu, K.C., Colcolough, H.L. and Sohal, R.S. (1969)
Immunofluorescent localization of Coxsackie-virus B antigen in
kidney at routine autopsy. Amer. J. Med. 47, 36-40.
Burch, G.E. and Sohal, R.S. (1969) Morphologic and pathologic aspects
of the intercalated disc of the heart. Amer. Heart J. 78,
358-368.
Sohal, R.S. (1970) Mitochondrial changes
repleta. Exp. Geront. 5, 213-216.
in the heart of Drosophila
Burch, G.E., Sohal, R.S. and Fairbanks, L.D. (1970) Senescent
changes in the heart of Drosophila repleta. Nature (London) 225,
386-388.
Aldinger, E.E. and Sohal, R.S. (1970) Effects of digitoxin on the
ultrastructural myocardial changes in the rat heart subjected to
chronic exercise. Amer. J. Cardio. 26, 369-374.
Burch, G.E., Sohal, R.S. and Fairbanks, L.D. (1971) Ultra-
structural changes in Drosophila heart with age. Arch. Path.
89, 128-136.
Sohal, R.S. and Allison, V.F. (1971) Senescent changes in the cardiac
myofiber of the housefly, Musca domestica. fu electron microsco-
pic study. J. Geront. 26, 490-496.
Sohal, R.S. and Allison, V.F. (1971) Age-related changes in the fine
structure of the flight muscle in the house fly. ExQ. Geront.
5, 213-216.
Wu, B.C., Valle, R.T., White, L.A.E., Sohal, R.S., Arcos, J.C., Argus,
M.F. and Burch, G.E. (1971) Mitochondrial ultrastructure and
energy transduction in rat heart during progressive thiamine
deficiency. Virch. Arch. B Cell Path. 2, 97-114.
Sohal, R.S., McCarthy, J.L. and Allison, V.F. (1972) The formation
of "giant" mitochondria in the fibrillar flight muscles of the
housefly, Musca domestica. J. Ultrast. Res. 39, 484-495.
Sohal, R.S., Sharma, S.P., and Couch, E.F. (1972) Fine structure of
the neural sheath, neurons and glia in the brain of the housefly,
Musca domestica. Z. Zellforsch. 135, 449-459.

pgNbr=3
3
Burch, G.E., Sun, S.C., Sohal, R.S., Chu, K.C. and Colcolough, H.L.
(1968) Diptheritic myocarditis: a histochemical and electron
microscopic study. Amer. J. Cardiol. 22, 261-268.
Arcos, J.C., Sohal, R.S., Sun, S.C., Argus, M.F. and Burch, G.E.
(1968) Changes in ultrastructure and respiratory control in
mitochondria of rat heart hypertrophied by exercise. Exp. Mol.
Path. 8, 49-65.
Burch, G.E., Sohal, R.S., Sun, S.C., Miller, C.C. and Colcolough, H.L.
(1968) Effects of radiation on the human heart. An electron
microscopic study. Arch. Int. Med. 121, 230-234.
Sun, S.C., Burch, G.E., Sohal, R.S. and Chu, K.C. (1968) Coxsackie
B4 viral nephritis in mice and its autoimmune-like phenomenon.
Proc. Soc. Ex~. Biol. Med. 126, 882-885.
Sun, S.C., Sohal, R.S., Colcolough, H.L. and Burch, G.E. (1968)
Histochemical and electron microscopic studies on the effects of
reserpine on the heart muscle of mice. J. Pharm Exp. Therap.
161, 210-221.
Sun, S.C., Sohal, R.S., Chu, K.C., Leiderman, E., Colcolough, H.L. and
Burch, G.E. (1968) Mycoplasma gallisepticum infection in mice
and cynomolgus monkeys. A histologic, immunofluorescent and
electron microscopic study of the heart. Amer. J. Path. 53,
1073-1096.
Burch, G.E., Sohal, R.S., Colcolough, H.L. and Sun, S.C. (1968)
Virus-like particles in the skeletal muscle of a heat stroke
victim. Arch. Env. Health 17, 984-95.
Sohal, R.S., Burch, G.E., Chu, K.C., Leiderman, E. and Colcolough,
H.L. (1969) Ultrastructural changes in cardiac capillaries of
Coxsackie virus B4 infected mice. Lab. Invest. 19, 399-405.
Sohal, R.S. and Burch, G.E. (1969) Ultrastructural lesions of
myocardial cell in Coxsackie B4 virus infected mice. Virch.
Arch. A Path. Anat. 346, 361-373.
Sohal, R.S. and Burch, G.E. (1969) Electron microscopic study of
the endocardium in Coxsackie virus B4 infected mice. Amer.
J. Path. 55, 133-145.
Sohal, R.S. and Burch, G.E. (1969) Effects of alcohol ingestion on
the intercalated disc in the mouse heart. Experientia 25,
279-280.
Sohal, R.S. and Burch, G.E. (1969) Effects of ethanol ingestion on
the cardiac capillaries of mice. Cardiovas. Res. 3, 369-370.

pgNbr=4
5
Sohal, R.S. and Sharma, S.P. (1972) Age-related changes in the fine
structure and number of neurons in the brain of the house fly,
Musca domestica. Exp. Geront. 7, 243-249.
Argus, M.F., Sohal, R.S., Bryant, G.M., Hoch-Ligetti, C. and Arcos,
J.C. (1972) Dose-response and ultrastructural alterations in
dioxane carcinogenesis. Metabolism-dependent toxicity. Eur. J.
Can. 9, 237-243.
Sohal, R.S. (1973) Fine structural alterations with age in the fat
body of the adult male housefly, Musca domestica. Z. Zellforsch.
140, 169-175.
Sohal, R.S. and McCarthy, J.L. (1973) Age-related changes in acid
phosphatase activity in adult male housefly, Musca domestica. A
histochemical and biochemical study. Ex_p. Geront. 8, 223-227.
Ragland, S.S. and Sohal, R.S. (1973) Mating behavior, physical
activity, and aging in the housefly, Musca domestica. Exp.
Geront. 8, 135-145.
Sohal, R.S. (1974) Fine structure of Malpighian tubules in the
housefly, Musca domestica. Tissue &amp; Cell 6, 719-728.
Beezeley, A.E., McCarthy, J.L. and Sohal, R.S. (1974) Changes in
alpha-glycerophosphate, succinic and isocitric dehydrogenase, in
the flight muscles of the housefly with age. Exp. Geront. 9,
71-74.
Sohal, R.S. (1975) Mitochondrial changes in the flight muscles of
normal and flightless Drosophila melanogaster with age. J.
Morph. 145, 337-354.
Ragland, S.S. and Sohal, R.S. (1975) Ambient temperature, physical
activity and aging in the housefly, Musca domestica. Exp.
Geront. 10, 279-289.
Sohal, R.S. (1976) Aging changes in insect flight muscle.
Gerontology 22, 317-333.
Sohal, R.S. (1976) Metabolic rate aiid life span. In Interdisciplinary
Topics in Gerontology (edit. H.P. von Hahn) Vol. 9, 25-40, S.
Karger, Basel.
Sohal, R.S., Peters, P.D. and Hall, T.A. (1976) Fine structure and
X-ray microanalysis of mineralized concretions in the Malpighian
tubules of the housefly, Musca domestica. Tissue &amp; Cell 8,
447-458.
Sohal, R.S. and Bridges, R.G. (1977) Effects of experimental altera-
tions in phospholipid composition on the size and number of
mitochondria in the flight muscles of the housefly, Musca
domestica. J. Cell Sci. 27, 273-287.

pgNbr=5
9
Sohal, R.S., Allen, R.G., Farmer, K.J., Newton, R.K. and Toy, P.L. (1985)
Effects of exogenous antioxidants on the levels of endogenous antioxidants,
lipid-soluble fluorescent material and life span in the housefly,
Musca domestica. Mech. Ageing Dev. 31, 329-336.
Sohal, R.S., Allen, R.G., Farmer, K.J. and Newton, R.K. (1985) Iron induces
oxidative stress and may alter the rate of aging in the housefly,
Musca domestica. Mech. Ageing Dev. 32, 33-38.
Allen, R.G. Newton, R.K., Sohal, R.S., Shipley, G.L. and Nations, C. (1985)
Alterations in superoxide dismutase, glutathione, and peroxides in
the plasmodial slime mold, Physarum polycephalum. J. Cell. Physiol.
(in press).
Allen, R.G., Toy, P.L., Newton, R.K., Farmer, K.J. and Sohal, R.S. (1985)
Effects of experimentally-altered glutathione levels on life span,
metabolic rate, superoxide dismutase, catalase and inorganic peroxides
in the adult housefly, Musca domestica. Comp. Biochem Physiol. (in press).
Nations, C., Allen, R.G., Farmer, K.J., Toy, P.L. and Sohal, R.S. (1985)
Superoxide dismutase activity during the plasmodial life cycle of
Physarum polycephalum. Experientia (in press).
Sohal, R.S. (in press) Cellular aspects of aging in insects. In: Handbook
of Cell Biology of Aging (edited by V.J. Cristofalo), CRC Press, Boca
Raton, Florida.
Sohal, R.S. (in press) The rate of living theory: a contemporary interpretation.
In: Comparative Biology of Aging in Insects (edited by K.G. Collatz and
R.S. Sohal), Springer-Verlag, Heidelberg.
Allen, R.G. and Sohal, R.S. (in press) Role of glutathione in the aging and
development of insects. In: Comparative Biology of Aging in Insects
(edited by K.G. Collatz and R.S. Sohal), Springer-Verlag, Heidelberg.
Sohal, R.S. (in press) Lipofuscin: characteristics and significance.
Prog. Brain Res.
Sohal, R.S. and Allen, R.G. (in press) Relationship between oxygen metabolism,
aging and development. Adv. Free Radicals Biol. Med.

pgNbr=6
6
Bryant, M.G., Sohal, R.S., Argus, M.F. and Arcos, J.C. (1977) Ultra-
structural and metabolic determinants of the resistance of the
guinea pig to azo dye and susceptibility to nitrosamine
carcinogenesis. Brit. J. Cancer 36, 678-691.
McCarthy, J.L., Green W., and Sohal, R.S. (1976) Crowding stress and
adrenal mitochondria 11B-hydroxylation in vitro. Proc. Soc. Exp.
Biol. Med. 153, 528-531. ~
Sohal, R.S. and Lamb, R.E. (1977) Intracellular deposition of metals
in the midgut of the adult housefly, Musca domestica. J. Insect
Physiol. 23, 1349-1354.
Sohal, R.S., Peters, P.D., and Hall, T.A. (1977) Structure, origin,
composition and age-dependence of mineralized dense bodies
(concretions) in the midgut of the adult housefly, Musca
domestica. Tissue &amp; Cell 9, 87-102.
Sohal, R.S. (1978) Aging changes in insect heart. In Aging in Muscle
(edited by G. Kaldor and J. DiBattista) Raven Press, New York,
pp. 211-226.
Donato, H. and Sohal, R.S. (1978) Age-related changes in lipofuscin-
associated fluorescent substances in the adult male housefly,
Musca domestica. Ex~. Geront. 13, 171-180.
Sohal, R.S. and Donato, H. (1978) Effects of experimentally altered
life spans on the accumulation of fluorescent age pigment in the
housefly Musca domestica. Exp. Geront. 13, 335-341.
Sohal, R.S. and Bridges, R.G. (1978) Associated changes in the size
and number of mitochondria present in the midgut of the larvae of
the housefly, Musca domestica and phospholipid composition. J.
Cell Sci. 34, 65-79.
Sohal, R.S. and Lamb, R. (1979) Storage-excretion of metallic cations
in the adult housefly, Musca domestica. J. Insect Physiol. 25,
119-124.
Sohal, R.S. and Donato, H. (1979) Effect of experimental prolongation
of life span on lipofuscin content and lysosomal enzyme activity
in the brain of the housefly, Musca domestica. J. Geront. 34,
489-496.
Donato, H., Hoselton, M. and Sohal, R. (1979) An analysis of the
effects of individual variation and selective mortality on
population averages. Exp. Ceront. 14, 133-140.
Donato, H., Hoselton, M. and Sohal, R. (1979) Lipofuscin accumulation:
effects of individual variation and selective mortality on
population averages. Exp. Geront. 14, 141-147.

pgNbr=7
7
Bridges, R.G. and Sohal, R.S. (1980) Relationship between age-associated
fluorescence and polyunsaturated fatty acids in the adult housefly,
Musca domestica. Insect Biochem. 10, 557-562.
Sohal, R.S. (1981) Metabolic rate, aging and lipofuscin accumulation.
In: Age Pigments (edited by R.S. Sohal), 303-316, Elsevier/North
Holland, Amsterdam.
Donato, H. and Sohal, R.S. (1981) Lipofuscin. In: Handbook of Aging,
Biochemistry (edited by J. Florini), 221-227, CRC Press, Cleveland.
Sohal, R.S. and Buchan, P.B. (1981) Relationship between physical activity
and life span in the adult housefly, Musca domestica. Exp. Geront. 16,
157-162.
Sohal, R.S. and Buchan, P.B. (1981) Relationship between fluorescent age
pigment, physiological age and physical activity in the housefly,
Musca domestica. Mech. Ageing Dev. 15, 243-249.
Buchan,P.B. and Sohal, R.S. (1981) Effect of temperature and different sex
ratios on physical activity and life span in the adult housefly, Musca
domestica. Exp. Geront. 16, 223-228.
Sohal, R.S., Donato, H., Biehl, E.R. (1981) Effect of age and metabolic
rate on lipid peroxidation in the housefly, Musca domestica. Mech.
Ageing Dev. 16, 159-167.
Sohal, R.S. (1981) Relationship between metabolic rate, lipofuscin
accumulation and lysosomal enzyme activity during aging in the adult
housefly, Musca domestica. Exp. Geront. 16, 347-355.
McArthur, M. and Sohal, R.S. (1982) Relationship between metabolic rate,
aging, lipid peroxidation and fluorescent age pigment in milkweed bug,
Oncopeltus fasciatus (Hemiptera). J. Geront. 37, 268-274.
Sohal, R.S. (1982) Oxygen consumption and life span in the adult housefly,
Musca domestica. Age 5, 21-24.
Allen, R.G. and Sohal, R.S. (1982) Life-lengthening effects of y-irradiation
in the housefly, Musca domestica. Mech. Ageing Dev. 20, 369-375.
Sohal, R.S., Ragland, S.S., Allen, R.G. and Farmer, K. (1983) Correlation
between oxygen consumption, lipofuscin, fluorescent age pigment, lipid
peroxidation potential and life span in insects. In: Oxy Radicals and
Their Scavenger Systems (edited by R. Greenwald and G. Cohen), voL. 2,
361-364, Elsevier/North Holland, Amsterdam and New York.
Allen, R.G., Farmer, K.J., and Sohal, R.S. (1983) Effect of catalase
inactivation on levels of inorganic peroxides, superoxide dismutase,
glutathione, oxygen consumption and life span in adult houseflies.
Biochem. J. 216, 503-506.
Sohal, R.S. (1984) Assay of lipofuscin/ceroid pigment in vivo during aging.
Methods in Enzymology 105, 484-487.

pgNbr=8
8
Sohal, R.S., Farmer, K.J., Allen, R.G. and Cohen, N.R. (1984) Effect of age
on oxygen consumption, superoxide dismutase, catalase, glutathione,
inorganic peroxides and chloroform-soluble antioxidants in the adult
male housefly, Musca domestica. Mech. Ageing Dev. 24, 185-195.
Sohal, R.S., Allen, R.G., Farmer, K.J. and Procter, J. (1984) Effect of
physical activity on superoxide dismutase, catalase, inorganic peroxides
and glutathione in the housefly, Musca domestica. Mech. Ageing Dev. 26,
75-81.
Sohal, R.S., Farmer, K.J., Allen, R.G. and Ragland, S.S. (1984) Effects of
diethyldithiocarbamate on life span, metabolic rate, superoxide dismutase,
catalase, inorganic peroxides and glutathione in the adult male housefly,
Musca domestica. Mech. Ageing Dev. 24, 175-183.
Allen, R.G., Farmer, K.J. and Sohal, R.S. (1984) Effect of diamide admini-
stration on longevity, oxygen consumption, superoxide dismutase, catalase,
inorganic peroxides and glutathione in the adult housefly, Musca domestica.
Comp. Biochem. Physio. 78c, 31-33.
Allen, R.G., Farmer, K.J., Newton, R.K. and Sohal, R.S. (1984) Effects of
paraquat administration on longevity, oxygen consumption, lipid peroxidation,
superoxide dismutase, catalase, glutathione reductase, inorganic peroxides
and glutathione in the adult housefly. Comp. Biochem. Physiol. 78c,
283-288.
Sohal, R.S. (1984) Metabolic rate, free radicals and aging. In: Free Radicals
in Molecular Biology, Aging and Disease (edited by D. Armstrong et al.),
pp. 119-128, Raven Press, New York.
Sohal, R.S., Bridges, R.G. and Howes, E.A. (1984) Relationship between
lipofuscin granules and polyunsaturated fatty acids in the housefly,
Musca domestica. Mech. Ageing Dev. 25, 355-363.
Sohal, R.S. (1985) Aging in Insects. In: Comprehensive Insect Physiology,
Biochemistry and Pharmacology (edited by L.I. Gilbert), vol. 10, pp. 595-631,
Pergamon Press, Oxford and New York.
Sohal, R.S., Muller, A., Koletzko, B. and Sies, H. (1985) Effect of age
and ambient temperature on n-pentane production in adult housefly,
Musca domestica. Mech. Ageing Dev. 29, 317-326.
Sohal, R.S. and Allen, R.G. (1985) Relationship between metabolic rate,
free radicals, differentiation and aging: a unified theory. In:
Molecular Biology of Aging (edited by A.D. Woodhead, A.D. Blackett
and A. Hollaender), pp. 75-104, Plenum, New York.
Allen, R.G., Farmer, K.J., Toy, P.L., Newton, R.K., Sohal, R.S. and
Nations, C. (1985) Effect of glutathione on differentiation in the
slime mold, Physarum polycephalum. Develop. Growth and Diff. 27, 551-556.
Sohal, R.S. (1985) Oxidative stress and aging. Life Chem. Rep. 3, 244-249.

pgNbr=9
</ot>
</LTDLWOCR>
